<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LGB on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/lgb/</link><description>Recent content in LGB on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 20:08:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/lgb/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One Huge Prickly Reason Why Anti-LGBTQ Folks Don’t Change Their Views</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/01/ignored-reason-people-dont-affirm-lgbtq-people-make-harder/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 20:08:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/01/ignored-reason-people-dont-affirm-lgbtq-people-make-harder/</guid><description>I need you to take a leap with me.
Leap into the shoes of someone who has walked through their life knowing that being gay, being bi, lesbian, or pan, or that being non-binary, gender non-conforming, or trans — that being different, different from straight, different from cisgender — is wrong.</description></item><item><title>How to explain that bisexuality (or pansexuality) is real</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/how-to-explain-to-someone-bisexuality-or-pansexuality-is-real/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 20:24:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/how-to-explain-to-someone-bisexuality-or-pansexuality-is-real/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Bisexuality is a thing. It’s not just “a stop between gay and straight.” But how do you explain that to someone who just. simply. won’t. believe. you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am going to focus on the struggle many bisexual and pansexual folks have convincing their straight (or gay/lesbian) peers that bisexuality is an identity, not just a stopping point between two others.  While I’m focusing this article on advice for bi- and pansexual folks, some of it applies to all sexuality discussions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have three main approaches you can take below, but I’d love to hear suggestions for more ways to breach this subject in the comments below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Flowchart: I Want To Say Gay (When it’s Okay)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/even-better-flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-gay/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 19:34:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/even-better-flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-gay/</guid><description>When I published my original flowchart, I said it was for the more analytical folks who are wondering if “gay” is the right word choice for them. Well, this one is for the most analytical folks, and also folks who enjoy data presented in cute and adorable ways.</description></item><item><title>Flowchart: when it’s okay to say “that’s so gay”</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-thats-so-gay-prin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 22:10:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-thats-so-gay-prin/</guid><description>For the more analytical folks, we created a handy flowchart to help make the decision “Is ‘gay’ the right word for me?”
As you can tell, in most cases, the answer is no. Print, post, and share freely.</description></item><item><title>When to use the word “gay”</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/when-to-use-the-word-gay-print/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 00:14:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/when-to-use-the-word-gay-print/</guid><description>When is it &amp;ldquo;okay&amp;rdquo; to say gay? Why is this even a question we need to be asking? Well, because it seems that people have some misconceptions, and this flowchart makes it simple.
This graphic was originally created to support this article, but then a comment was made saying this should be hung on every dorm wall in America.</description></item><item><title>Ron Paul: When the morality changes, it will reflect on the laws</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/ron-paul-when-the-morality-changes-it-will-reflect-on-the-laws/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 05:46:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/ron-paul-when-the-morality-changes-it-will-reflect-on-the-laws/</guid><description>I was watching one of the recent GOP debates and I heard Ron Paul say something that really struck me, responding with his thoughts on abortion. I transcribed the quote, but the video is down below that if you’d like to watch.</description></item><item><title>“Gay Marriage Equals” Poster</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/gay-marriage-equals-poster-print/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/gay-marriage-equals-poster-print/</guid><description>This poster is for Rick Santorum, et al. Same-sex marriages are happening, gays are serving openly in the military, and the world isn’t falling apart (well, maybe it is, but it was a preexisting condition).
Yet anti-human-rights activists like Santorum and the rest of the Slippery Slopers can’t help but remind us that gay marriage is just the beginning.</description></item><item><title>30+ Examples of Heterosexual (Straight) Privileges</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/29-examples-of-heterosexual-privilege/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 23:03:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/29-examples-of-heterosexual-privilege/</guid><description>Following is a list of examples of heterosexual privilege. If you are straight, these are unearned benefits you receive as a result of the sexuality you were born with.
If you are straight (or in some cases, perceived to be), you can live without ever having to think twice, face, confront, engage, or cope with anything listed below.</description></item><item><title>Why same-sex marriage is constitutional, and marrying a toaster is not.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/why-same-sex-marriage-is-constitutional-and-marrying-a-toaster-is-not/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 21:07:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/why-same-sex-marriage-is-constitutional-and-marrying-a-toaster-is-not/</guid><description>A graphic representation of an issue that should be simpler than it is, but it always leading to absurd slippery-slope arguments.
Below is a wonderful graphic that was shared with me that does a fantastic job of clearing the whole thing up.</description></item><item><title>A visual aid: when “gay” is okay</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/a-visual-aid-when-gay-okay-to-sa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 21:51:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/a-visual-aid-when-gay-okay-to-sa/</guid><description>For those of you still struggling with the idea of when it is and isn’t ideal to use the word “gay”, even after reading my article outlining the whole idea, I decided to create a few visual aids. Hopefully they are straightforward.</description></item></channel></rss>