<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>List on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/list/</link><description>Recent content in List on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 19:29:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/list/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Your Ally is Someone Who… (A Few Ways to Be #BetterAllies)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/10/better-ally-week/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 19:29:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/10/better-ally-week/</guid><description>To celebrate GLSEN‘s Ally Week, It Gets Better and I put our heads together to create a series of images. These comics exemplify what _they _described as the top traits of better allies, and in my best ally fashion I used my doodling powers to elevate that message.</description></item><item><title>15+ Fantastic Resources for Talking about “Homosexuality” (i.e., LGBTQ people) and The Bible</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/10/resources-lgbtq-homosexual-bible-christianity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 21:47:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/10/resources-lgbtq-homosexual-bible-christianity/</guid><description>Only a tiny, tiny part of the bible can even be argued to reference “homosexuality” (and that argument, in a few of the verses in particular, is worth looking into), yet it seems like whenever we hear about the Bible in the news it’s being slammed against LGBTQ equality.</description></item><item><title>30+ Examples of Masculine Dude (“Bro”) Privileges</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/02/30-examples-of-masculine-dude-bro-privilege/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 23:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/02/30-examples-of-masculine-dude-bro-privilege/</guid><description>I’ve written a few privilege lists, several of which are about privileged identities I possess. They are serious articles that provide a couple hundred examples of systemic oppression (in the US and elsewhere). This article is not that.
I ask that you please humor me as I take a moment to address the many privileges I _don’t _have access to, due to my gender expression/ metrosexuality.</description></item><item><title>Comprehensive* List of LGBTQ+ Vocabulary Definitions</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/01/a-comprehensive-list-of-lgbtq-term-definitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 23:46:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/01/a-comprehensive-list-of-lgbtq-term-definitions/</guid><description>Hi! This post is now available as part of an E-Book called &amp;#8220;Defining LGBTQ+&amp;#8221;. It includes the most recently updated definitions for all the terms below, the rules, and a bunch of other stuff. You can download it as a .</description></item><item><title>5 Reasons Why So Many People Believe Feminism Hates Men and Why They’re Not True</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/12/reasons-people-believe-feminism-hates-men/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 06:10:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/12/reasons-people-believe-feminism-hates-men/</guid><description>&lt;p>“The feminist agenda is not about equal rights for women. It is about a socialist, anti-family political movement that encourages women to leave their husbands, kill their children, practice witchcraft, destroy capitalism, and become lesbians.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pat Robertson famously said this in the 90s, and the sentiment still rings as true in the ears of many today.  It’s an understatement to say that &lt;a href="http://everydayfeminism.com/2012/07/feminist-myths/" title="How Most Things You Know About Feminists Are Vicious Conservative Lies">feminism has a bad rap.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feminism doesn’t hate men.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So why do so many people think feminism = man-hating? Let’s look at a few explanations for this fallacy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>30+ Examples of Male Privileges</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/11/30-examples-of-male-privilege/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 20:49:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/11/30-examples-of-male-privilege/</guid><description>Following is a list of male privileges. If you are male (and a man), listed below are benefits that result from being born with that gender and sex.
If you identify as a man, there’s a good chance you’ve never thought about these things.</description></item><item><title>50+ concrete things you can do today to make for a more socially just tomorrow</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/11/things-you-can-do-today-for-social-justice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 05:34:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/11/things-you-can-do-today-for-social-justice/</guid><description>&lt;p>Social justice — the idea that everyone in a society, regardless of the identities they embody, can have an equitable shot at success and happiness — is a goal that seems unrealistic for many people. “It’s a pipe dream, Sam,” they say, smugly. “Life isn’t rainbows and butterflies,” they say, adorably.&lt;/p>
&lt;aside class="heyHeyLook wednesdayEmail">&lt;p>&lt;span class="icon">💌&lt;/span>&lt;strong>Most Wednesdays&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>&lt;p>I publish new Social Justice, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Resources.&lt;/p> &lt;a class="button" title="Join my mailing list" href="http://bit.ly/2MmE28c" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Get the Email.&lt;/a>&lt;/aside>
&lt;p>To achieve social justice we will have to break down a lot of huge barriers that exist on a scale far above the individual, but even the biggest scale change is nothing more than the sum of &lt;em>a whole lot&lt;/em> of individual efforts.  My goal with this site is to support you in doing just that: making big change on an individual level.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following are &lt;em>a whole&lt;/em> &lt;em>lot&lt;/em> of individual efforts you can make today that will be significant steps toward that biggest scale change we need for a socially just tomorrow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>30+ Examples of Middle-to-Upper Class Privileges</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/list-of-upperclass-privilege/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 01:36:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/list-of-upperclass-privilege/</guid><description>Following is a list of middle-to-upper class privileges. If you are a member of the middle class or upper class economic groups (or, in some cases, perceived to be) listed below are benefits that may be granted to you based on your group membership — benefits not granted to folks in the lower classes.</description></item><item><title>4 Reasons You Should Stop Saying “Non-Straight”</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/reasons-you-should-stop-saying-non-straight-and-say-queer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 18:13:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/reasons-you-should-stop-saying-non-straight-and-say-queer/</guid><description>With all the talk of marriage equality, gay comic book weddings, and even gayer flowcharts flowing around the web, people are getting ever more sensitive about using inclusive language when they can.
That’s great! But more often than ever I am hearing folks use the term “non-straight” to refer to people who are lesbian, gay, bi-, pan- or even trans*.</description></item><item><title>30+ Examples of Christian Privileges</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/list-of-examples-of-christian-privileg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 18:13:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/list-of-examples-of-christian-privileg/</guid><description>Following is a list of privileges granted to people in the U.S. (and many western nations) for being Christian.
💌Most Wednesdays
I publish new Social Justice, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Resources.
Get the Email. Please comment below if you have any additions or revisions to make!</description></item><item><title>5 Reasons My Approach to Social Justice Work is Better than Yours</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/5-reasons-my-approach-to-social-justice-work-is-better-than-yours/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 21:10:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/5-reasons-my-approach-to-social-justice-work-is-better-than-yours/</guid><description>&lt;p>The way I approach social justice and ally work on this site and &lt;a title="A show about snap judgments, identity, and oppression." href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/a-show-about-snap-judgments-identity-and-oppression/" target="_blank">in my show&lt;/a> has a distinct flavor.  Some would call it sweet, but I think &lt;a title="The Genderbread Person v2.0" href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/03/the-genderbread-person-v2-0/" target="_blank">ginger&lt;/a> is a bit spicy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t often do things by accident, and in this case it is very _on purpose.  _My flavor is even so noticeable that if you’ve seen a lot of what I’ve created here, you’re likely taken aback by the headline of this article.  Well, that actually leads me into my first point.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Reasons for being an Ally (AKA Social Justice Advocate)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/5-reasons-im-a-social-justice-all/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 20:00:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/5-reasons-im-a-social-justice-all/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hey, folks.  First of all, thanks for continuing to read what I write here, and thanks even more for sharing.  I don't say that enough.  I've been thinking a lot about why I do what I do lately, and I want to once-and-for-all answer a question I get asked an average of 1.6 times per day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Sam, why do you do what you do?&amp;rdquo; people say, but they are only saying half of what they're thinking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Depending on the context, they might be thinking, &amp;ldquo;Sam, if you're straight, why do you work so much for gay equality?&amp;rdquo;  Or &amp;ldquo;Sam, you're a man, why do you work so much for women's or trans people's equality&amp;rdquo;  Or &amp;ldquo;Sam, you're White, why do you care about equality for people of color?&amp;rdquo;  Or &amp;ldquo;Sam, you're a huge dork, why don't you do anything about that?&amp;rdquo;  And on it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My answer is different every time, because it's hard for me to get down to the absolute root of it all.  But let me provide some of the front-runner explanations for why I do what I do.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 Reasons Positive Stereotypes aren’t that Positive</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/reasons-positive-stereotypes-are-not-positive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 04:30:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/reasons-positive-stereotypes-are-not-positive/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a title="A show about snap judgments, identity, and oppression." href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/a-show-about-snap-judgments-identity-and-oppression/" target="_blank">my show&lt;/a>, I address the issue of positive stereotypes head-on, but I wanted to write an article about it as well.  For those of you unaware, positive stereotypes are assumptions about an entire group or identity (e.g., gay men) that are considered to be &amp;ldquo;good.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some examples of positive stereotypes of gay men: they are artsy, friendly, fun, social, well-spoken, well-dressed, well-groomed, fit, and sassy (I think sassy is positive).  The list goes on.  Those are all good things, yeah?  There can’t be any harm in perpetuating those stereotypes, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Positive stereotypes exist for just about every identity and have the capacity to be just as damaging as the negative ones.  Don’t believe me?  Read this list of reasons why and get back to me afterward.  Oh, and if you have any additional examples, as always, share them in the comments below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5+ Ways to Make Our World More Trans*-Friendly</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/list-of-ways-to-make-world-trans-friendl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 17:55:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/list-of-ways-to-make-world-trans-friendl/</guid><description>&lt;p>We live in a world that recognizes two options for gender.  If you’re not &lt;em>exactly&lt;/em> “man” or “woman” you’re going to have a hard time finding your place, because right now there isn’t a &lt;em>place&lt;/em> for you.  Let’s change that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is a list of suggestions to make the world a bit less binary and a lot more transgender inclusive.  Read ’em, live ’em, and add to ’em in the comments below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>10 reasons LEGOs aren’t for girls</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/10-reasonslegos-arent-for-girls/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 22:45:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/10-reasonslegos-arent-for-girls/</guid><description>Update: check out this video of a little girl explaining her frustration with gendered toys. It’s amazing how gendered toys are. If you see an action figure, you think boy. If you see a barbie, you think girl. If you see a boy with a barbie, you think gay.</description></item><item><title>30+ Examples of Heterosexual (Straight) Privileges</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/29-examples-of-heterosexual-privilege/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 23:03:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/29-examples-of-heterosexual-privilege/</guid><description>Following is a list of examples of heterosexual privilege. If you are straight, these are unearned benefits you receive as a result of the sexuality you were born with.
If you are straight (or in some cases, perceived to be), you can live without ever having to think twice, face, confront, engage, or cope with anything listed below.</description></item><item><title>30+ Examples of Cisgender Privileges</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/list-of-cisgender-privileges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 04:01:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/list-of-cisgender-privileges/</guid><description>Heads up!&amp;nbsp;I wrote a book all about gender that provides tools for standing up against gender-based oppression (like the things below) and working toward a socially justice society. If you appreciate all that jazz,&amp;nbsp;you’ll love this book. Following is a list of cisgender identity privileges.</description></item></channel></rss>