<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rant on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/rant/</link><description>Recent content in Rant on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 16:11:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>-isms, not -ists</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/isms-not-ists/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 16:11:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/isms-not-ists/</guid><description>&lt;p>To achieve the goals of &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/socialjustice/">social justice&lt;/a>, we need to reform society at the system level. We need to dismantle rac_ism_, sex_ism_, cissex_ism_, heterosex_ism_, gender_ism_, able_ism_, class_ism_, and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Too much of social justice discourse and calls-to-action are focused on the &lt;em>-ists&lt;/em>, the people participating in (and perpetuating) those systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Our focus on individual actors keeps increasing in social justice spaces&lt;/strong> I occupy. It’s almost all of what I notice in online social justice activism/advocacy. I’m guessing you’ve noticed it, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This focus often takes the form of &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/10/what-kind-of-social-justice-are-you-talking-about/">punitive social justice&lt;/a>, identifying perpetrators, dragging them, publicly shaming them, “canceling” them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Replacing One Binary with Another</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/binary-thinking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 16:43:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/binary-thinking/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve always believed that one of our superpowers as gender/sexuality activists, and &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/">social justice people&lt;/a> more broadly, is our ability to hold space for nuance. In the past few years, that belief has been crumbling. In part because of how much I’m seeing us replace one way of binary thinking for another.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a long time, we’ve known that sexuality isn’t a binary thing. It’s not gay/straight, either/or. It’s often both/and, neither, or another option altogether. &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kinsey_scale">The Kinsey Scale&lt;/a> often comes to mind here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More recently, we’ve recognized the same thing about gender. We’ve &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NRcPXtqdKjE">addressed the complexities of gender&lt;/a>, viewing it on a spectrum, &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/02/gender-scales-or-spectrums/">or, better, on scales&lt;/a>. And &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/breaking-through-the-binary-gender-explained-using-continuums/">broken through the binary&lt;/a> of woman/man. Just like sexuality, it’s not an either/or, but more of a both/and, neither, or another option altogether.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, it’s not entirely clear to me that everyone writing about binaries (e.g., the gender binary) is saying the same thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So allow me to be clear what I mean (and have always meant) by binary: two options. Two ways to be. Two categories. And that’s it. Only two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A binary can be succinctly summed up by this (no words needed):&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Hypocrisy Theatre Is, and Why It Doesn’t Work</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/hypocrisy-theatre/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 18:25:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/hypocrisy-theatre/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let’s say a friend of yours made a New Year’s resolution to stop being on their phone during dinner. It’s January 4th, you’re sharing a table, and you catch them peeping their insta. You call them on it, they apologize, and put their phone away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypocrisy, meet behavior. Behavior, meet change. &lt;em>Huzzah!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s how calling someone out on their hypocrisy &lt;em>works&lt;/em>. There are a few important factors here:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The person you’re calling out has stated (or otherwise believes) that they want to walk a particular (moral) path: &lt;strong>“From now on, I’m going to do X.”&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You notice their actions are contrary to that, and actively getting in the way of them living that espoused value, or walking their talk.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You point out this gap: “&lt;strong>You said you were going to do X, but now you’re doing Anti-X.”&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This prompts &lt;a href="https://www.verywellmind.com/what-is-cognitive-dissonance-2795012">cognitive dissonance&lt;/a>, and they have to pick a path: do as they said they’d do, or give up on that moral stance.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Each one of those four steps is necessary. They work as a chain reaction.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="welcome-to-hypocrisy-theatre-where-social-media-is-our-stage-and-our-audience-is-only-people-who-already-agree-with-us">Welcome to Hypocrisy Theatre: Where Social Media is Our Stage and Our Audience is Only People Who Already Agree With Us&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For several years now, there’s been a new show in town: Hypocrisy Theatre. And unlike the example above, Hypocrisy Theatre isn’t effective in changing the hypocrite’s behavior. Indeed, they’re not even part of the audience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe you’ve caught a performance of it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The cast changes daily, but the show always follows the same script: some random person on social media points out that some other random person they disagree with once said something that flies in the face of a thing they’re saying now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It often looks like this:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yes, gender is a social construction. No, that doesn’t mean it’s not real.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/09/yes-gender-is-a-social-construction-no-that-doesnt-mean-its-not-real/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 21:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/09/yes-gender-is-a-social-construction-no-that-doesnt-mean-its-not-real/</guid><description>&lt;p>Gender is a social construction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even if you take the most extreme &lt;a href="https://www.encyclopedia.com/science-and-technology/biology-and-genetics/biology-general/biological-determinism">biological determinist&lt;/a> stance (which a lot of the “gender isn’t a social construction” crowd take), you cannot deny the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>What it means to be a “woman” or “man” changes over time (often within the timeframe of a generation — ask your grandparents if you don’t believe me).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Further, right now, the traits associated with each of those roles are different in different parts of the world (watch a sitcom from another country if you don’t believe me).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If our understanding of gender changes faster than our biology could possibly evolve, and currently exists in many forms around the world reflecting cultural differences, it’s socially constructed. End of argument. That’s what those two words, combined, &lt;em>mean.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>And gender is real.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just because something’s a social construction doesn’t mean it’s not real (despite many fellow “social construction” folks saying so).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Social Justice Fandom (AKA Creating New Barriers in the Name of Dismantling Others)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/social-justice-fandom-aka-creating-new-barriers-name-dismantling-others/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 20:31:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/social-justice-fandom-aka-creating-new-barriers-name-dismantling-others/</guid><description>Maybe it was Glee. I don’t know. But at some point, within a small subsection of a small subsection of the population, social justice became cool. And whenever something becomes cool, two things tend to follow.
The first is that some of the people who like the cool thing start to covet it, protect it from outsiders, and claim it as their own — when just moments before those same people were making desperate pleas to others to like the thing they liked.</description></item><item><title>One Huge Prickly Reason Why Anti-LGBTQ Folks Don’t Change Their Views</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/01/ignored-reason-people-dont-affirm-lgbtq-people-make-harder/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 20:08:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/01/ignored-reason-people-dont-affirm-lgbtq-people-make-harder/</guid><description>I need you to take a leap with me.
Leap into the shoes of someone who has walked through their life knowing that being gay, being bi, lesbian, or pan, or that being non-binary, gender non-conforming, or trans — that being different, different from straight, different from cisgender — is wrong.</description></item><item><title>Let’s Talk About Bathrooms</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/03/lets-talk-about-bathrooms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 23:13:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/03/lets-talk-about-bathrooms/</guid><description>In the winter of 2013, I was bouncing around North America attending town halls. I was invited by local activists, trans* folks, and advocacy groups who wanted me to hear about or weigh in on a discussion that was taking center stage in their communities.</description></item><item><title>Every Shirt is Political.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/02/every-shirt-is-political/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 22:17:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/02/every-shirt-is-political/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Dear White, Straight, Cisgender, Man People: You Are Privileged</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/05/dear-white-straight-cisgender-men-privilege/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 17:17:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/05/dear-white-straight-cisgender-men-privilege/</guid><description>I’ve written about privilege here, and I’ve written my own privilege lists, inspired by Peggy McIntosh (blame her!), which have garnered a lot of hullabaloo on my site. Now, there seems to be a groundswell of backlash, where privileged people (like this super privileged Princeton student) are “denouncing their privilege” and “finally standing up for straight white guys” (HAHAHA).</description></item><item><title>I Have Not Given You Consent</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/i-have-not-given-you-consent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 23:43:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/i-have-not-given-you-consent/</guid><description>I work on the internet. It’s true. I write things for you to read (or not read), and spend a lot of my free time creating things that may (or may not) help you fill yours. I’m not asking for thanks, or really asking for you to do anything at all, but there are a few things I’m asking that you don’t do.</description></item><item><title>Solution for the “Confusing” Gender Neutral Toilet Sign Issue</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/gender-neutral-bathroom-sign/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 22:53:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/gender-neutral-bathroom-sign/</guid><description>A while ago I had the opportunity to sit in on some meetings where a group was lobbying their state legislators for gender neutral bathrooms. Recently, I attended a town hall where the same issue came up. In both cases, the elected officials were flabbergasted.</description></item><item><title>Being an Ally Between a Rock and a Hard Place</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/being-an-ally-between-a-rock-and-a-hard-place/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 23:14:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/being-an-ally-between-a-rock-and-a-hard-place/</guid><description>I’m an ally. I’ve written before why I’m an ally, and I’ve even once defended my allyship publicly, highlighting many of my privileged identities. But one thing I’ve never fully addressed is the double-edged-sword, Kobayashi-Maru-no-win scenario that _can be _what it means to be an ally like me.</description></item><item><title>5 Reasons Why So Many People Believe Feminism Hates Men and Why They’re Not True</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/12/reasons-people-believe-feminism-hates-men/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 06:10:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/12/reasons-people-believe-feminism-hates-men/</guid><description>&lt;p>“The feminist agenda is not about equal rights for women. It is about a socialist, anti-family political movement that encourages women to leave their husbands, kill their children, practice witchcraft, destroy capitalism, and become lesbians.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Pat Robertson famously said this in the 90s, and the sentiment still rings as true in the ears of many today.  It’s an understatement to say that &lt;a href="http://everydayfeminism.com/2012/07/feminist-myths/" title="How Most Things You Know About Feminists Are Vicious Conservative Lies">feminism has a bad rap.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feminism doesn’t hate men.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So why do so many people think feminism = man-hating? Let’s look at a few explanations for this fallacy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to respond when someone uses non-inclusive (or bigoted) language</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-respond-to-non-inclusive-language-or-bigoted-speec/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 21:24:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-respond-to-non-inclusive-language-or-bigoted-speec/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Intentions don’t matter, outcomes do&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->.  However, I still think we need to do a much better job of being supportive of newcomers to the social justice “scene” who may be well-intended, but don’t quite know the ropes yet.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is my picture guide (sorry, no &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->flowchart&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->) of how to properly handle such situations, without scaring off a potential ally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/how-to-respond-comic.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>4 Reasons You Should Stop Saying “Non-Straight”</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/reasons-you-should-stop-saying-non-straight-and-say-queer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 18:13:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/reasons-you-should-stop-saying-non-straight-and-say-queer/</guid><description>With all the talk of marriage equality, gay comic book weddings, and even gayer flowchartsflowing around the web, people are getting ever more sensitive about using inclusive language when they can.
That’s great! But more often than ever I am hearing folks use the term “non-straight” to refer to people who are lesbian, gay, bi-, pan- or even trans*.</description></item><item><title>I’m not anti-Christian, but religion shouldn’t have a place in political decisions.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/im-not-anti-religion-it-just-shouldnt-have-a-place-in-political-decisions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 23:25:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/im-not-anti-religion-it-just-shouldnt-have-a-place-in-political-decisions/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let’s make a deal. Promise me that you’ll do everything in your power to read this entire article (all 800 words of it) before you start mentally formulating the comment/email/death threat you’re going to respond with.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you can make that promise, read on.  If not, go find an website that reinforces your current dispositions on the matter and read that instead.  We’ll both be happier for it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5 Reasons My Approach to Social Justice Work is Better than Yours</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/5-reasons-my-approach-to-social-justice-work-is-better-than-yours/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 21:10:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/5-reasons-my-approach-to-social-justice-work-is-better-than-yours/</guid><description>&lt;p>The way I approach social justice and ally work on this site and &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->in my show&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> has a distinct flavor.  Some would call it sweet, but I think &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->ginger&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> is a bit spicy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t often do things by accident, and in this case it is very _on purpose.  _My flavor is even so noticeable that if you’ve seen a lot of what I’ve created here, you’re likely taken aback by the headline of this article.  Well, that actually leads me into my first point.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An open letter to Bradlee Dean (and all Biblical literalists who label homosexuality as sin)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/open-letter-to-biblical-literalists-on-homosexualit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 00:59:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/open-letter-to-biblical-literalists-on-homosexualit/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/bradley-dean.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>Bradlee Dean, heavy metal rocker slash minister, recently alluded that the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Muslims who were calling for execution of gays&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> are “more moral” than Christians (read about it at the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Huffington Post&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He’s since backtracked a lot, and wishy-washied, and etc.  But it’s as apparent how he truly feels as it is how bad he is at playing politics.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>Little Girl Goes on a Rant Over Pink Toys</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/little-girl-goes-on-a-rant-over-pink-toys-video/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 18:42:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/little-girl-goes-on-a-rant-over-pink-toys-video/</guid><description>How awesome is this?!
So many of us have experienced the frustration of being told something isn't for us &amp;ndash; something we wanted to wear, or play with, or be &amp;ndash; because of our gender. It's outrageous, and it's something that doesn't seem to be going away any time soon.</description></item><item><title>“Gay Marriage Equals” Poster</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/gay-marriage-equals-poster-print/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/gay-marriage-equals-poster-print/</guid><description>This poster is for Rick Santorum, et al. Same-sex marriages are happening, gays are serving openly in the military, and the world isn’t falling apart (well, maybe it is, but it was a preexisting condition).
Yet anti-human-rights activists like Santorum and the rest of the Slippery Slopers can’t help but remind us that gay marriage is just the beginning.</description></item><item><title>10 reasons LEGOs aren’t for girls</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/10-reasonslegos-arent-for-girls/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 22:45:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/10-reasonslegos-arent-for-girls/</guid><description>It’s amazing how gendered toys are. If you see an action figure, you think boy. If you see a barbie, you think girl. If you see a boy with a barbie, you think gay. And now LEGO is saying if you see LEGOs, you should think _boy – _that is, unless it’s a LadyFigs LEGO set (pictured below), then you should think girl girl girl.</description></item><item><title>The Corruption of the Golden Rule</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/the-corruption-of-the-golden-rule/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 21:25:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/the-corruption-of-the-golden-rule/</guid><description>Do unto others as you would have them do unto you. Right?
Wrong.
What we’ve been teaching our children, what I have learned and re-learned all of my life, is one of the worst pieces of advice around. What’s worse: it’s nearly universally accepted as gospel (pun intended).</description></item><item><title>If you call someone gay, he better be a guy who likes guys.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/if-you-call-someone-gay-he-better-be-a-guy-who-likes-guys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 21:32:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/if-you-call-someone-gay-he-better-be-a-guy-who-likes-guys/</guid><description>Gay isn’t a bad word, assuming you’re using it to describe a man who is attracted (physically, spiritually, and emotionally) to other men, (depending on label preference) a woman who is attracted to women, or anyone else who self-identifies as gay.</description></item></channel></rss>