<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Start Here on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/start-here/</link><description>Recent content in Start Here on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 23:09:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/start-here/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducing the Social Justice Compass</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 23:09:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you sailing the seas of social injustice, looking for a path toward equity, and in need of a tool that can point you in the right direction? Perhaps you are &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/social-justice-then-and-now/">rethinking how you &lt;em>do&lt;/em> social justice now&lt;/a>, today, in 2019 — with everything happening in the world — and searching for a new path forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Avast!&lt;/em> A new model for thinking about and doing social justice… &lt;em>ho&lt;/em>! This is off to a bad start. It turns out that every day can be &lt;a href="http://talklikeapirate.com/wordpress/">International Talk like a Pirate Day&lt;/a> if you don’t care about having friends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But if you care about social justice, friend, well, look no further!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, I’m happy to share with you a new model for thinking about social justice, for considering your actions, attitudes, and beliefs, and for guiding yourself and your community toward equity: The Social Justice Compass.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s dive right in.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Self-Guided Foundational Safe Zone Training</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/self-guided-foundational-safe-zone-training/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/self-guided-foundational-safe-zone-training/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Learn about your first impressions of LGBTQ+ people, core vocabulary, gender &amp;amp; sexuality theory, privilege &amp;amp; coming out, and get your questions answered.&amp;rdquo;
That's from the course description, and does a good job of summing this up. I co-created this course with Meg Bolger based on our years of experience facilitating countless in-person Safe Zone workshops.</description></item><item><title>What's the best way to view gender? As a Spectrum? Continuums?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/videos/gender-from-checkboxes-to-continuums/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/videos/gender-from-checkboxes-to-continuums/</guid><description>I was invited to give a Nerd Nite talk and speak about the subject I nerd out about the most: gender. And I got to talk about a lot of the dimensions of my work that I usually don't &amp;ndash; stuff that usually stays behind the scenes.</description></item><item><title>When Someone Comes Out To You: DO &amp; DON’T</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2016/04/when-someone-comes-out-to-you-do-dont/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 20:32:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2016/04/when-someone-comes-out-to-you-do-dont/</guid><description>In one of the first safe zone trainings I remember participating in, there was a loaded question about coming out that was followed by an excellent answer from the facilitator. The question was something like “Why don’t some people come out of the closet?</description></item><item><title>Your Ally is Someone Who… (A Few Ways to Be #BetterAllies)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/10/better-ally-week/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 19:29:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/10/better-ally-week/</guid><description>To celebrate GLSEN‘s Ally Week, It Gets Better and I put our heads together to create a series of images. These comics exemplify what _they _described as the top traits of better allies, and in my best ally fashion I used my doodling powers to elevate that message.</description></item><item><title>My TED Talk: Understanding the Complexities of Gender</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/my-ted-talk-understanding-the-complexities-of-gender/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/my-ted-talk-understanding-the-complexities-of-gender/</guid><description>I had the honor of being asked to give another TEDx talk, and they let me do it all about gender.
You can watch the video below, and see as I try to condense hundreds of pages of my book into 16 minutes of comprehensible, enjoyable, and sometimes-rhyming words.</description></item><item><title>Comprehensive* List of LGBTQ+ Vocabulary Definitions</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/01/a-comprehensive-list-of-lgbtq-term-definitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 23:46:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/01/a-comprehensive-list-of-lgbtq-term-definitions/</guid><description>Hi! This post is now available as part of an E-Book called &amp;#8220;Defining LGBTQ+&amp;#8221;. It includes the most recently updated definitions for all the terms below, the rules, and a bunch of other stuff. You can download it as a .</description></item><item><title>50+ concrete things you can do today to make for a more socially just tomorrow</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/11/things-you-can-do-today-for-social-justice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 05:34:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/11/things-you-can-do-today-for-social-justice/</guid><description>&lt;p>Social justice — the idea that everyone in a society, regardless of the identities they embody, can have an equitable shot at success and happiness — is a goal that seems unrealistic for many people. “It’s a pipe dream, Sam,” they say, smugly. “Life isn’t rainbows and butterflies,” they say, adorably.&lt;/p>
&lt;aside class="heyHeyLook wednesdayEmail">&lt;p>&lt;span class="icon">💌&lt;/span>&lt;strong>Most Wednesdays&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>&lt;p>I publish new Social Justice, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Resources.&lt;/p> &lt;a class="button" title="Join my mailing list" href="http://bit.ly/2MmE28c" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Get the Email.&lt;/a>&lt;/aside>
&lt;p>To achieve social justice we will have to break down a lot of huge barriers that exist on a scale far above the individual, but even the biggest scale change is nothing more than the sum of &lt;em>a whole lot&lt;/em> of individual efforts.  My goal with this site is to support you in doing just that: making big change on an individual level.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following are &lt;em>a whole&lt;/em> &lt;em>lot&lt;/em> of individual efforts you can make today that will be significant steps toward that biggest scale change we need for a socially just tomorrow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>You Soup: understanding diversity and the intersections of identity</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 19:17:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/</guid><description>&lt;p>In doing the work I do, I often find myself struggling to help people make sense of the two extremes of identity: on one side we have the idea that people in a group are all the same (stereotypes); while the other side supports this idea that everyone is absolutely unique (snowflakes).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I find myself saying “we’re not the same, but we’re also not that different,” to the furrowing of brows, so I wanted to take a moment here to talk about the relationship of individual identity and social group memberships, as well as introduce a new graphic concept.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to respond when someone uses non-inclusive (or bigoted) language</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-respond-to-non-inclusive-language-or-bigoted-speec/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 21:24:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-respond-to-non-inclusive-language-or-bigoted-speec/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a title="Why your intentions don’t really matter, but outcomes do" href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/why-your-intentions-dont-matter-victim-blaming-and-political-correctness/" target="_blank">Intentions don’t matter, outcomes do&lt;/a>.  However, I still think we need to do a much better job of being supportive of newcomers to the social justice “scene” who may be well-intended, but don’t quite know the ropes yet.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is my picture guide (sorry, no &lt;a title="Even better flowchart: when it’s okay to say “gay”" href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/even-better-flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-gay/" target="_blank">flowchart&lt;/a>) of how to properly handle such situations, without scaring off a potential ally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/how-to-respond-comic.jpg">&lt;img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1835 lazy-load" title="&amp;quot;How to Respond&amp;quot; Comic" data-src="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/how-to-respond-comic.jpg" alt="&amp;quot;How to Respond&amp;quot; Comic" width="800" height="3900" data-srcset="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/how-to-respond-comic.jpg 800w, https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/how-to-respond-comic-210x1024.jpg 210w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Flowchart: I Want To Say Gay (When it’s Okay)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/even-better-flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-gay/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 19:34:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/even-better-flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-gay/</guid><description>When I published my original flowchart, I said it was for the more analytical folks who are wondering if “gay” is the right word choice for them. Well, this one is for the most analytical folks, and also folks who enjoy data presented in cute and adorable ways.</description></item><item><title>3 Reasons Positive Stereotypes aren’t that Positive</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/reasons-positive-stereotypes-are-not-positive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 04:30:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/reasons-positive-stereotypes-are-not-positive/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a title="A show about snap judgments, identity, and oppression." href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/a-show-about-snap-judgments-identity-and-oppression/" target="_blank">my show&lt;/a>, I address the issue of positive stereotypes head-on, but I wanted to write an article about it as well.  For those of you unaware, positive stereotypes are assumptions about an entire group or identity (e.g., gay men) that are considered to be &amp;ldquo;good.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some examples of positive stereotypes of gay men: they are artsy, friendly, fun, social, well-spoken, well-dressed, well-groomed, fit, and sassy (I think sassy is positive).  The list goes on.  Those are all good things, yeah?  There can’t be any harm in perpetuating those stereotypes, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Positive stereotypes exist for just about every identity and have the capacity to be just as damaging as the negative ones.  Don’t believe me?  Read this list of reasons why and get back to me afterward.  Oh, and if you have any additional examples, as always, share them in the comments below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Flowchart: when it’s okay to say “that’s so gay”</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-thats-so-gay-prin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 22:10:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-thats-so-gay-prin/</guid><description>For the more analytical folks, we created a handy flowchart to help make the decision “Is ‘gay’ the right word for me?”
As you can tell, in most cases, the answer is no. Print, post, and share freely.</description></item><item><title>5+ Ways to Make Our World More Trans*-Friendly</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/list-of-ways-to-make-world-trans-friendl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 17:55:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/list-of-ways-to-make-world-trans-friendl/</guid><description>&lt;p>We live in a world that recognizes two options for gender.  If you’re not &lt;em>exactly&lt;/em> “man” or “woman” you’re going to have a hard time finding your place, because right now there isn’t a &lt;em>place&lt;/em> for you.  Let’s change that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is a list of suggestions to make the world a bit less binary and a lot more transgender inclusive.  Read ’em, live ’em, and add to ’em in the comments below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>When to use the word “gay”</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/when-to-use-the-word-gay-print/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 00:14:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/when-to-use-the-word-gay-print/</guid><description>When is it &amp;ldquo;okay&amp;rdquo; to say gay? Why is this even a question we need to be asking? Well, because it seems that people have some misconceptions, and this flowchart makes it simple.
This graphic was originally created to support this article, but then a comment was made saying this should be hung on every dorm wall in America.</description></item><item><title>Political Correctness VS. Inclusiveness</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/political-correct-versus-being-inclusiv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 21:41:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/political-correct-versus-being-inclusiv/</guid><description>I would never ask you to be politically correct. I’ve gotten some flak from my “When Gay is Okay” and “Why I say partner” articles. People feel that I’m soap-boxing for political correctness, when that couldn’t be further from the truth.</description></item><item><title>The Corruption of the Golden Rule</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/the-corruption-of-the-golden-rule/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 21:25:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/the-corruption-of-the-golden-rule/</guid><description>Do unto others as you would have them do unto you. Right?
Wrong.
What we’ve been teaching our children, what I have learned and re-learned all of my life, is one of the worst pieces of advice around. What’s worse: it’s nearly universally accepted as gospel (pun intended).</description></item><item><title>A visual aid: when “gay” is okay</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/a-visual-aid-when-gay-okay-to-sa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 21:51:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/a-visual-aid-when-gay-okay-to-sa/</guid><description>Created a printer-friendly version of the first graphic (and a high-resolution version). Check it, share it, print it, love it. Also, check out the new-and-improved flowchart. For those of you still struggling with the idea of when it is and isn’t ideal to use the word “gay”, even after reading my article outlining the whole idea, I decided to create a few visual aids.</description></item><item><title>30+ Examples of Cisgender Privileges</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/list-of-cisgender-privileges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 04:01:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/list-of-cisgender-privileges/</guid><description>Heads up!&amp;nbsp;I wrote a book all about gender that provides tools for standing up against gender-based oppression (like the things below) and working toward a socially justice society. If you appreciate all that jazz,&amp;nbsp;you’ll love this book. Following is a list of cisgender identity privileges.</description></item><item><title>Breaking through the binary: Gender explained using continuums</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/breaking-through-the-binary-gender-explained-using-continuums/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 03:15:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/breaking-through-the-binary-gender-explained-using-continuums/</guid><description>&lt;address class="focus">
&lt;strong>Update:&lt;/strong> &lt;a title="The Genderbread Person v4" href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/10/the-genderbread-person-v4/">View my newest version of the Genderbread Person, version 4 here.&lt;/a>  It&amp;#8217;s a heckuvalot better and just as free to use however you&amp;#8217;d like! And here is the &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/genderbread-person/">Genderbread Person page&lt;/a> with downloads and all versions.
&lt;/address>
&lt;p>Gender is a tough subject to tackle.  There are a lot of facets to consider, a lot of pressures at play, and we have all been conditioned in such a way that our first instinct is almost unanimously wrong.  But we’re going to tackle it.  No, we’re going to tackle the snot out of it.  Coming to our aid, I would like to present to you: The Genderbread Person!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>