<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Humor on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/humor/</link><description>Recent content in Humor on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 17:34:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/humor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What's the best way to view gender? As a Spectrum? Continuums?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/videos/gender-from-checkboxes-to-continuums/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/videos/gender-from-checkboxes-to-continuums/</guid><description>I was invited to give a Nerd Nite talk and speak about the subject I nerd out about the most: gender. And I got to talk about a lot of the dimensions of my work that I usually don't &amp;ndash; stuff that usually stays behind the scenes.</description></item><item><title>9+ Silly Gender Comics I drew in 5 Minutes or Less</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/silly-gender-comics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 01:19:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/silly-gender-comics/</guid><description>I made all of these comics for my book. Some of them are in there. Some didn’t make the cut. And many more that aren’t here did. Hope they give you a gender-equity giggle.</description></item><item><title>My TED Talk: Understanding the Complexities of Gender</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/my-ted-talk-understanding-the-complexities-of-gender/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/my-ted-talk-understanding-the-complexities-of-gender/</guid><description>I had the honor of being asked to give another TEDx talk, and they let me do it all about gender.
You can watch the video below, and see as I try to condense hundreds of pages of my book into 16 minutes of comprehensible, enjoyable, and sometimes-rhyming words.</description></item><item><title>30+ Examples of Masculine Dude (“Bro”) Privileges</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/02/30-examples-of-masculine-dude-bro-privilege/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 23:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/02/30-examples-of-masculine-dude-bro-privilege/</guid><description>I’ve written a few privilege lists, several of which are about privileged identities I possess. They are serious articles that provide a couple hundred examples of systemic oppression (in the US and elsewhere). This article is not that.
I ask that you please humor me as I take a moment to address the many privileges I _don’t _have access to, due to my gender expression/ metrosexuality.</description></item><item><title>How To Avoid Being a Stereotype</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-avoid-being-a-stereotype/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 23:57:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-avoid-being-a-stereotype/</guid><description>&lt;p>You want to be seen as an individual, right?  Of course you do.  But it’s bordering on impossible to avoid perpetuating at least some of the stereotypes attached to the various aspects of your identity.  There are just too many of them!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, that’s where I can help.  Consider this a “How to be [X], without being a stereotypical [X]” guide.  I’m hitting a variety of major identities, but feel free to request addendums to the guide in the comments below, on &lt;a href="http://facebook.com/metrosam" title="http://facebook.com/metrosam">Facebook&lt;/a>, or on &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Twitter&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, if you’re more prone to spot-reading than reading-reading, &lt;strong>I strongly encourage you to at least read the last section before you formulate your reaction to this article&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without further ado, in alphabetical order…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to respond when someone uses non-inclusive (or bigoted) language</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-respond-to-non-inclusive-language-or-bigoted-speec/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 21:24:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-respond-to-non-inclusive-language-or-bigoted-speec/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Intentions don’t matter, outcomes do&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->.  However, I still think we need to do a much better job of being supportive of newcomers to the social justice “scene” who may be well-intended, but don’t quite know the ropes yet.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is my picture guide (sorry, no &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->flowchart&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->) of how to properly handle such situations, without scaring off a potential ally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/how-to-respond-comic.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Toyota airs a Gay-Friendly Super Bowl Commercial</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/toyota-airs-a-gay-friendly-super-bowl-commercial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 17:29:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/toyota-airs-a-gay-friendly-super-bowl-commercial/</guid><description>Hello, Toyota.
@EricTeskepointed out the Super Bowl ad below, with the following comment:
The add features a decidedly gay-friendly moment, and we’re not talking about the Lionel Richie (he’s straight, folks). About 8 seconds in a man is presented with options for a super-hot near-naked ladies couch, or a super-hot near-naked dudes couch.</description></item><item><title>Little Girl Goes on a Rant Over Pink Toys</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/little-girl-goes-on-a-rant-over-pink-toys-video/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 18:42:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/little-girl-goes-on-a-rant-over-pink-toys-video/</guid><description>How awesome is this?!
So many of us have experienced the frustration of being told something isn't for us &amp;ndash; something we wanted to wear, or play with, or be &amp;ndash; because of our gender. It's outrageous, and it's something that doesn't seem to be going away any time soon.</description></item><item><title>10 reasons LEGOs aren’t for girls</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/10-reasonslegos-arent-for-girls/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 22:45:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/10-reasonslegos-arent-for-girls/</guid><description>It’s amazing how gendered toys are. If you see an action figure, you think boy. If you see a barbie, you think girl. If you see a boy with a barbie, you think gay. And now LEGO is saying if you see LEGOs, you should think _boy – _that is, unless it’s a LadyFigs LEGO set (pictured below), then you should think girl girl girl.</description></item><item><title>Why same-sex marriage is constitutional, and marrying a toaster is not.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/why-same-sex-marriage-is-constitutional-and-marrying-a-toaster-is-not/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 21:07:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/why-same-sex-marriage-is-constitutional-and-marrying-a-toaster-is-not/</guid><description>A graphic representation of an issue that should be simpler than it is, but it always leading to absurd slippery-slope arguments.
Below is a wonderful graphic that was shared with me that does a fantastic job of clearing the whole thing up.</description></item></channel></rss>