<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Social Justice on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/categories/social-justice/</link><description>Recent content in Social Justice on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 17:34:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/categories/social-justice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Maybe we should stop using “White supremacist” and “bad” interchangeably?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/07/maybe-we-should-stop-using-white-supremacist-and-bad-interchangeably/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 17:34:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/07/maybe-we-should-stop-using-white-supremacist-and-bad-interchangeably/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, I’ve been noticing this weird trend. It’s become prevalent within the social justice movement, and I haven’t seen anyone else flag it. I brought it up in the context of our &lt;a href="https://www.sjmd.space">Social Justice, Minus Dogma Course + Community&lt;/a>, and it turns out other people are noticing it too. So let’s flag it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The short version is this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of people are using domination/oppression language (e.g., “white supremacist”, “patriarchal”) as synonyms for “bad” and marginalization/anti-oppression language (e.g., “indigenous,” “decolonized,” “feminist”) as synonyms for “good” — devoid of any meaningful connection to the actual structure, system, or culture they’re mentioning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My guess is that it’s a combination of our &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/isms-not-ists/">over focusing on “-ists” instead of “-isms”&lt;/a> plus the &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-social-justice-power-inverse/">“social justice power inverse,”&lt;/a> but I’ll leave the detective work up to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why highlight this at all? In short, because actual, sincere, real-life White supremacy is on the rise, and we need to be able to call it when we see it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Calling things “White supremacist” that aren’t creates a lot of unhelpful noise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wrote this article a few days before we got a blazingly clear example of White supremacy in action, when &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1150381394234941448">U.S. President Donald Trump went on a “go back to your country” rant&lt;/a> against several members of congress, all of whom are women of color.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Being careful to use the phrase “White supremacy” correctly would allow a criticism of Trump’s rant, and other White supremacist actions, to be held as distinct from general criticisms of Trump.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Both are totally valid, by the way! However, we need to know which basket we’re putting our eggs into.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We need to be able to separate “I don’t like what you’re saying” from “What you’re saying is advancing White supremacy and ethnic cleansing.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And right now we’re not doing a good job of that, at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll explain what I’m talking about in more detail, then talk about a few of the reasons &lt;em>I&lt;/em> think this is (deeply) unhelpful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’d be curious to hear what you think, if you’re also noticing this. We’ll make space for that, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="8220white-supremacist8221-doesn8217t-mean-a-8220white-person-doing-something-bad8221">“White Supremacist” doesn’t mean a “White person doing something bad”&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Let me first say that, overall, it’s great that more people are becoming comfy using phrases like “white supremacist.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The same goes for words like “patriarchal,” “colonial,” “heterosexist,” etc. They’re useful words that can be used to pinpoint exactly what we’re talking about, concerned about in society, and wanting to change.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(If we could just add “capitalist” to our comfort zone, &lt;a href="https://www.mediaed.org/transcripts/Bell-Hooks-Transcript.pdf">we might even make bell hooks proud&lt;/a>.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The issue I’m flagging here is&lt;/strong> &lt;em>&lt;strong>not&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> &lt;strong>the use of the phrase “white supremacist”&lt;/strong> (or any of these other words I’m lumping together as domination/oppression language).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The issue is people using these words like duct tape, sticking them to every problem they notice.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here’s what it looks like in general:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Social Justice Minus Dogma Online Course</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/social-justice-minus-dogma-course/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/social-justice-minus-dogma-course/</guid><description>Over the course of 6 weeks of self-guided learning (or however long you choose), explore the social justice dogma, identify its cornerstones and pitfalls, and plot a path forward toward true living social justice.
This course is an extension of all the writing I've done here about &amp;ldquo;social justice dogma.</description></item><item><title>How much injustice can we justify on the path toward social justice?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/05/justifying-injustice-for-social-justice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:36:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/05/justifying-injustice-for-social-justice/</guid><description>&lt;p>Close your eyes and imagine the world you would describe as living social justice. Equitable. Utopian, even. Whatever comes to mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Give it a shot. I’ll wait a moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What does it feel like to occupy that [future world][1] where all of our work as [social justice people][2] came to fruition?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How does it differ from our world today?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How radical of a difference you notice will be determined by the world you have in your mind. But surely the ways we spend our time, the social problems we grapple with, and even the ways we organize societies aren’t the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What do “jobs” look like? Do they even still exist? What about politics? What will there be more of? What will there be less of?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There’s likely a long list of [actions, attitudes, and beliefs][3] that wouldn’t make sense in that world, but seem perfectly sensical in our world right now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What comes to mind?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Focus on the gap, the distance between what would be normal in a socially-just world, compared to what is normal now in our oppressive and unjust world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay, now here comes the really tough part:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>-isms, not -ists</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/isms-not-ists/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 16:11:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/isms-not-ists/</guid><description>&lt;p>To achieve the goals of &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/socialjustice/">social justice&lt;/a>, we need to reform society at the system level. We need to dismantle rac_ism_, sex_ism_, cissex_ism_, heterosex_ism_, gender_ism_, able_ism_, class_ism_, and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Too much of social justice discourse and calls-to-action are focused on the &lt;em>-ists&lt;/em>, the people participating in (and perpetuating) those systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Our focus on individual actors keeps increasing in social justice spaces&lt;/strong> I occupy. It’s almost all of what I notice in online social justice activism/advocacy. I’m guessing you’ve noticed it, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This focus often takes the form of &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/10/what-kind-of-social-justice-are-you-talking-about/">punitive social justice&lt;/a>, identifying perpetrators, dragging them, publicly shaming them, “canceling” them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Privilege Lie</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/the-privilege-lie/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 23:41:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/the-privilege-lie/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve said it myself. I’ve read it a hundred times. You’ve probably heard it, or said it yourself. It usually goes something like, “We’re not asking you to give up your privileges. We’re trying to grant access to others who don’t have them.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or a pie analogy: “Privilege isn’t like pie. You don’t have to give up your slice for others to enjoy it.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The idea behind these sentiments is that the goal of &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/socialjustice/">social justice&lt;/a> is not to take privileges away&lt;/strong> from the “privileged” and give them to the “oppressed” (&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/binary-thinking/">an unhelpful binary&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/privilege-lists/">list privileges&lt;/a> (e.g., &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/11/30-examples-of-male-privilege/">male privileges&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/list-of-cisgender-privileges/">cisgender privileges&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/list-of-examples-of-christian-privileg/">Christian privileges&lt;/a>) and ask people to “check their privilege,” we say we’re not asking them to give anything up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Instead, we say that the goal is for &lt;em>everyone&lt;/em> to have access to those privileges.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We say this, usually, as a defense to [privileged] people pushing back against our goals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>And it’s a lie. A well-intentioned lie, but a lie nonetheless.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Replacing One Binary with Another</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/binary-thinking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 16:43:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/binary-thinking/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve always believed that one of our superpowers as gender/sexuality activists, and &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/">social justice people&lt;/a> more broadly, is our ability to hold space for nuance. In the past few years, that belief has been crumbling. In part because of how much I’m seeing us replace one way of binary thinking for another.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a long time, we’ve known that sexuality isn’t a binary thing. It’s not gay/straight, either/or. It’s often both/and, neither, or another option altogether. &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kinsey_scale">The Kinsey Scale&lt;/a> often comes to mind here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More recently, we’ve recognized the same thing about gender. We’ve &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NRcPXtqdKjE">addressed the complexities of gender&lt;/a>, viewing it on a spectrum, &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/02/gender-scales-or-spectrums/">or, better, on scales&lt;/a>. And &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/breaking-through-the-binary-gender-explained-using-continuums/">broken through the binary&lt;/a> of woman/man. Just like sexuality, it’s not an either/or, but more of a both/and, neither, or another option altogether.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, it’s not entirely clear to me that everyone writing about binaries (e.g., the gender binary) is saying the same thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So allow me to be clear what I mean (and have always meant) by binary: two options. Two ways to be. Two categories. And that’s it. Only two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A binary can be succinctly summed up by this (no words needed):&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Social Justice Power Inverse</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-social-justice-power-inverse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 18:19:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-social-justice-power-inverse/</guid><description>&lt;p>A lot of social justice conversations focus on power. Who has power in society and who doesn’t?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We highlight how systems inequitably distribute power to some while withholding it from others — based on &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/">who we are&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We refer to people who are granted disproportionate power as “privileged,” “majoritized,” “centered,” etc. And those from whom power is withheld as “oppressed,” “minoritized,” “marginalized,” etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, nobody is only one of those two. We’re both, depending on which situation we’re in, and what dimensions of ourselves are brought to the forefront.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our goal in talking about this is dismantling inequitable power structures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/">The needle on our compass points toward equity.&lt;/a> Removing barriers, promoting access, and shrinking the gap between the “haves” and “have nots” — or, in &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-two-worlds-dilemma/">a perfect world&lt;/a>, making that dichotomy irrelevant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the things we don’t talk about is how power structures manifest in social justice spaces, or the micro-society that is the community of &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/">social justice people&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here, we preserve the idea of the power structure, but swap out who sits where.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Two Worlds Dilemma</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-two-worlds-dilemma/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 18:37:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-two-worlds-dilemma/</guid><description>&lt;p>Every justice movement — from &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/gender-2/">gender&lt;/a>, to &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/sexuality">sexuality&lt;/a>, to &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/">every other dimension&lt;/a> of who we are and how the world sees us — has to answer two big questions: What’s wrong with the world now? And what future world do you want to create?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m the fly on the wall for thousands of conversations about &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/socialjustice/">social justice&lt;/a>. And a lot of what I witness online and in-person (in workshops and conferences and retreats) goes off the rails because of &lt;strong>The Two Worlds Dilemma&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Incoming: “Social Justice, Minus Dogma” Course + Community</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/social-justice-dogma-course-community/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 19:49:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/social-justice-dogma-course-community/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over 1,000 of you said you’d want to participate in an &lt;a href="https://mailchi.mp/970acc41bb9c/social-justice-minus-dogma">online course and community focusing on Social Justice, Minus Dogma&lt;/a>. So I’m going to hold up my end of the bargain and make the thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>First, I want to say how blown away I am that so many people are up for this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a few weeks, I showed a question at the top of the site to some readers asking if you’d want to participate in a course about “social justice, minus dogma.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m wasn’t sure what to expect, but I was bracing for &lt;em>bad&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How (Not) To Use a Privilege List</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/how-not-to-use-a-privilege-list/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 18:34:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/how-not-to-use-a-privilege-list/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/privilege-lists/">Privilege Lists&lt;/a> that &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/about/about-sam-killermann/">I’ve&lt;/a> published &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/about/">here&lt;/a> have been downloaded over 100 million times cumulatively. I share this because it’s cool to say (big number!), but also because that reach has allowed me to see these lists used in a variety of ways: some good, some neutral, and some downright harmful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ways to use a privilege list are innumerable, and the creativity I’ve witnessed has been astounding. As a tool, they can be transformative.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So instead of using this space to advocate for ways I encourage using the lists, it’ll be easier to write few quick “Please Don’t Do This” bullets:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introducing the Social Justice Compass</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 23:09:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you sailing the seas of social injustice, looking for a path toward equity, and in need of a tool that can point you in the right direction? Perhaps you are &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/social-justice-then-and-now/">rethinking how you &lt;em>do&lt;/em> social justice now&lt;/a>, today, in 2019 — with everything happening in the world — and searching for a new path forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Avast!&lt;/em> A new model for thinking about and doing social justice… &lt;em>ho&lt;/em>! This is off to a bad start. It turns out that every day can be &lt;a href="http://talklikeapirate.com/wordpress/">International Talk like a Pirate Day&lt;/a> if you don’t care about having friends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But if you care about social justice, friend, well, look no further!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, I’m happy to share with you a new model for thinking about social justice, for considering your actions, attitudes, and beliefs, and for guiding yourself and your community toward equity: The Social Justice Compass.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s dive right in.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If You’re Still Doing Social Justice How You Were Then, Reconsider.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/social-justice-then-and-now/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 19:41:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/social-justice-then-and-now/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve seen people at conferences giving the same talk they gave two years ago. Activists speaking and organizing in ways unchanged since 2015. Educators facilitating workshops with a curriculum written in 2012.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The world is different now than it was then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The people you’re working with — or against, or for — have different mindsets, beliefs, knowledge, perspectives, values, opinions, grudges, predispositions, awarenesses, and biases now than they did then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The world you’re working in — and trying to improve — is comprised of different technologies, constituencies, zeitgeists, cultural norms, and public knowledge now than it was then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the “then” could be yesterday. Or last year. Your “then” could be “before Trump was elected. Or “when we didn’t know this huge thing.” Or “before ‘Black Lives Matter’ activism started.” Or “when we weren’t sure whether this one thing would work or not.” Or “before our community experienced that travesty.” Or “when we didn’t have social media.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I started doing social justice work, most people didn’t know what “social justice” meant. They’d never heard the phrase. It was brand new to them. That was the first bar to jump: explaining &lt;em>what I was working to do&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s a “then”: when most people I encountered hadn’t heard the phrase “social justice.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Hypocrisy Theatre Is, and Why It Doesn’t Work</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/hypocrisy-theatre/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 18:25:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/hypocrisy-theatre/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let’s say a friend of yours made a New Year’s resolution to stop being on their phone during dinner. It’s January 4th, you’re sharing a table, and you catch them peeping their insta. You call them on it, they apologize, and put their phone away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hypocrisy, meet behavior. Behavior, meet change. &lt;em>Huzzah!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s how calling someone out on their hypocrisy &lt;em>works&lt;/em>. There are a few important factors here:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The person you’re calling out has stated (or otherwise believes) that they want to walk a particular (moral) path: &lt;strong>“From now on, I’m going to do X.”&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You notice their actions are contrary to that, and actively getting in the way of them living that espoused value, or walking their talk.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>You point out this gap: “&lt;strong>You said you were going to do X, but now you’re doing Anti-X.”&lt;/strong>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This prompts &lt;a href="https://www.verywellmind.com/what-is-cognitive-dissonance-2795012">cognitive dissonance&lt;/a>, and they have to pick a path: do as they said they’d do, or give up on that moral stance.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Each one of those four steps is necessary. They work as a chain reaction.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="welcome-to-hypocrisy-theatre-where-social-media-is-our-stage-and-our-audience-is-only-people-who-already-agree-with-us">Welcome to Hypocrisy Theatre: Where Social Media is Our Stage and Our Audience is Only People Who Already Agree With Us&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For several years now, there’s been a new show in town: Hypocrisy Theatre. And unlike the example above, Hypocrisy Theatre isn’t effective in changing the hypocrite’s behavior. Indeed, they’re not even part of the audience.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe you’ve caught a performance of it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The cast changes daily, but the show always follows the same script: some random person on social media points out that some other random person they disagree with once said something that flies in the face of a thing they’re saying now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It often looks like this:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Elephant in Every Socially-Just Room</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/12/the-elephant-in-every-socially-just-room/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 20:45:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/12/the-elephant-in-every-socially-just-room/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the past year, I’ve been in conversation with folks about what I’ve been calling the “Social Justice Dogma.” I’ve &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/12/introduction-social-justice-dogma/">written&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/12/why-i-finally-broke-silence-social-justice-dogma/">about&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tag/social-justice-dogma">it&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/06/unhelpful-tenets-social-justice-dogma/">here&lt;/a> (&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tag/social-justice-dogma">read all&lt;/a>), &lt;a href="https://hereticpodcast.com/updates/want-to-be-a-guest-want-to-nominate-one-yes-please-heres-how/">tried to interview people&lt;/a> about it for a &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/videos-podcasts/">podcast&lt;/a>, and I’ve been having lots and lots of phone calls with social justice educators.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In &lt;em>literally&lt;/em> every case, when I’d start a conversation about Social Justice Dogma (SJD), the person I was talking with recognized the phenomenon, without me needing to explain what I meant —  even if they’d never heard the phrase “social justice dogma.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They’d reply with something like, “Oh, I know what you’re talking about,” or “Oh yeah, that’s a big thing in my circle.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then we’d get into some particular tenet that they were struggling with. Or talk through a recent current event, using the dogma as the lens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the conversations generally ended the same, with them saying something like “I’m happy you’re talking about this” or “This conversation is needed” or “I’m looking forward to seeing more on this.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But then the conversation ended.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What kind of “Social Justice” are you talking about?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/10/what-kind-of-social-justice-are-you-talking-about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 20:57:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/10/what-kind-of-social-justice-are-you-talking-about/</guid><description>&lt;p>I had lunch with a friend this week, and our conversation hit a peculiar roadblock: A lot of people are saying the same words — “social justice” — but meaning different things. This is a problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When you say “social justice,” what kind of justice are you talking about?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 Tenets of Social Justice Dogma that are Getting in Our Way</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/06/unhelpful-tenets-social-justice-dogma/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 17:46:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/06/unhelpful-tenets-social-justice-dogma/</guid><description>Now that I’ve been talking openly about Social Justice Dogma (SJD) for a few months, I have some findings I want to share. Below I’ve written about a bunch of tenets of the SJD that are likely unhelpful, counter-productive, or downright obstructive to the goals of social justice.</description></item><item><title>Social Justice Fandom (AKA Creating New Barriers in the Name of Dismantling Others)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/social-justice-fandom-aka-creating-new-barriers-name-dismantling-others/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 20:31:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/social-justice-fandom-aka-creating-new-barriers-name-dismantling-others/</guid><description>Maybe it was Glee. I don’t know. But at some point, within a small subsection of a small subsection of the population, social justice became cool. And whenever something becomes cool, two things tend to follow.
The first is that some of the people who like the cool thing start to covet it, protect it from outsiders, and claim it as their own — when just moments before those same people were making desperate pleas to others to like the thing they liked.</description></item><item><title>The Magical Power of “Some” for Social Justice Educators</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/magical-power-social-justice-educators/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 22:56:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/magical-power-social-justice-educators/</guid><description>There are few things that changed how effective of a social justice educator I was as much as the word “some.”
It started as a way to correct people, or redirect them, or respond to problematic questions.
Someone would ask something like “When people say they’re bisexual, isn’t it really just a phase?</description></item><item><title>Some Different Taxonomies for Social Justice People</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 22:29:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/</guid><description>We often group social justice people by identity, cause, or “-ism” (e.g., racial justice people, gender justice, queer justice, wage justice). People outside of the social justice movement seem inclined to group SJ people as being either “social justice warriors” or not.</description></item><item><title>One Huge Prickly Reason Why Anti-LGBTQ Folks Don’t Change Their Views</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/01/ignored-reason-people-dont-affirm-lgbtq-people-make-harder/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 20:08:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/01/ignored-reason-people-dont-affirm-lgbtq-people-make-harder/</guid><description>I need you to take a leap with me.
Leap into the shoes of someone who has walked through their life knowing that being gay, being bi, lesbian, or pan, or that being non-binary, gender non-conforming, or trans — that being different, different from straight, different from cisgender — is wrong.</description></item><item><title>Why I Finally Broke My Silence about the Social Justice Dogma</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/12/why-i-finally-broke-silence-social-justice-dogma/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 02:27:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/12/why-i-finally-broke-silence-social-justice-dogma/</guid><description>A few days ago I wrote what I described as the scariest thing I’ve ever published to this site. So why did I do it? Why take the risk? That’s what I want to write about today.
Now, I know “scariest” is a relative term.</description></item><item><title>I can’t stop thinking about the “Social Justice Dogma,” or keeping quiet.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/12/introduction-social-justice-dogma/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 21:04:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/12/introduction-social-justice-dogma/</guid><description>Last spring, I got to spend a couple weeks in rural Ontario giving a few dozen (!) talks, assemblies, and shows at schools and organizations around the province. Every time I visit the Ontario countryside, I’m struck by how much it reminds me of my now-home state of Texas, in ways that are equal parts comfy (lots of hospitality) and uncomfy (lots of camouflage and usage of the word “lifestyle”).</description></item><item><title>Every Shirt is Political.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/02/every-shirt-is-political/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 22:17:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/02/every-shirt-is-political/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Taking Up Space vs. Adding to a Space: Questions to Consider</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/02/taking-up-space-vs-adding-to-a-space-questions-to-consider/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 22:46:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/02/taking-up-space-vs-adding-to-a-space-questions-to-consider/</guid><description>A lot of us want to just “be people,” and leave our social identities at the door when we enter a room. In September 2016, I was asked to participate in Katie Couric’s “Gender Revolution” documentary (by National Geographic). The following questions were what I worked through — and what I generally work through — when deciding to say “yes” or “no.</description></item><item><title>A Few Small Tips for Attending Your First Protest March</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/01/a-few-small-tips-for-attending-your-first-protest-march/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 23:28:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/01/a-few-small-tips-for-attending-your-first-protest-march/</guid><description>I’ve organized and participated in a lot of political resistance over the years. From high school walkouts, to college sit-ins, to guerrilla activism campaigns, to marches and public demonstrations. And I’m guessing that a lot of folks in the U.S. may be wading into these waters for the first time this year (because Trump presidency year one), or this week (because Women’s March on Washington).</description></item><item><title>Unlocking the Magic of Facilitation</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/books/unlocking-the-magic-of-facilitation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 00:21:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/books/unlocking-the-magic-of-facilitation/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Meg and Sam have given us a gift; their book is smartly designed to invite new and seasoned facilitators to be intentional about having those tough group discussions. As an educator and facilitator, this book gives me a framework to understand my own facilitation style, and ways that I can continue to improve.</description></item><item><title>Empathy leads to Understanding</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/10/empathy-leads-to-understanding/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2014 21:57:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/10/empathy-leads-to-understanding/</guid><description>The other day I was at Lehigh University engaging in a bunch of conversations about identity, sexuality, gender, and social justice (ya know — my jam). The groups I was talking with and to were eager and willing to learn, which is not to be taken for granted, but a sentiment kept popping up: “This identity stuff is complicated.</description></item><item><title>Dear White, Straight, Cisgender, Man People: You Are Privileged</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/05/dear-white-straight-cisgender-men-privilege/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 17:17:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/05/dear-white-straight-cisgender-men-privilege/</guid><description>I’ve written about privilege here, and I’ve written my own privilege lists, inspired by Peggy McIntosh (blame her!), which have garnered a lot of hullabaloo on my site. Now, there seems to be a groundswell of backlash, where privileged people (like this super privileged Princeton student) are “denouncing their privilege” and “finally standing up for straight white guys” (HAHAHA).</description></item><item><title>I Have Not Given You Consent</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/i-have-not-given-you-consent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 23:43:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/i-have-not-given-you-consent/</guid><description>I work on the internet. It’s true. I write things for you to read (or not read), and spend a lot of my free time creating things that may (or may not) help you fill yours. I’m not asking for thanks, or really asking for you to do anything at all, but there are a few things I’m asking that you don’t do.</description></item><item><title>The Intentions vs. Outcomes Matrix</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/12/the-intentions-vs-outcomes-matrix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 22:42:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/12/the-intentions-vs-outcomes-matrix/</guid><description>It’s no secret I’m not a big fan of how highly we regard intentions. There’s even a whole chapter in my bookabout it, and it recently led to a great conversation, which led to this more visual representation of the dynamics between intentions and outcomes.</description></item><item><title>15+ Fantastic Resources for Talking about “Homosexuality” (i.e., LGBTQ people) and The Bible</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/10/resources-lgbtq-homosexual-bible-christianity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 21:47:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/10/resources-lgbtq-homosexual-bible-christianity/</guid><description>Only a tiny, tiny part of the bible can even be argued to reference “homosexuality” (and that argument, in a few of the verses in particular, is worth looking into), yet it seems like whenever we hear about the Bible in the news it’s being slammed against LGBTQ equality.</description></item><item><title>Being an Ally Between a Rock and a Hard Place</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/being-an-ally-between-a-rock-and-a-hard-place/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 23:14:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/being-an-ally-between-a-rock-and-a-hard-place/</guid><description>I’m an ally. I’ve written before why I’m an ally, and I’ve even once defended my allyship publicly, highlighting many of my privileged identities. But one thing I’ve never fully addressed is the double-edged-sword, Kobayashi-Maru-no-win scenario that _can be _what it means to be an ally like me.</description></item><item><title>50+ concrete things you can do today to make for a more socially just tomorrow</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/11/things-you-can-do-today-for-social-justice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 05:34:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/11/things-you-can-do-today-for-social-justice/</guid><description>&lt;p>Social justice — the idea that everyone in a society, regardless of the identities they embody, can have an equitable shot at success and happiness — is a goal that seems unrealistic for many people. “It’s a pipe dream, Sam,” they say, smugly. “Life isn’t rainbows and butterflies,” they say, adorably.&lt;/p>
&lt;aside class="heyHeyLook wednesdayEmail">&lt;p>&lt;span class="icon">💌&lt;/span>&lt;strong>Most Wednesdays&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>&lt;p>I publish new Social Justice, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Resources.&lt;/p> &lt;a class="button" title="Join my mailing list" href="http://bit.ly/2MmE28c" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Get the Email.&lt;/a>&lt;/aside>
&lt;p>To achieve social justice we will have to break down a lot of huge barriers that exist on a scale far above the individual, but even the biggest scale change is nothing more than the sum of &lt;em>a whole lot&lt;/em> of individual efforts.  My goal with this site is to support you in doing just that: making big change on an individual level.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following are &lt;em>a whole&lt;/em> &lt;em>lot&lt;/em> of individual efforts you can make today that will be significant steps toward that biggest scale change we need for a socially just tomorrow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>30+ Examples of Middle-to-Upper Class Privileges</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/list-of-upperclass-privilege/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2012 01:36:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/list-of-upperclass-privilege/</guid><description>Following is a list of middle-to-upper class privileges. If you are a member of the middle class or upper class economic groups (or, in some cases, perceived to be) listed below are benefits that may be granted to you based on your group membership — benefits not granted to folks in the lower classes.</description></item><item><title>You Soup: understanding diversity and the intersections of identity</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 19:17:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/</guid><description>&lt;p>In doing the work I do, I often find myself struggling to help people make sense of the two extremes of identity: on one side we have the idea that people in a group are all the same (stereotypes); while the other side supports this idea that everyone is absolutely unique (snowflakes).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I find myself saying “we’re not the same, but we’re also not that different,” to the furrowing of brows, so I wanted to take a moment here to talk about the relationship of individual identity and social group memberships, as well as introduce a new graphic concept.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Build Your Own World</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/build-your-own-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 22:30:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/build-your-own-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>Look around you.  Every product, gadget, building, company — every &lt;em>thing&lt;/em> — was created by a person who is just like you or me or Uncle Jesse from Full House (kidding — &lt;em>nobody&lt;/em> is like Uncle Jesse).  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>As you walk through your life, you’re surrounded by the accomplishments and influences of individuals of the past and present.  You’re surrounded by a world &lt;em>they&lt;/em> built — for you, and everyone around you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I, for one, am not entirely happy with the world that has been built for me.  I want to live in a world that is socially just, where individuals all have the same access to the good stuff — education, jobs, swedish fish, etc. — regardless of the identities they do or do not possess.  If you’re like me, you’ve likely thought, at some point, something along the lines of &lt;em>I want to make this world a better place to live in&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How To Avoid Being a Stereotype</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-avoid-being-a-stereotype/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 23:57:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-avoid-being-a-stereotype/</guid><description>&lt;p>You want to be seen as an individual, right?  Of course you do.  But it’s bordering on impossible to avoid perpetuating at least some of the stereotypes attached to the various aspects of your identity.  There are just too many of them!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, that’s where I can help.  Consider this a “How to be [X], without being a stereotypical [X]” guide.  I’m hitting a variety of major identities, but feel free to request addendums to the guide in the comments below, on &lt;a href="http://facebook.com/metrosam" title="http://facebook.com/metrosam">Facebook&lt;/a>, or on &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Twitter&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, if you’re more prone to spot-reading than reading-reading, &lt;strong>I strongly encourage you to at least read the last section before you formulate your reaction to this article&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without further ado, in alphabetical order…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to respond when someone uses non-inclusive (or bigoted) language</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-respond-to-non-inclusive-language-or-bigoted-speec/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 21:24:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-respond-to-non-inclusive-language-or-bigoted-speec/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Intentions don’t matter, outcomes do&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->.  However, I still think we need to do a much better job of being supportive of newcomers to the social justice “scene” who may be well-intended, but don’t quite know the ropes yet.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is my picture guide (sorry, no &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->flowchart&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->) of how to properly handle such situations, without scaring off a potential ally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/how-to-respond-comic.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>6+ LGBTQ Obama 2012 Campaign Graphics</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/6-lgbtq-obama-2012-campaign-graphics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2012 01:45:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/6-lgbtq-obama-2012-campaign-graphics/</guid><description>&lt;p>I support &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Barack Obama&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> because I want to see more legislation protecting marginalized social groups and identities and he’s the only one likely to make it happen.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>If that’s something you value, you should probably support him, too.  I made these LGBTQ-themed Obama support graphics for fun.  If you like ’em, share ’em.  If you don’t, don’t.  It’s that simple 🙂&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If I create more (I likely will) I’ll post them below (stay tuned on &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Facebook&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> and &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Twitter&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> for updates). &lt;strong>Also, feel free to make requests in the comments below (but no promises).&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/gay-for-obama.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/trans-for-obama.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/strong>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/obama-2012-lgbt.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>[&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I’m not anti-Christian, but religion shouldn’t have a place in political decisions.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/im-not-anti-religion-it-just-shouldnt-have-a-place-in-political-decisions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2012 23:25:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/im-not-anti-religion-it-just-shouldnt-have-a-place-in-political-decisions/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let’s make a deal. Promise me that you’ll do everything in your power to read this entire article (all 800 words of it) before you start mentally formulating the comment/email/death threat you’re going to respond with.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you can make that promise, read on.  If not, go find an website that reinforces your current dispositions on the matter and read that instead.  We’ll both be happier for it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>30+ Examples of Christian Privileges</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/list-of-examples-of-christian-privileg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 18:13:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/list-of-examples-of-christian-privileg/</guid><description>Following is a list of privileges granted to people in the U.S. (and many western nations) for being Christian.
💌Most Wednesdays
I publish new Social Justice, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Resources.
Get the Email. Please comment below if you have any additions or revisions to make!</description></item><item><title>5 Reasons My Approach to Social Justice Work is Better than Yours</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/5-reasons-my-approach-to-social-justice-work-is-better-than-yours/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 21:10:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/5-reasons-my-approach-to-social-justice-work-is-better-than-yours/</guid><description>&lt;p>The way I approach social justice and ally work on this site and &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->in my show&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> has a distinct flavor.  Some would call it sweet, but I think &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->ginger&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> is a bit spicy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t often do things by accident, and in this case it is very _on purpose.  _My flavor is even so noticeable that if you’ve seen a lot of what I’ve created here, you’re likely taken aback by the headline of this article.  Well, that actually leads me into my first point.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Reasons for being an Ally (AKA Social Justice Advocate)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/5-reasons-im-a-social-justice-all/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 20:00:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/5-reasons-im-a-social-justice-all/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hey, folks.  First of all, thanks for continuing to read what I write here, and thanks even more for sharing.  I don't say that enough.  I've been thinking a lot about why I do what I do lately, and I want to once-and-for-all answer a question I get asked an average of 1.6 times per day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Sam, why do you do what you do?&amp;rdquo; people say, but they are only saying half of what they're thinking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Depending on the context, they might be thinking, &amp;ldquo;Sam, if you're straight, why do you work so much for gay equality?&amp;rdquo;  Or &amp;ldquo;Sam, you're a man, why do you work so much for women's or trans people's equality&amp;rdquo;  Or &amp;ldquo;Sam, you're White, why do you care about equality for people of color?&amp;rdquo;  Or &amp;ldquo;Sam, you're a huge dork, why don't you do anything about that?&amp;rdquo;  And on it goes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My answer is different every time, because it's hard for me to get down to the absolute root of it all.  But let me provide some of the front-runner explanations for why I do what I do.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why your intentions don’t really matter, but outcomes do</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/why-your-intentions-dont-matter-victim-blaming-and-political-correctness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 23:34:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/why-your-intentions-dont-matter-victim-blaming-and-political-correctness/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/ingrids-intentionality-elixir.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve created a &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->few&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->graphics&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> about &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->when it’s okay to say “gay”&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> and the one argument that keeps coming up goes something like “How can you regulate language? What’s offensive to one person is not to another.  What matters is your intentions.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Intentions don’t matter, effect does.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will elaborate on my response to that question more in a bit, but first I want to pose another question, and posit an answer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An open letter to Bradlee Dean (and all Biblical literalists who label homosexuality as sin)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/open-letter-to-biblical-literalists-on-homosexualit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 00:59:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/open-letter-to-biblical-literalists-on-homosexualit/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/bradley-dean.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>Bradlee Dean, heavy metal rocker slash minister, recently alluded that the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Muslims who were calling for execution of gays&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> are “more moral” than Christians (read about it at the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Huffington Post&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He’s since backtracked a lot, and wishy-washied, and etc.  But it’s as apparent how he truly feels as it is how bad he is at playing politics.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --></description></item><item><title>One reason I’m a social justice advocate (as a white, straight, male)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/one-reason-i-do-what-i-do/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2012 21:29:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/one-reason-i-do-what-i-do/</guid><description>I’ve dedicated my life to progressing social justice, in the hopes that one day we can have a society that is equitable for all. I have a lot of reasons for doing this, but there are just as many reasons why it might be viewed that I _shouldn’t.</description></item><item><title>Why I’m Boycotting Marriage</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/why-im-boycotting-marriage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 01:52:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/why-im-boycotting-marriage/</guid><description>If five days ago you told me I would consider Sarah Silverman a role model, even in just one aspect, I would have laughed milk through my nose. And I don’t even drink milk.
But that was all before someone shared this Silverman quote with me:</description></item><item><title>Ron Paul: When the morality changes, it will reflect on the laws</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/ron-paul-when-the-morality-changes-it-will-reflect-on-the-laws/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 05:46:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/ron-paul-when-the-morality-changes-it-will-reflect-on-the-laws/</guid><description>I was watching one of the recent GOP debates and I heard Ron Paul say something that really struck me, responding with his thoughts on abortion. I transcribed the quote, but the video is down below that if you’d like to watch.</description></item><item><title>Political Correctness VS. Inclusiveness</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/political-correct-versus-being-inclusiv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 21:41:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/political-correct-versus-being-inclusiv/</guid><description>I would never ask you to be politically correct. I’ve gotten some flak from my “When Gay is Okay” and “Why I say partner” articles. People feel that I’m soap-boxing for political correctness, when that couldn’t be further from the truth.</description></item><item><title>The Corruption of the Golden Rule</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/the-corruption-of-the-golden-rule/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 21:25:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/the-corruption-of-the-golden-rule/</guid><description>Do unto others as you would have them do unto you. Right?
Wrong.
What we’ve been teaching our children, what I have learned and re-learned all of my life, is one of the worst pieces of advice around. What’s worse: it’s nearly universally accepted as gospel (pun intended).</description></item></channel></rss>