<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>It's Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/</link><description>Learn about gender, sexuality, &amp; social justice with Sam Killermann. Your free online resource for everything from genderbread people to LGBTQ vocabulary.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 17:34:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Maybe we should stop using “White supremacist” and “bad” interchangeably?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/07/maybe-we-should-stop-using-white-supremacist-and-bad-interchangeably/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 17:34:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/07/maybe-we-should-stop-using-white-supremacist-and-bad-interchangeably/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/white-supremacy-in-action-flowchart-on-brick.jpg"/><description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;#8217;ve been noticing this weird trend. It&amp;#8217;s become prevalent within the social justice movement, and I haven&amp;#8217;t seen anyone else flag it. I brought it up in the context of our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sjmd.space&#34;&gt;Social Justice, Minus Dogma Course + Community&lt;/a&gt;, and it turns out other people are noticing it too. So let&amp;#8217;s flag it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The short version is this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people are using domination/oppression language (e.g., &amp;#8220;white supremacist&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;patriarchal&amp;#8221;) as synonyms for &amp;#8220;bad&amp;#8221; and marginalization/anti-oppression language (e.g., &amp;#8220;indigenous,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;decolonized,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;feminist&amp;#8221;) as synonyms for &amp;#8220;good&amp;#8221; &amp;#8212; devoid of any meaningful connection to the actual structure, system, or culture they&amp;#8217;re mentioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My guess is that it&amp;#8217;s a combination of our &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/isms-not-ists/&#34;&gt;over focusing on &amp;#8220;-ists&amp;#8221; instead of &amp;#8220;-isms&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; plus the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-social-justice-power-inverse/&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;social justice power inverse,&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; but I&amp;#8217;ll leave the detective work up to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why highlight this at all? In short, because actual, sincere, real-life White supremacy is on the rise, and we need to be able to call it when we see it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calling things &amp;#8220;White supremacist&amp;#8221; that aren&amp;#8217;t creates a lot of unhelpful noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote this article a few days before we got a blazingly clear example of White supremacy in action, when &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1150381394234941448&#34;&gt;U.S. President Donald Trump went on a &amp;#8220;go back to your country&amp;#8221; rant&lt;/a&gt; against several members of congress, all of whom are women of color.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being careful to use the phrase &amp;#8220;White supremacy&amp;#8221; correctly would allow a criticism of Trump&amp;#8217;s rant, and other White supremacist actions, to be held as distinct from general criticisms of Trump.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both are totally valid, by the way! However, we need to know which basket we&amp;#8217;re putting our eggs into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to be able to separate &amp;#8220;I don&amp;#8217;t like what you&amp;#8217;re saying&amp;#8221; from &amp;#8220;What you&amp;#8217;re saying is advancing White supremacy and ethnic cleansing.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And right now we&amp;#8217;re not doing a good job of that, at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll explain what I&amp;#8217;m talking about in more detail, then talk about a few of the reasons &lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt; think this is (deeply) unhelpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;d be curious to hear what you think, if you&amp;#8217;re also noticing this. We&amp;#8217;ll make space for that, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8220-white-supremacist-8221-doesn-8217-t-mean-a-8220-white-person-doing-something-bad-8221&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;White Supremacist&amp;#8221; doesn&amp;#8217;t mean a &amp;#8220;White person doing something bad&amp;#8221;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me first say that, overall, it&amp;#8217;s great that more people are becoming comfy using phrases like &amp;#8220;white supremacist.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same goes for words like &amp;#8220;patriarchal,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;colonial,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;heterosexist,&amp;#8221; etc. They&amp;#8217;re useful words that can be used to pinpoint exactly what we&amp;#8217;re talking about, concerned about in society, and wanting to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(If we could just add &amp;#8220;capitalist&amp;#8221; to our comfort zone, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mediaed.org/transcripts/Bell-Hooks-Transcript.pdf&#34;&gt;we might even make bell hooks proud&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The issue I&amp;#8217;m flagging here is&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;the use of the phrase &amp;#8220;white supremacist&amp;#8221;&lt;/strong&gt; (or any of these other words I&amp;#8217;m lumping together as domination/oppression language).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The issue is people using these words like duct tape, sticking them to every problem they notice.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s what it looks like in general:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Someone does something harmful.&lt;/em&gt; Are they White? &amp;#8220;White supremacy in action.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Someone shares a terrible idea.&lt;/em&gt; Are they a man? &amp;#8220;Patriarchy in action.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An organization has a White man executive director&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;does something unhelpful&lt;/em&gt;. &amp;#8220;White supremacist patriarchy.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here it is in flowchart form:&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-src=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/FLOWCHART-If-a-white-person-did-it-its-white-supremacy.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-3978 lazy-load&#34; srcset=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/FLOWCHART-If-a-white-person-did-it-its-white-supremacy.png 800w, https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/FLOWCHART-If-a-white-person-did-it-its-white-supremacy-300x180.png 300w, https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/FLOWCHART-If-a-white-person-did-it-its-white-supremacy-768x462.png 768w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the flipside of the same coin is also true, where we see people attributing anything positive someone does or shares to a marginalized identity or anti-oppression -ism. For example, a &amp;#8220;better&amp;#8221; approach to something becomes labeled as the &amp;#8220;feminist&amp;#8221; approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a few concrete examples, I&amp;#8217;ve recently seen high profile, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/social-justice-fandom-aka-creating-new-barriers-name-dismantling-others/&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;social justice famous,&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; or virally-shared takes that included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Democracy equated with White supremacy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercising and being a physical trainer equated with literal Nazism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facilitating a Q&amp;amp;A session in a thoughtful way equated with feminist decolonialization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t focus too much on those examples if you have seen your own and they&amp;#8217;re different. I just pulled them from the top of my mind as things I&amp;#8217;ve seen in the last few days, and wanted to share them for people for whom this was all too abstract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The examples don&amp;#8217;t matter as much as the phenomenon in general, which is using loaded oppression language as synonymous with &amp;#8220;bad.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;address&gt;
I&amp;#8217;m not linking to specific examples, because I refuse to publicly drag people, especially people who are working with the intent of social justice. Examples of this are abound in my social media feeds, as well as the mainstream social justice blogs/sites I read, so I&amp;#8217;m guessing the same is true for you, if you&amp;#8217;re a person reading this site.
&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so hopefully this all makes sense so far. Let me say another big disclaimer before I go on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A lot of times this is all true.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, I&amp;#8217;m &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; saying that white people doing bad things is never an example of white supremacy. A lot of bad things white people do, and bad ideas white people have, are white supremacist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m also &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; saying that a better approach to something isn&amp;#8217;t feminist. A lot of better approaches are feminist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Repeat the above examples for every parallel domination/oppression and marginalization/anti-oppression axis in your head, and I&amp;#8217;ll stand by it. I&amp;#8217;m just going to save you the reading time, and the earth the carbon emissions, and not type those 1,000+ words.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;heyHeyLook wednesdayEmail&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;💌&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most Wednesdays&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I publish new Social Justice, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Resources.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; title=&#34;Join my mailing list&#34; href=&#34;http://bit.ly/2MmE28c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Get the Email.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s the part I&amp;#8217;m flagging:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A lot of times it&amp;#8217;s not true.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;White people do stupid stuff that isn&amp;#8217;t White supremacist. Men have terrible ideas that aren&amp;#8217;t patriarchal. And there are great ideas that aren&amp;#8217;t feminist. Etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, and more prickly, advancing White supremacy isn&amp;#8217;t merely the domain of white people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Black people, indigenous people, and people of color in general can all advance White supremacy, can share White supremacist ideas, and can do bad things that are White supremacist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Us using &amp;#8220;White supremacist&amp;#8221; as a synonym for &amp;#8220;White person doing stupid shit&amp;#8221; erases those realities, which is one of the problems that led me to flagging this. But it&amp;#8217;s not the &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt; problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-8217-s-the-big-problem&#34;&gt;What&amp;#8217;s the big problem?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it&amp;#8217;s true a lot of the time, what&amp;#8217;s the harm in labeling things as &amp;#8220;white supremacist&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;patriarchal&amp;#8221; when they&amp;#8217;re bad?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if we want to advance the goals of feminism, why not arbitrarily label good things as &amp;#8220;feminist&amp;#8221;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The big problem here is that when you use a word to mean everything, it stops meaning anything.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re diluting the usefulness of these otherwise super useful, targeted, precise words when we use them to describe everything bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a person who spends a lot of time trying to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/01/a-comprehensive-list-of-lgbtq-term-definitions/&#34;&gt;clarify language for people, writing definitions, and updating meanings of terminology&lt;/a&gt; as it shifts with culture, I have both a unique vantage point and ax to grind on this front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Words have power. Language shapes our realities as much as it reflects them. Every time a person uses a word incorrectly it erodes the power of that word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because what we&amp;#8217;re doing here &amp;#8212; trying to advance the goals of social justice, move towards equity and liberation &amp;#8212; matters deeply to us, so should every misstep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calling things White supremacist that aren&amp;#8217;t ultimately helps White supremacy, and hinders the progress of social justice.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ditto goes for every other &amp;#8220;bad thing&amp;#8221; we falsely attribute to an &amp;#8220;-ism&amp;#8221; we&amp;#8217;re trying to unravel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;#8217;m not &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; talking &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.storyarts.org/library/aesops/stories/boy.html&#34;&gt;&amp;#8220;Boy Who Cried Wolf&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt;-style either. Let&amp;#8217;s work through some of the other problems within the frame of a proposed solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;proposing-an-alternative&#34;&gt;Proposing an Alternative&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if, instead of the algorithm above, we committed the following:&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-src=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/FLOWCHART-If-it-advances-the-goals-of-White-supremacy-its-white-supremacy.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-3984 lazy-load&#34; srcset=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/FLOWCHART-If-it-advances-the-goals-of-White-supremacy-its-white-supremacy.png 800w, https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/FLOWCHART-If-it-advances-the-goals-of-White-supremacy-its-white-supremacy-300x189.png 300w, https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/FLOWCHART-If-it-advances-the-goals-of-White-supremacy-its-white-supremacy-768x484.png 768w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;White supremacy, patriarchy, colonialism, and the rest are all ideologies and belief systems. They are social projects with specific goals. They&amp;#8217;re not synonyms for &amp;#8220;evil.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how can we &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; if something contributes to the goals, outcomes, or ideology of White supremacy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-8217-ll-have-to-discuss-it-and-figure-it-out-ourselves&#34;&gt;We&amp;#8217;ll have to discuss it, and figure it out ourselves.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we discuss, with other social justice people, whether or not something said or done is &amp;#8220;contributing to the goals, outcomes, or ideology of White supremacy&amp;#8221;, and not just something we disagree with, dislike, or find gross, I have full faith we land on the truth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that will, in the long run, benefit social justice and our individual efforts &amp;#8212; whether it turns out the thing &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;wasn&amp;#8217;t&lt;/em&gt; White supremacy in action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When we determine that it is&lt;/strong&gt;, we&amp;#8217;ll have spent time figuring it out, questioning, digging in, proposing alternatives, and getting to the bottom of the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this time spent isn&amp;#8217;t time wasted, it&amp;#8217;s practice! Because anyone else we talk to about that thing will likely have some of those same questions, counterpoints, and skepticisms, and we&amp;#8217;ll already have an answer in mind that can move the conversation from that sticking point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When we determine that it&amp;#8217;s not,&lt;/strong&gt; we&amp;#8217;ll have spared ourselves a ton of wasted time advocating something to other people an idea that &amp;#8212; when we really dug into it &amp;#8212; wasn&amp;#8217;t rooted in something meaningful. That&amp;#8217;s not just time saved, but an opportunity cost of trust and respect avoided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the outcome, discussing whether or not something actually &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; White supremacist will have another benefit&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;we-can-8217-t-just-fall-back-on-dogma&#34;&gt;We can&amp;#8217;t just fall back on dogma.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tag/social-justice-dogma/&#34;&gt;Social Justice Dogma&lt;/a&gt; shows up in our lives in lots of ways, and many of those prevent us from asking questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If someone says something is racist, our knee-jerk reaction is to distance ourselves as far away from it as possible, not to ask questions and get to the bottom of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don&amp;#8217;t often ask &amp;#8220;Is this &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; White supremacy in action? What if it were something else?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we question it, we run the risk of being questioned ourselves: &amp;#8220;Are &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; enabling racism? Have &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; internalized White supremacy? Why are &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; defending a racist?&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we don&amp;#8217;t question it. We just jump in and support. That&amp;#8217;s all the dogma allows us to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this might benefit us individually, it hinders us as a movement. Because when we toe the line of dogma we&amp;#8217;re more concerned with preserving our relationships, or not being &amp;#8220;canceled&amp;#8221; or outcast, and we center our individual status instead of the cause we&amp;#8217;re advancing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way, the social justice dogma is a trap: it always gives us an answer, but sometimes what we really need is the ability to ask constructive questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we keep our cause in mind, the movement front and center, the path seems forward becomes clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As soon as we start questioning things, and getting to the root of an issue, we&amp;#8217;re pushing back against the dogma and creating a chance for living social justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cleaning-up-the-garbage-we-notice&#34;&gt;Cleaning up the garbage we notice.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a moment, imagine that every time we notice an injustice &amp;#8212; something standing in the way of social justice, or gender equity, or sexual liberation &amp;#8212; we&amp;#8217;re flagging a piece of garbage in a park.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re walking around and making mental notes. &amp;#8220;There&amp;#8217;s an empty potato chip bag by that tree. A crumpled can under that bench. Some styrofoam floating in that pond.&amp;#8221; And so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we&amp;#8217;re walking around the park making those notes because we plan to clean up the park. But first we&amp;#8217;re getting a sense of the tools we need. How many trash bags, nets for the water, little poker things for the cans, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would it be helpful if we mistook a leaf for a potato chip bag? Or some pond scum for styrofoam? It would not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we want to actually rid the park of trash, we&amp;#8217;d have to focus on the trash. We&amp;#8217;d be wasting our time and resources trying to scoop up everything that looks kinda like trash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can see social justice, and our efforts within the social justice movement, in this same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time we call something &amp;#8220;White supremacist&amp;#8221; we&amp;#8217;re creating a task for ourselves, something we need to clean up, in order to advance the cause of equity and racial justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We can&amp;#8217;t dismantle White supremacy unless we can accurately spot it in action. To do that&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;we need to be able to ask questions,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;and be willing to find the answers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ll only benefit from focusing on the real problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-recap&#34;&gt;To Recap:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I&amp;#8217;m concerned this article is one of those that&amp;#8217;s likely to get misinterpreted (and there&amp;#8217;s a &lt;em&gt;non-zero&lt;/em&gt; chance it will un-ironically be labeled White supremacist itself), let&amp;#8217;s recap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to be absotively sure you know what I&amp;#8217;m saying here, and &amp;#8212; if it motivates you &amp;#8212; that it pushes you in the direction I&amp;#8217;m hoping to nudge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here&amp;#8217;s what I&amp;#8217;m saying:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We often use the phrase &amp;#8220;White supremacist&amp;#8221; simply to mean &amp;#8220;a white person did something bad.&amp;#8221;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some bad things aren&amp;#8217;t White supremacist (or patriarchal, or sexist, cissexist, heterosexist, ableist, or any-ist).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being careless about the distinction enables actual White supremacy (and other -isms) by providing cover and distraction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being clear about the distinction between &amp;#8220;White supremacy&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;bad things that aren&amp;#8217;t actually White supremacy&amp;#8221; will help us move justice movements forward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So let&amp;#8217;s be intentional with how and when we choose to call something &amp;#8220;White supremacy&amp;#8221; (and make sure that the thing in question is actually White supremacy in action).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully that shines through in the article above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now I&amp;#8217;d like to hear what you have to say&lt;/strong&gt;! &lt;strong&gt;You can respond to me directly by&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;typeform-share&#34; data-mode=&#34;popup&#34; style=&#34;font-weight: bold;&#34; href=&#34;https://hues.typeform.com/to/LApMm4&#34;&gt;clicking here&lt;/a&gt; (anonymous, quick, &amp;amp; easy)&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Social Justice Minus Dogma Online Course</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/social-justice-minus-dogma-course/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/social-justice-minus-dogma-course/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/img/posts/social-justice-minus-dogma-course-screenshot.jpg"/><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the course of 6 weeks of self-guided learning (or however long you choose), explore the social justice dogma, identify its cornerstones and pitfalls, and plot a path forward toward true living social justice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course is an extension of all the writing I&amp;rsquo;ve done here about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/social-justice-dogma/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;social justice dogma.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; Beyond thoroughly explaining what it is, and why it might be problematic, it&amp;rsquo;s a map for taking steps toward living social justice, minus the dogma &amp;ndash; for educators, activists, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/&#34;&gt;all types of social justice people&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;button-stack&#34; style=&#34;margin: 2em auto; text-align: center; font-size: 1.2em;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;https://gum.co/sjmdcourse?wanted=true&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Enroll Now&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;button button-alt&#34; href=&#34;https://course.sjmd.space&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Learn More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course consists of 6 modules (in addition to Orientation &amp;amp; Graduation):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dot-Com-Munity&lt;/strong&gt;, answering: What does it take to create a community where you confront a dogma? What’s at stake? How easily can things go wrong? How can we create a durable container to hold real community?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barks Like a Dogma&lt;/strong&gt;, answering: What do we mean by “Social Justice Dogma”? Can we spot dogmatic thinking, acting, and believing? In what ways does SJD show up in our lives?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cutting Cornerstones&lt;/strong&gt;, answering: Why does dogma flourish? What are the foundational beliefs of SJD? How does SJD provide positive feedback?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Acolytes&lt;/strong&gt;, answering: What are the virtues of the defenders of SJD? How can we give SJD acolytes a way out? What will an SJMD conversation feel like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theses Pieces&lt;/strong&gt;, answering: What does social justice look like without the dogma? How do we avoid the pitfalls of recreating SJD? What are the building blocks of living social justice? How do we chart paths forward?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SJMD IRL&lt;/strong&gt;, answering: How do we bring SJMD to our IRL communities? What’s included in our MVP? What are the first steps we’re going to take?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like everything I do, it&amp;rsquo;s offered in the gift economy, meaning you choose a tuition level that works for you (even $0), based on your ability, gratitude, or sense of what it&amp;rsquo;s worth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;button-stack&#34; style=&#34;margin: 2em auto; text-align: center; font-size: 1.2em;&#34;&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; href=&#34;https://gum.co/sjmdcourse?wanted=true&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Enroll Now&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;button button-alt&#34; href=&#34;https://course.sjmd.space&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Learn More&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description></item><item><title>How much injustice can we justify on the path toward social justice?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/05/justifying-injustice-for-social-justice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:36:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/05/justifying-injustice-for-social-justice/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/dont-worry.jpg"/><description>&lt;p&gt;Close your eyes and imagine the world you would describe as living social justice. Equitable. Utopian, even. Whatever comes to mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give it a shot. I’ll wait a moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does it feel like to occupy that &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-two-worlds-dilemma/&#34;&gt;future world&lt;/a&gt; where all of our work as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/&#34;&gt;social justice people&lt;/a&gt; came to fruition?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How does it differ from our world today?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How radical of a difference you notice will be determined by the world you have in your mind. But surely the ways we spend our time, the social problems we grapple with, and even the ways we organize societies aren&amp;#8217;t the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do “jobs” look like? Do they even still exist? What about politics? What will there be more of? What will there be less of?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s likely a long list of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/&#34;&gt;actions, attitudes, and beliefs&lt;/a&gt; that wouldn’t make sense in that world, but seem perfectly sensical in our world right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What comes to mind?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus on the gap, the distance between what would be normal in a socially-just world, compared to what is normal now in our oppressive and unjust world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, now here comes the really tough part:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;heyHeyLook wednesdayEmail&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;💌&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most Wednesdays&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I publish new Social Justice, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Resources.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;button&#34; title=&#34;Join my mailing list&#34; href=&#34;http://bit.ly/2MmE28c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Get the Email.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many things are you currently doing, arguing, and believing — in this world, today, on a regular basis — that are &lt;em&gt;directly antithetical&lt;/em&gt; to the socially-just world you imagined?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That fly in the face of it. The things you know aren’t “ideal.” The things “We&amp;#8217;ll stop&amp;#8221; doing, arguing, or believing &amp;#8220;once we get there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where’s the line between &lt;em&gt;justifying an inequitable action&lt;/em&gt; today in the pursuit of a socially-just tomorrow, and &lt;em&gt;actively creating&lt;/em&gt; a different form of injustice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suspect we cross that line daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what inequitable actions do we need to stop justifying today, in order to clear the path to the world you imagined?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hunch: all of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>-isms, not -ists</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/isms-not-ists/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 16:11:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/isms-not-ists/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/found-the-problem.jpg"/><description>&lt;p&gt;To achieve the goals of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/socialjustice/&#34;&gt;social justice&lt;/a&gt;, we need to reform society at the system level. We need to dismantle rac&lt;em&gt;ism&lt;/em&gt;, sex&lt;em&gt;ism&lt;/em&gt;, cissex&lt;em&gt;ism&lt;/em&gt;, heterosex&lt;em&gt;ism&lt;/em&gt;, gender&lt;em&gt;ism&lt;/em&gt;, able&lt;em&gt;ism&lt;/em&gt;, class&lt;em&gt;ism&lt;/em&gt;, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too much of social justice discourse and calls-to-action are focused on the &lt;em&gt;-ists&lt;/em&gt;, the people participating in (and perpetuating) those systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our focus on individual actors keeps increasing in social justice spaces&lt;/strong&gt; I occupy. It’s almost all of what I notice in online social justice activism/advocacy. I’m guessing you’ve noticed it, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This focus often takes the form of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/10/what-kind-of-social-justice-are-you-talking-about/&#34;&gt;punitive social justice&lt;/a&gt;, identifying perpetrators, dragging them, publicly shaming them, “canceling” them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also see it in listicles with titles that highlight the # Ways You’re Part of the Problem. Or the inverse: # Ways to Be Part of the Solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We experience it in workshops with activities designed to highlight individuals&amp;#8217; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tag/privilege&#34;&gt;privilege&lt;/a&gt; or contributions to oppression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time a finger gets pointed at &lt;strong&gt;a person&lt;/strong&gt; — whether they’re a Fortune 500 CEO or a high school student — we’re focusing on an &lt;em&gt;-ist&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do it because it feels good, or tangible, or even just doable. It’s something that’s within our power. The system seems out of reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every campaign to “cancel” an &lt;em&gt;-ist&lt;/em&gt; — whether successful or not — isn’t the same as addressing the system. It brings our attention &lt;em&gt;away&lt;/em&gt; from the system and toward an individual within it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s the &lt;em&gt;-ism&lt;/em&gt; that created the conditions where that person&amp;#8217;s behavior seemed right, celebrated, or like the only path they could walk, but instead of addressing that, we scapegoat the &lt;em&gt;-ist&lt;/em&gt;. A ceremonial sacrifice that opens up a vacancy the machine will dutifully fill with a replacement who can perform the role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system is unscathed, and potentially strengthened: the next person won&amp;#8217;t make that same misstep, better concealing the machinations of the &lt;em&gt;-ism&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do we need to focus on &lt;em&gt;-ists&lt;/em&gt;, to some extent, in the pursuit of social justice? To hold people accountable, transform them, foster growth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe. I don’t know. I certainly know that I’m not saying — here, now — that we never should, or that we never need to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I’m saying is that focusing on&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-ists&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;will never be sufficient. That it’s energy we’re directing toward a symptom, not a cause.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that if we don’t do it carefully, it’s likely to create more problems than solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It already is.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Privilege Lie</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/the-privilege-lie/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 23:41:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/the-privilege-lie/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/privilege-pie.jpg"/><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve said it myself. I&amp;#8217;ve read it a hundred times. You&amp;#8217;ve probably heard it, or said it yourself. It usually goes something like, &amp;#8220;We&amp;#8217;re not asking you to give up your privileges. We&amp;#8217;re trying to grant access to others who don&amp;#8217;t have them.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or a pie analogy: &amp;#8220;Privilege isn&amp;#8217;t like pie. You don&amp;#8217;t have to give up your slice for others to enjoy it.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The idea behind these sentiments is that the goal of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/socialjustice/&#34;&gt;social justice&lt;/a&gt; is not to take privileges away&lt;/strong&gt; from the &amp;#8220;privileged&amp;#8221; and give them to the &amp;#8220;oppressed&amp;#8221; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/binary-thinking/&#34;&gt;an unhelpful binary&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/privilege-lists/&#34;&gt;list privileges&lt;/a&gt; (e.g., &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/11/30-examples-of-male-privilege/&#34;&gt;male privileges&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/list-of-cisgender-privileges/&#34;&gt;cisgender privileges&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/list-of-examples-of-christian-privileg/&#34;&gt;Christian privileges&lt;/a&gt;) and ask people to &amp;#8220;check their privilege,&amp;#8221; we say we&amp;#8217;re not asking them to give anything up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instead, we say that the goal is for &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; to have access to those privileges.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We say this, usually, as a defense to [privileged] people pushing back against our goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And it&amp;#8217;s a lie. A well-intentioned lie, but a lie nonetheless.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To oversimplify, privilege shows up in two ways: ways society is organized to &lt;em&gt;give you advantages&lt;/em&gt;, and ways &lt;em&gt;you aren&amp;#8217;t penalized&lt;/em&gt; for who you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything that falls into the first bucket only exists in contrast to not having it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If white-ness is how you got your job, or male-ness is why your opinion is received as fact, or straight-ness is why your parental fitness is unquestioned, then a socially just world is one where your job, opinion, parenthood, and more aren&amp;#8217;t granted based on those identities. Where your advantage is taken away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that equity? And justice? And &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/build-your-own-world/&#34;&gt;a world I want to build&lt;/a&gt;? Absolutely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;#8217;s also one where a lot of people no longer hold privileges they currently do. We need to be honest about that.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Replacing One Binary with Another</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/binary-thinking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 16:43:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/binary-thinking/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/toucans-of-people.jpg"/><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve always believed that one of our superpowers as gender/sexuality activists, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/&#34;&gt;social justice people&lt;/a&gt; more broadly, is our ability to hold space for nuance. In the past few years, that belief has been crumbling. In part because of how much I&amp;#8217;m seeing us replace one way of binary thinking for another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a long time, we&amp;#8217;ve known that sexuality isn&amp;#8217;t a binary thing. It&amp;#8217;s not gay/straight, either/or. It&amp;#8217;s often both/and, neither, or another option altogether. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kinsey_scale&#34;&gt;The Kinsey Scale&lt;/a&gt; often comes to mind here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More recently, we&amp;#8217;ve recognized the same thing about gender. We&amp;#8217;ve &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NRcPXtqdKjE&#34;&gt;addressed the complexities of gender&lt;/a&gt;, viewing it on a spectrum, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/02/gender-scales-or-spectrums/&#34;&gt;or, better, on scales&lt;/a&gt;. And &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/breaking-through-the-binary-gender-explained-using-continuums/&#34;&gt;broken through the binary&lt;/a&gt; of woman/man. Just like sexuality, it&amp;#8217;s not an either/or, but more of a both/and, neither, or another option altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, it&amp;#8217;s not entirely clear to me that everyone writing about binaries (e.g., the gender binary) is saying the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So allow me to be clear what I mean (and have always meant) by binary: two options. Two ways to be. Two categories. And that&amp;#8217;s it. Only two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A binary can be succinctly summed up by this (no words needed):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure class=&#34;wp-block-image&#34;&gt;
&lt;img data-src=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/boxes-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Two empty checkboxes&#34; class=&#34;wp-image-3733 lazy-load&#34; data-srcset=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/boxes-1.png 800w, https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/boxes-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/boxes-1-768x432.png 768w&#34; sizes=&#34;(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And while neither the gender or sexuality binary is without plenty of debate (from middle-of-the-road people to outright anti-social justice people), there&amp;#8217;s a feeling of consensus amongst social justice people: It&amp;#8217;ll be better for everyone if we move beyond these binary ways of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth that we&amp;#8217;re pushing for here is the recognition that gender, sexuality, and other aspects of our personhood are complicated, nuanced, and more shades-of-gray (ahem) than black/white.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We argue that it&amp;#8217;s important for everyone to recognize that truth because it results in the recognition, or visibility, of people made invisible by the previous discourse. We&amp;#8217;re able to see people where they stand, for who they are, and allow them to show up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A binary simply doesn&amp;#8217;t create enough room for most of us to fit. People are more complicated than that. More diverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we can&amp;#8217;t recognize people, we can&amp;#8217;t hear their voice. Can&amp;#8217;t be made to care about their collective or individual suffering. Won&amp;#8217;t be bothered to do anything about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two binaries &amp;#8220;smashed.&amp;#8221; Destroyed. Demolished. Etc. other unnecessarily violent and hyperbolic descriptors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But (uh oh) there&amp;#8217;s a hitch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-binaries-we-8217-ve-come-to-love&#34;&gt;The Binaries We&amp;#8217;ve Come to Love&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all of our campaigning against binary thinking &amp;#8212; our arguments for recognizing the complexity and nuance and gradations of experience that are intrinsic to the human experience &amp;#8212; we seem to have lost the plot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To accomplish our goal of convincing people that binaries are bad, we&amp;#8217;ve created a bunch of new binaries. (At least, a lot of us who are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/social-justice-fandom-aka-creating-new-barriers-name-dismantling-others/&#34;&gt;parts of the fandom of social justice&lt;/a&gt; have)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-social-justice-power-inverse/&#34;&gt;social justice power inverse&lt;/a&gt;, we haven&amp;#8217;t moved beyond the harmful mechanism &amp;#8212; in this case, binary thinking, or forcing people to reduce nuance and complexity into simple dualities &amp;#8212; we&amp;#8217;ve just swapped out the binaries and options you can choose from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re maintaining and upholding the value of thinking in binary ways, as long as you confine yourself within the &lt;em&gt;correct&lt;/em&gt; binaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Those binaries are bad. But I have some new ones that aren&amp;#8217;t. Trust me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, here&amp;#8217;s a binary that gets reinforced constantly in conversations about gender, sexuality, and social justice:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Privileged&lt;/span&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Oppressed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people (almost non-hypothetically everyone) can&amp;#8217;t check just one of those boxes. Most of us are both of those, depending on which aspect of us you&amp;#8217;re talking about, or what situation we&amp;#8217;re in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when people bring &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; up, what I just said &amp;#8212; in workshops, online, or in other social justice education spaces &amp;#8212; they&amp;#8217;re met with another binary to either self-select into, or be shoved into:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Unquestioningly Supportive&lt;/span&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Oppressive&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Have fun picking which of those boxes to check. It&amp;#8217;s like when your parents gave you the &amp;#8220;option&amp;#8221; of putting on your shoes before the count of 3.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve seen this happen more times than I can recount, and I&amp;#8217;m guessing you have too. Someone raises their hand, offers a counterpoint or constructive criticism, and suddenly the mood of the space changes from education to trial. Witnessing this over and over is one of the things that led me to start writing about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tag/social-justice-dogma/&#34;&gt;social justice dogma&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you question a social justice narrative, or complicate things, or add nuance, you risk being lumped into the &amp;#8220;oppressive&amp;#8221; box, being seen as part of the problem. Oh, that&amp;#8217;s another binary we love:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Part of the Solution&lt;/span&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Part of the Problem&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have so many new binaries that we&amp;#8217;ve created, that we actively sort people into. New either/or ways of thinking, that tell us who is good, who we&amp;#8217;re allowed to like, what ideas we should support, and how we&amp;#8217;re allowed to show our support, and more. Each of those with a dichotomous opposite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the risk of boring you with example overload, I&amp;#8217;ll just quickly blurt out a few more before I wrap this thing up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/12/reasons-people-believe-feminism-hates-men/&#34;&gt;feminism&lt;/a&gt; is either&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Intersectional&lt;/span&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Racist/Supremacist/Bigoted&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;#8217;re either an&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Ally Who Wants Cookies&lt;/span&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Good Ally (Who Doesn&amp;#8217;t)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on your &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/&#34;&gt;identities&lt;/a&gt;, choosing to speak is either&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Sharing Your Truth&lt;/span&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Taking Up Space&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on community verdict, you&amp;#8217;re either&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Okay (for now)&lt;/span&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Canceled&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And ultimately, you&amp;#8217;re either&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Woke&lt;/span&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Problematic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could go on (and on, and on) with that list. You can probably think of a few binaries I haven&amp;#8217;t listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could also elaborate on each of them, and really dig into the unhelpfulness of &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; binary way of thinking (e.g., arguing that everyone &amp;#8212; including your favs, your friends, and you &amp;#8212; is problematic).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, I&amp;#8217;m going to end this more broadly, focusing on binary thinking itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what&#34;&gt;So what?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the risk of this article coming across as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/hypocrisy-theatre/&#34;&gt;hypocrisy theatre&lt;/a&gt;, let me get to my point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a simple one, I think. And something that on its face feels obvious, but will nonetheless feel controversial to many:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We can&amp;#8217;t undo the harms of one oversimplified binary by enacting another oversimplified binary.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liberating everyone from the confines of one of two boxes, only to force them into one of two &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; boxes is not &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/&#34;&gt;a path toward equity, or a truly just society&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;#8217;m not saying that we &amp;#8220;can&amp;#8217;t&amp;#8221; do this because we have a moral imperative, or should take &amp;#8220;the high road.&amp;#8221; It&amp;#8217;s not about this being hypocritical. It&amp;#8217;s not that at all. I&amp;#8217;m saying can&amp;#8217;t do it because it&amp;#8217;s not working. It won&amp;#8217;t work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combatting dichotomous, rigid, reductive thinking with dichotomous, rigid, reductive thinking is not a winning strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It works when you&amp;#8217;re preaching to the converted, sure. You can wield it as a weapon of fear to keep your people from stepping out of line. &amp;#8220;Keep believing this, in these specific ways, or we&amp;#8217;ll cast you out.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And weapon isn&amp;#8217;t an overstatement. The threat of rejection, isolation, and alienation is the threat of &lt;a href=&#34;http://science.sciencemag.org/content/302/5643/290&#34;&gt;physical pain&lt;/a&gt;. Kicking someone out of your community is &lt;a href=&#34;https://fs.blog/2013/11/why-our-brains-are-wired-to-connect/&#34;&gt;tantamount to breaking their leg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;re not just in the business of preaching to the converted. We&amp;#8217;re about changing, and opening, minds. Creating health where before there was suffering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we want people to recognize the diversity inherent in humanity &amp;#8212; that shows up as spectrums of genders and sexualities &amp;#8212; and the limitations of reducing all of that to two boxes into which we lump everyone, we have to recognize the diversity inherent in humanity. And stop lumping everyone into one of two boxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to embrace nuance. Tap into &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/magical-power-social-justice-educators/&#34;&gt;the magical power of &amp;#8220;some.&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; Recognize the truth that almost none of this is absolute, either/or. The same goes for us: we live in the gray. Hiding from that isn&amp;#8217;t helping anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The tool of binary thinking isn&amp;#8217;t capable of fixing the problem of binary thinking.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or, to borrow the words of someone more brilliant than me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;The master&amp;#8217;s tools will never dismantle the master&amp;#8217;s house. They may allow us temporarily to beat him at his own game, but they will never enable us to bring about genuine change.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you going to disagree with Audre Lorde? Watch out, or you might land yourself in a box you don&amp;#8217;t want to be in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Disagreeing with Audre Lorde&lt;/span&gt; &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style=&#34;display:inline-block&#34;&gt;&lt;input type=&#34;checkbox&#34; /&gt; Not 100% Regretting A Foolish Mistake&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Social Justice Power Inverse</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-social-justice-power-inverse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 18:19:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-social-justice-power-inverse/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/social-justice-power-inverse.jpg"/><description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of social justice conversations focus on power. Who has power in society and who doesn&amp;#8217;t?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We highlight how systems inequitably distribute power to some while withholding it from others &amp;#8212; based on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/&#34;&gt;who we are&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We refer to people who are granted disproportionate power as &amp;#8220;privileged,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;majoritized,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;centered,&amp;#8221; etc. And those from whom power is withheld as &amp;#8220;oppressed,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;minoritized,&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;marginalized,&amp;#8221; etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, nobody is only one of those two. We&amp;#8217;re both, depending on which situation we&amp;#8217;re in, and what dimensions of ourselves are brought to the forefront.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our goal in talking about this is dismantling inequitable power structures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/&#34;&gt;The needle on our compass points toward equity.&lt;/a&gt; Removing barriers, promoting access, and shrinking the gap between the &amp;#8220;haves&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;have nots&amp;#8221; &amp;#8212; or, in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-two-worlds-dilemma/&#34;&gt;a perfect world&lt;/a&gt;, making that dichotomy irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the things we don&amp;#8217;t talk about is how power structures manifest in social justice spaces, or the micro-society that is the community of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/&#34;&gt;social justice people&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, we preserve the idea of the power structure, but swap out who sits where.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We center people who are generally marginalized, privilege people who are otherwise oppressed, majoritize the previously minoritized. The more your voice is taken away in society based on intersecting aspects of who are, the more your voice holds weight here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do it, in part, as a protection against the harms of society, where dominant group members often silence others, misinform, and act selfishly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rationale here makes sense: it feels like righting a wrong. And it results in a lot of positive outcomes (e.g., agency, representation, solidarity).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But like all disproportionate power relationships, it&amp;#8217;s also susceptible to abuse. We empower some to silence others, misinform, and act selfishly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s also, ultimately, inequitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reversing who holds disproportionate power doesn&amp;#8217;t reverse inequity. It maintains it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Two Worlds Dilemma</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-two-worlds-dilemma/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 18:37:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-two-worlds-dilemma/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/two-worlds-dilemma.jpg"/><description>&lt;p&gt;Every justice movement &amp;#8212; from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/gender-2/&#34;&gt;gender&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/sexuality&#34;&gt;sexuality&lt;/a&gt;, to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/&#34;&gt;every other dimension&lt;/a&gt; of who we are and how the world sees us &amp;#8212; has to answer two big questions: What&amp;#8217;s wrong with the world now? And what future world do you want to create?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m the fly on the wall for thousands of conversations about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/socialjustice/&#34;&gt;social justice&lt;/a&gt;. And a lot of what I witness online and in-person (in workshops and conferences and retreats) goes off the rails because of &lt;strong&gt;The Two Worlds Dilemma&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, there&amp;#8217;s the world we live in currently. The one we grew up in, the one we see as flawed. Let&amp;#8217;s call this &lt;strong&gt;Now World&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, there&amp;#8217;s the world we&amp;#8217;re working toward. The goal of our activism and change. &lt;a href=&#34;https://charleseisenstein.org/books/the-more-beautiful-world-our-hearts-know-is-possible/&#34;&gt;The more beautiful world our hearts know is possible&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Future World&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dilemma plays out in a few different ways, but they all feel roughly the same:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone doesn&amp;#8217;t agree with how your characterize Now World, so they argue against your Future World (and vice versa)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Someone thinks you&amp;#8217;re talking about Future World when really you&amp;#8217;re just describing Now World (and vice versa)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These arguments happen within the social justice movement as much as they do between &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/social-justice-fandom-aka-creating-new-barriers-name-dismantling-others/&#34;&gt;SJ Fandom&lt;/a&gt; and Anti-SJ people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course! Because there are tons of little things we can latch on to, and use to undermine the entire conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As SJ people, we can do a lot more to clarify:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What world we&amp;#8217;re talking about (Now, Future, or some other)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How our aspirational Future differs from Now&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The specific changes (new systems, norms, laws, etc.) we think will get us from Now to Future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can&amp;#8217;t just point out what&amp;#8217;s bad (about our Now, or other people&amp;#8217;s proposed Future).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we want to walk our talk, we have to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/&#34;&gt;point people toward&lt;/a&gt; good.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Incoming: “Social Justice, Minus Dogma” Course &#43; Community</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/social-justice-dogma-course-community/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 19:49:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/social-justice-dogma-course-community/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/social-justice-dogma-mooc-incoming.jpg"/><description>&lt;p&gt;Over 1,000 of you said you&amp;#8217;d want to participate in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://mailchi.mp/970acc41bb9c/social-justice-minus-dogma&#34;&gt;online course and community focusing on Social Justice, Minus Dogma&lt;/a&gt;. So I&amp;#8217;m going to hold up my end of the bargain and make the thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;address&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Update! The Course + Community is officially launched. &lt;/strong&gt;Read all about it at &lt;a href=&#34;https://course.sjmd.space&#34;&gt;www.sjmd.space&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://gum.co/sjmdcourse?wanted=true&#34;&gt;sign up today&lt;/a&gt; and you can start learning and participating in the community immediately.
&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I want to say how blown away I am that so many people are up for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a few weeks, I showed a question at the top of the site to some readers asking if you&amp;#8217;d want to participate in a course about &amp;#8220;social justice, minus dogma.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m wasn&amp;#8217;t sure what to expect, but I was bracing for &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past year plus that I&amp;#8217;ve been talking about &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tag/social-justice-dogma/&#34;&gt;Social Justice Dogma&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;#8217;ve become more and more aware of how pernicious it is, hearing from tons of you about how it&amp;#8217;s showing up in your life/work, but I haven&amp;#8217;t found a lot of hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest issues is that, by its very nature, Social Justice Dogma is something that a lot of people aren&amp;#8217;t willing, safe, and/or prepared to talk about. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/12/introduction-social-justice-dogma/&#34;&gt;first rule of SJD is you don&amp;#8217;t talk about SJD&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;#8217;ve written articles here, and I get emails from people saying &amp;#8220;Thanks for writing that. I see it all the time. Unfortunately, I can&amp;#8217;t share it because _____.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&#34;https://hereticpodcast.com/updates/want-to-be-a-guest-want-to-nominate-one-yes-please-heres-how/&#34;&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to get people to talk about Social Justice Dogma on a&lt;/a&gt; [][5]&lt;a href=&#34;https://hereticpodcast.com/updates/want-to-be-a-guest-want-to-nominate-one-yes-please-heres-how/&#34;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;, and I get replies like &amp;#8220;This is such an important conversation. I&amp;#8217;m totally with you. Unfortunately, I can&amp;#8217;t be on the show because _____.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In both cases, the blanks are the same: a list of reasons why being public about any of this stuff will be a disaster for them, personally and/or professionally. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/12/the-elephant-in-every-socially-just-room/&#34;&gt;This elephant has found its way to&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/12/the-elephant-in-every-socially-just-room/&#34;&gt;so many&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/12/the-elephant-in-every-socially-just-room/&#34;&gt;people&amp;#8217;s rooms.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The worst part: I totally get it. Talking about Social Justice Dogma has derailed my life. So far, it&amp;#8217;s not something I can say &amp;#8212; with any honesty &amp;#8212; that I&amp;#8217;m &lt;em&gt;happy&lt;/em&gt; I started writing about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that does not a good recipe for articles or podcast make. How are we supposed to fix problems that nobody is able to publicly talk about?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s where the 1,000+ of you come in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fact that over a thousand of you want to learn about this &amp;#8212; and will help&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;me&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;learn about it &amp;#8212; gives me hope.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even if &lt;em&gt;all I have&lt;/em&gt; is hope, I&amp;#8217;ve got plenty to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-the-course-community-1&#34;&gt;About the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mailchi.mp/970acc41bb9c/social-justice-minus-dogma&#34;&gt;Course + Community&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was holding off on creating even an outline of a syllabus until I knew it was something y&amp;#8217;all wanted, so I don&amp;#8217;t have a lot to share today other than &amp;#8220;I heard you loud and clear,&amp;#8221; and some really broad, vague ideas that I have in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I do know a few things. Whatever I put together will be&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/11/uncopyright/&#34;&gt;Uncopyrighted&lt;/a&gt; and offered in the spirit of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/gift-economy/&#34;&gt;gift economy&lt;/a&gt; (like everything I make here on IPM and elsewhere). Meaning &lt;strong&gt;money won&amp;#8217;t be a barrier, and I won&amp;#8217;t restrict you using any of the course materials&lt;/strong&gt; in your own community / work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community-driven, participative, and peer facilitated.&lt;/strong&gt; I will be learning from you, taking what I learn and doing my best to translate it into something that benefits us all, and doing what I can to create a platform where you can learn from one another.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guided by a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/&#34;&gt;social justice compass&lt;/a&gt;, with &lt;strong&gt;the goal of helping you better effect social justice&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/05/3-dimensional-social-justice/&#34;&gt;3-dimensionally&lt;/a&gt;, in your real life, local community, and movements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open to new learners on an ongoing, open enrollment basis. &lt;strong&gt;The first cohort to sign up with have a massive impact on the overall shape of the course&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8212; the structure, topics, community, outcomes, etc. &amp;#8212; &lt;strong&gt;but we won&amp;#8217;t be closing the door&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;#8217;s it. I have far more questions (and ideas, and vague excitements that I need to pin down) than answers right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve already talked with some fellow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/&#34;&gt;social justice people&lt;/a&gt; (an educator, an activist, and a non-profit leader) to get their ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking about this constantly for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ball is rolling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-to-come-soon&#34;&gt;More to Come. Soon.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll update this post as I have more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;s&gt;You can &lt;/s&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mailchi.mp/970acc41bb9c/social-justice-minus-dogma&#34;&gt;&lt;s&gt;sign up to get an invite via email when I open the course&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;s&gt; &lt;/s&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;s&gt;(if you already signed up, no need to do so again &amp;#8212; I got you, boo).&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;#8217;s live: Sign up at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sjmd.space&#34;&gt;www.sjmd.space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;d like to help out, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/contact/&#34;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m here to serve.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Defining LGBTQ&#43;</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/books/defining-lgbtq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:21:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/books/defining-lgbtq/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/img/posts/defining-lgbtq-by-sam-killermann-featured-image.jpg"/><description>&lt;p&gt;Defining LBGTQ+ is a helpful guide for getting a grasp on the terminology of gender and sexuality. It includes definitions for lots of terms, explainers for how to use them, and more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, before you get too excited, it&amp;#8217;s not really a book-book. Think of it more like an elaborately annotated glossary, or a dictionary with way too much context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;#8217;s short.&lt;/strong&gt; It weighs in at 37 pages and about 10,000 words.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;#8217;s printer-friendly.&lt;/strong&gt; I formatted to look great on an 8.5&amp;#8243; x 11&amp;#8243; letter size (sorry to my A4 friends abroad &amp;#8212; if enough of you ask, I&amp;#8217;ll format it in A4 as well!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;#8217;s uncopyrighted&lt;/strong&gt;. Like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/11/uncopyright/&#34;&gt;everything else I make here&lt;/a&gt;, so you can modify it and use it in your educational endeavors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a work in progress.&lt;/strong&gt; Just like my original post, I&amp;#8217;ll update this continually with changes suggested by you, and to reflect the evolution of culture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;#8217;s pay-what-you-want/can.&lt;/strong&gt; You can get it for free, or choose to pay (whatever amount you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;want to&lt;/em&gt; pay, even $0! I&amp;#8217;m happy to provide this as my gift to you). I&amp;#8217;m delivering this via &lt;a href=&#34;https://gum.co/dWKTo&#34;&gt;Gumroad&lt;/a&gt; (instead of as a .PDF download here) to make it easier to update you when I improve it or fix tpyos.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a big ol&amp;#8217; backstory behind it that I might get into at some point, but right now I just want to keep it at that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a thing that a lot of you asked for, and you now you can have it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share it with a friend, print a copy for your parent(s), or add it to a new employee orientation handbook. Do you. I&amp;#8217;m here to help.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>