<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title>It's Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/</link><description>Learn about gender, sexuality, &amp; social justice with Sam Killermann. Your free online resource for everything from genderbread people to LGBTQ vocabulary.</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 15:53:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Does the Genderbread Person Exclude Genderfluid People?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/articles/genderbread-person-and-genderfluidity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 15:53:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/articles/genderbread-person-and-genderfluidity/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/img/featured/genderfluid-genderbread.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>I got an email pointing out to me that &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/genderbread-person/">my versions of the Genderbread Person&lt;/a> exclude genderfluid people. And not just people who use &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/01/a-comprehensive-list-of-lgbtq-term-definitions/#term-genderfluid">the term &amp;ldquo;genderfluid&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> to identify themselves, but anyone who expresses gender differently at different times. So, do they? Let's figure it out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, I want to say what I pretty much always say when I get asked a question &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/genderbread/">about Genderbread&lt;/a>: it's not perfect, and it's a forever work in progress. That's why I've released so many different versions, all based on wonderful insight and pointed constructive criticism like this question. I addressed this in my &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/videos/gender-from-checkboxes-to-continuums">Nerd Nite Talk &amp;ldquo;Gender: From Boxes to -Ness.&amp;quot;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So nothing that follows is my trying to say this model can't be improved, or doesn't have issues. It can and it does. That's what we're doing here!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay, so wrapped cozily in that weighted blanket caveat, &lt;strong>does the Genderbread Person exclude genderfluid people? Or not make room for gender fluidity in general?&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don't think so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here's why:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The Genderbread Person is a tool for helping ourselves and others understand gender &amp;ndash; both our own, others&amp;rsquo;, and gender in general. Like any tool, it's efficacy is really dependent upon how well you use it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Just because you've only used a hammer for building, doesn't mean it's not great at dismantling. That's what those little claws on the back are for.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, of course, the Genderbread Person, like any other tool, has its limitations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, the Genderbread Person &lt;strong>is not&lt;/strong> a great tool for depicting comprehensive sexuality (that's why we have &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2016/05/sexualitree-model-of-comprehensive-sexuality/">the Sexualitree&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Try as you might, a hammer is never good for screwing. That's why we have screwdrivers.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, &lt;strong>it is&lt;/strong> well-suited to include and depict genderfuid people and gender fluidity, if you use it right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The problem, in this case, isn't the tool itself, but the ways a lot of people might be using it.&lt;/strong> And what is the &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; way to use the tool in this case?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, you just have to have two things in mind if you're using Genderbread to describe yourself, or include bits of instructions when you're using it with others:&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-youre-not-limited-to-a-single-dot">1. You're not limited to a single dot.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>You are invited to see yourself as existing anywhere along any of the continua (or scales). Including (and especially!) in multiple places!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, on the gender identity scales, you might see yourself as existing &lt;em>between&lt;/em> the roughly 20% point and 60% point of &amp;ldquo;woman-ness&amp;rdquo; &lt;strong>and&lt;/strong> 40% point and 80% point on the &amp;ldquo;man-ness.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="aligncenter">
&lt;img src="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/img/posts/genderbread-person-fluid-identity-scales.jpg" alt="A 0-100 scale for woman-ness with a circle drawn from the 20% point to the 60% point and a scale for man-ness with a circle from 40% to 80%" class="shadow" />
&lt;figcaption>How you might plot that example.&lt;figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Those ranges being the wiggle room for the fluidity you notice in your experience of gender. (Sidebar: if that's actually how you see yourself, we should be friends, because ditto: that's how I'd plot my Genderbread 😘)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or maybe you're a firm 0% on man-ness, but identify with different amounts of woman-ness depending on your situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here's how a friend of mine plots their gender identity scales, to describe themself as above &amp;ndash; a &amp;ldquo;genderfluid femme&amp;rdquo; way of doodling gender:&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="aligncenter">
&lt;img src="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/img/posts/genderbread-person-fluid-femme-identity.jpg" alt="An X at 0 for man-ness, with a big circle covering most of woman-ness, and an asterisk anchored at about the 30% mark" class="shadow" />
&lt;figcaption>The asterisk represents how they most often feel, but the circle is range of fluidity.&lt;figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>Drawing ranges (e.g., with circles, brackets, or lines) are one of the ways you can represent fluidity on the Genderbread scales (btw: not just on Identity, but also on the Expression, Sex, and Attraction scales). But it's not the only way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, I've seen other people in workshops use different letters (instead of a dot or a star or asterisk) to represent the different ways they experience things based on different situations. Like an &amp;ldquo;F&amp;rdquo; for &amp;ldquo;around family,&amp;rdquo; an &amp;ldquo;M&amp;rdquo; for &amp;ldquo;me, by myself,&amp;rdquo; and an &amp;ldquo;S&amp;rdquo; for &amp;ldquo;in society.&amp;rdquo; This method highlights the fluidity of how being around other people, or in certain situations, can affect how we experience gender.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the list goes on. These examples aren't meant to be exhaustive, or even clear &amp;ldquo;Do it this way&amp;rdquo; instructions, but meant to highlight the broader point I made above:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you're not just limiting yourself to one dot on each continuum, the Genderbread Person is a great starting place for understanding and depicting gender fluidity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, on to the other point.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="2-your-place-on-the-scales-can-change">2. Your place on the scales can change.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>However you see yourself in regards to the Genderbread scales of Identity, Expression, Sex, and Attraction right now &amp;ndash; today, in this exact moment &amp;ndash; isn't set in stone. If you doodled yourself into that diagram again in the future, it's totally okay if your answers change. And they most likely will!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This hits at the more long-term time frame aspect of gender fluidity, and also at the societal evolution of gender itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of people think that filling out the Genderbread Person is like filling in a birth certificate: it's a one-time thing. Well, it's not a one-time thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You're welcome to update how you see yourself based on how you've changed, or how society has changed, or how you haven't really changed but you just finally see yourself for who you are &amp;ndash; however often as you like!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Revisit the Genderbread, and &lt;em>your&lt;/em> Genderbread, as often as you'd like. I always smile when I hear from people &amp;ndash; in workshops or &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/reply/">via replies&lt;/a> on this site &amp;ndash; that how they've seen themselves in the scales of the Genderbread Person has changed since last time they considered it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You're not doing it wrong if it changes, or if you're not sure if how you see yourself now will represent how you see yourself in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Indeed, the Genderbread Person is &lt;em>just like&lt;/em> a birth certificate*: you can update it later if you realize the scribbles that were scribbled don't do a good job of representing who you really are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(*This parallel is true in many countries and states, and generally true as a &amp;ldquo;should&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; it &lt;em>should&lt;/em> be this way with birth certificates)&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="creativity-is-encouraged">Creativity is encouraged.&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Take your marker out and have fun. Blot out things that don't apply for you, and draw in the things you need to better show up. Color outside the lines.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is as much a statement about gender in general, as a suggestion for how to use the Genderbread Person as a tool.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And, of course, this applies directly to using Genderbread to represent and understand genderfluid experiences, identities, expressions, and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don't think that, if you're following the above rules (or, more importantly, not adding restrictive rules that need not be added), the Genderbread Person is inherently exclusive of gender fluidity. It's not a hammer trying to be a screwdriver in this regard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But maybe I'm wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If, after reading this, you still think the Genderbread Person isn't inclusive of genderfluid people, please let me know! And share your ideas for how it can be improved. That's what the reply button is for.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Brand New Site for a Brand New Decade</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/news/brand-new-site-for-a-brand-new-decade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 11:49:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/news/brand-new-site-for-a-brand-new-decade/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/img/featured/succulent-not-included.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>I created &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/about/">the IPM site&lt;/a> in 2011 not knowing what I was doing, or what to expect. Hundreds of millions of downloads, shares, and resources distributed later, as we're about to embark on a new decade, I figured it was time to recreate this site. Bonus: now I &lt;em>kinda&lt;/em> know what I'm doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let's start with some context.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The short version of the history of this site goes like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It started purely as a way to tell people about the comedy show I was performing on college campuses (named &amp;ldquo;It's Pronounced Metrosexual&amp;rdquo;). Then I started writing articles here, which quickly took off, and it turned into a comedy show + free online resource (and I had millions of people coming to the site not even knowing it was a comedy show). That chimera existed until last year, when I stopped performing the comedy show, and this site became solely a free online resource.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Throughout that decade, I redesigned this site four times (all four versions powered by Wordpress), to respond to the changing nature of what it was, and to keep improving based on the best practices I was learning about. The site was hacked countless times (and brought down a few).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because of the traffic the site gets, combined with the threat of hacking, I was booted from hosting companies, donated servers, and migrated hosting companies about 10 times. Each time more expensive than the last, with the most recent bill running between $400 and $800 per month. That's a lot of money for me, someone whose personal income fluctuates around the poverty line.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a long time, performing the show (and being paid honoraria for doing so) was able to cover the costs of providing this free online resource to millions of people every year, in every country on Earth. But when I stopped performing the show last year, I &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/09/the-state-of-this-site-or-funding-online-work-in-2018-an-infographic/">turned to my readers&lt;/a> for direct support.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now we're here, at the end of 2019, and the end of this weird-to-describe decade (the 2010s?), wrapping up a year that itself has lasted &lt;em>at least&lt;/em> four decades (#ThanksTrump), and you're reading these words on a brand new version of the site.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="whats-new-pussycat">What's new, pussycat?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you've ever visited IPM before, the difference will be obvious (&lt;a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20191028041633/https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/">here's what the site looked like yesterday&lt;/a> for the unanointed). But the change goes WAY beyond what you're seeing on the surface.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the first version of the site that I've built to actually do what you all seem insistent upon using this site for: sharing &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/articles/">articles&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/downloads/">downloading .PDFs&lt;/a> bajillions of times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I'm no longer using &lt;a href="https://wordpress.org">Wordpress&lt;/a> &amp;ndash; or even servers, in the traditional sense &amp;ndash; to power this site in a traditional sense. I created it using what's called &lt;a href="https://jamstack.org/">JAMStack methodology&lt;/a>, which I'll suffice it to say &amp;ndash; at the risk of losing you in the weeds &amp;ndash; is &lt;em>very different&lt;/em> from Wordpress (&lt;a href="https://github.com/killermann/ipm">here's the code&lt;/a>, for the curious). And good different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>IPM can now, finally, handle huge spikes in traffic&lt;/strong>, and those traffic spikes won't bring down the site or cost me a ton of money in server overages. For the past few years, I've had this really weird problem where I actually don't want new articles to go &amp;ldquo;viral,&amp;rdquo; because I literally couldn't afford it. Now that IPM is serverless, this is longer a problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>IPM finally works well in the parts of the world where internet bandwidth is sparse.&lt;/strong> I have always been amazed at the traffic the resources I post here get from remote, isolated parts of the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, a few years ago I realized that I had a big constituency of readers in Egypt, many of whom lived in the middle of the Sahara, and &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/sam-killermann-in-cairo/">I went to visit them&lt;/a> and learn about how they were using this site, articles, and edugraphics. It was an eye-opening trip in a million ways, one of which was I realized how much of a pain in the ass it was to load my site on a phone in the desert. Or to download a .PDF that was 5MB for local organizing and protesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That's no longer a problem, now that I've left the bloated and slow architecture of Wordpress, and reduced my overall data delivery by about 90%.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The benefits of this change are two-fold: people can access the site faster regardless of where you are in the world, and the carbon footprint of the site is significantly reduced (Yes, websites create greenhouse gases &amp;ndash; and most of them are an unrecognized nightmare on this front).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>And speaking of access, most importantly to me, IPM finally works for all users, especially those of you who are blind or visually impaired.&lt;/strong> &lt;a href="https://www.wired.com/story/web-accessibility-blind-users-dominos/">Accessibility is a huge problem on the internet at large&lt;/a>, and maybe you'd think websites about &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/categories/social-justice">social justice&lt;/a> wouldn't contribute to that problem. But we do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Literally &lt;em>every&lt;/em> social justice / feminism / activist website I visit regularly is inaccessible. I'm not going to name names here and put people on blast, or do a little &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/hypocrisy-theatre/">hypocrisy theatre performance&lt;/a>, but you probably go to a lot of the same sites. And some of them &lt;em>perform&lt;/em> accessibility, but none of them actually do it. Because they're not prioritizing accessibility &amp;ndash; they're prioritizing search engines or clicks or donations or something else. IPM was no different yesterday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I've always &lt;em>said&lt;/em> IPM was accessible. Because it's free, &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/uncopyright/">uncopyrighted&lt;/a>, and I don't have paywalls or other barriers preventing people from accessing the content here (operating outside of capitalism an within the &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/gift-economy/">&amp;ldquo;gift economy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>). But it never truly was.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the past 5 months, as I was building this new site from the foundation up, I had a cabal of accessibility activists and IPM fans who are blind in my corner. I'd send them a new version of the site, they'd point out all the things I messed up, then I'd google a ton, learn how to fix it, fix it, and send it back.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now, today, IPM is finally accessible in every sense of the word &amp;ndash; or at least as close as it's ever been. This was the primary guiding light for the redesign of this site. There's still room for improvement, and improving is the goal. With that in mind, please &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/contact/">let me know&lt;/a> how I can make this site more accessible to you, and I'll get on it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>TL;DR: &lt;strong>All of these new things can represented in this one image&lt;/strong>, which is the new &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/web/tools/lighthouse">Google Lighthouse&lt;/a> score for IPM:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://i.imgur.com/eKcVSJF.png" alt="100 for performance, 100 for accessibility, 100 for best practices, 100 for SEO, and progressive web app enabled">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="whats-not-new-pussycats">What's not new, pussycats:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Beyond the site's digital architecture itself, not much is changing.&lt;/p>
&lt;aside class="heyHeyLook wednesdayEmail">&lt;p>&lt;span class="icon">💌&lt;/span>&lt;strong>Most Wednesdays&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>&lt;p>I publish new Social Justice, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Resources.&lt;/p> &lt;a class="button" title="Join my mailing list" href="http://bit.ly/2MmE28c" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Get the Email.&lt;/a>&lt;/aside>
&lt;p>This is still a ship with a single crew member, and I'll be the one writing &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/articles/">all the words&lt;/a>, doodling all &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/edugraphics/">the doodles&lt;/a>, creating &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/">the courses&lt;/a>, publishing &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/books/">the books&lt;/a>, replying to your &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/reply#source=Brand%20New%20Site%20for%20a%20Brand%20New%20Decade">replies&lt;/a>, and coding the code (and &lt;em>learning how to code the code&lt;/em>, because &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/about/about-sam-killermann/">my background&lt;/a> and degrees are all decidedly &lt;em>humanities&lt;/em>, so this computer science world is my exploration of an alien planet).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everything here is &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/11/uncopyright/">still uncopyrighted&lt;/a>, and yours to print, use, improve, and share however you'd like.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I still think &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mw7Gryt-rcc">John Mulaney's &amp;ldquo;What's New Pussycat?&amp;rdquo; bit&lt;/a> is one of the funniest stories ever told on stage.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/5-reasons-im-a-social-justice-all/">I still love you.&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me know what you think about the new site by hitting that reply button below, or &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/contact/">sending me an email&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here's to another 10 years of learning, teaching, activism, advocacy, and trying to make the world a more socially-just place,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;lt;3 sK&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Maybe we should stop using “White supremacist” and “bad” interchangeably?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/07/maybe-we-should-stop-using-white-supremacist-and-bad-interchangeably/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 17:34:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/07/maybe-we-should-stop-using-white-supremacist-and-bad-interchangeably/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/white-supremacy-in-action-flowchart-on-brick.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>Recently, I’ve been noticing this weird trend. It’s become prevalent within the social justice movement, and I haven’t seen anyone else flag it. I brought it up in the context of our &lt;a href="https://www.sjmd.space">Social Justice, Minus Dogma Course + Community&lt;/a>, and it turns out other people are noticing it too. So let’s flag it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The short version is this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of people are using domination/oppression language (e.g., “white supremacist”, “patriarchal”) as synonyms for “bad” and marginalization/anti-oppression language (e.g., “indigenous,” “decolonized,” “feminist”) as synonyms for “good” — devoid of any meaningful connection to the actual structure, system, or culture they’re mentioning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My guess is that it’s a combination of our &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/isms-not-ists/">over focusing on “-ists” instead of “-isms”&lt;/a> plus the &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-social-justice-power-inverse/">“social justice power inverse,”&lt;/a> but I’ll leave the detective work up to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why highlight this at all? In short, because actual, sincere, real-life White supremacy is on the rise, and we need to be able to call it when we see it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Calling things “White supremacist” that aren’t creates a lot of unhelpful noise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wrote this article a few days before we got a blazingly clear example of White supremacy in action, when &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1150381394234941448">U.S. President Donald Trump went on a “go back to your country” rant&lt;/a> against several members of congress, all of whom are women of color.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Being careful to use the phrase “White supremacy” correctly would allow a criticism of Trump’s rant, and other White supremacist actions, to be held as distinct from general criticisms of Trump.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Both are totally valid, by the way! However, we need to know which basket we’re putting our eggs into.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We need to be able to separate “I don’t like what you’re saying” from “What you’re saying is advancing White supremacy and ethnic cleansing.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And right now we’re not doing a good job of that, at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll explain what I’m talking about in more detail, then talk about a few of the reasons &lt;em>I&lt;/em> think this is (deeply) unhelpful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’d be curious to hear what you think, if you’re also noticing this. We’ll make space for that, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="8220white-supremacist8221-doesn8217t-mean-a-8220white-person-doing-something-bad8221">“White Supremacist” doesn’t mean a “White person doing something bad”&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Let me first say that, overall, it’s great that more people are becoming comfy using phrases like “white supremacist.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The same goes for words like “patriarchal,” “colonial,” “heterosexist,” etc. They’re useful words that can be used to pinpoint exactly what we’re talking about, concerned about in society, and wanting to change.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(If we could just add “capitalist” to our comfort zone, &lt;a href="https://www.mediaed.org/transcripts/Bell-Hooks-Transcript.pdf">we might even make bell hooks proud&lt;/a>.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The issue I’m flagging here is&lt;/strong> &lt;em>&lt;strong>not&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> &lt;strong>the use of the phrase “white supremacist”&lt;/strong> (or any of these other words I’m lumping together as domination/oppression language).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The issue is people using these words like duct tape, sticking them to every problem they notice.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here’s what it looks like in general:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Someone does something harmful.&lt;/em> Are they White? “White supremacy in action.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Someone shares a terrible idea.&lt;/em> Are they a man? “Patriarchy in action.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>An organization has a White man executive director&lt;/em> and &lt;em>does something unhelpful&lt;/em>. “White supremacist patriarchy.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here it is in flowchart form:&lt;figure class="wp-block-image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img data-src="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/FLOWCHART-If-a-white-person-did-it-its-white-supremacy.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3978 lazy-load" srcset="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/FLOWCHART-If-a-white-person-did-it-its-white-supremacy.png 800w, https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/FLOWCHART-If-a-white-person-did-it-its-white-supremacy-300x180.png 300w, https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/FLOWCHART-If-a-white-person-did-it-its-white-supremacy-768x462.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" />&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the flipside of the same coin is also true, where we see people attributing anything positive someone does or shares to a marginalized identity or anti-oppression -ism. For example, a “better” approach to something becomes labeled as the “feminist” approach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a few concrete examples, I’ve recently seen high profile, &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/social-justice-fandom-aka-creating-new-barriers-name-dismantling-others/">“social justice famous,”&lt;/a> or virally-shared takes that included:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Democracy equated with White supremacy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Exercising and being a physical trainer equated with literal Nazism&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Facilitating a Q&amp;amp;A session in a thoughtful way equated with feminist decolonialization&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Don’t focus too much on those examples if you have seen your own and they’re different. I just pulled them from the top of my mind as things I’ve seen in the last few days, and wanted to share them for people for whom this was all too abstract.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The examples don’t matter as much as the phenomenon in general, which is using loaded oppression language as synonymous with “bad.”&lt;/p>
&lt;address>
I&amp;#8217;m not linking to specific examples, because I refuse to publicly drag people, especially people who are working with the intent of social justice. Examples of this are abound in my social media feeds, as well as the mainstream social justice blogs/sites I read, so I&amp;#8217;m guessing the same is true for you, if you&amp;#8217;re a person reading this site.
&lt;/address>
&lt;p>Okay, so hopefully this all makes sense so far. Let me say another big disclaimer before I go on:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A lot of times this is all true.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That is, I’m &lt;em>not&lt;/em> saying that white people doing bad things is never an example of white supremacy. A lot of bad things white people do, and bad ideas white people have, are white supremacist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m also &lt;em>not&lt;/em> saying that a better approach to something isn’t feminist. A lot of better approaches are feminist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(Repeat the above examples for every parallel domination/oppression and marginalization/anti-oppression axis in your head, and I’ll stand by it. I’m just going to save you the reading time, and the earth the carbon emissions, and not type those 1,000+ words.)&lt;/p>
&lt;aside class="heyHeyLook wednesdayEmail">&lt;p>&lt;span class="icon">💌&lt;/span>&lt;strong>Most Wednesdays&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>&lt;p>I publish new Social Justice, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Resources.&lt;/p> &lt;a class="button" title="Join my mailing list" href="http://bit.ly/2MmE28c" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Get the Email.&lt;/a>&lt;/aside>
&lt;p>Here’s the part I’m flagging:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A lot of times it’s not true.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>White people do stupid stuff that isn’t White supremacist. Men have terrible ideas that aren’t patriarchal. And there are great ideas that aren’t feminist. Etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Further, and more prickly, advancing White supremacy isn’t merely the domain of white people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Black people, indigenous people, and people of color in general can all advance White supremacy, can share White supremacist ideas, and can do bad things that are White supremacist.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Us using “White supremacist” as a synonym for “White person doing stupid shit” erases those realities, which is one of the problems that led me to flagging this. But it’s not the &lt;em>big&lt;/em> problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what8217s-the-big-problem">What’s the big problem?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If it’s true a lot of the time, what’s the harm in labeling things as “white supremacist” or “patriarchal” when they’re bad?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And if we want to advance the goals of feminism, why not arbitrarily label good things as “feminist”?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The big problem here is that when you use a word to mean everything, it stops meaning anything.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’re diluting the usefulness of these otherwise super useful, targeted, precise words when we use them to describe everything bad.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As a person who spends a lot of time trying to &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/01/a-comprehensive-list-of-lgbtq-term-definitions/">clarify language for people, writing definitions, and updating meanings of terminology&lt;/a> as it shifts with culture, I have both a unique vantage point and ax to grind on this front.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Words have power. Language shapes our realities as much as it reflects them. Every time a person uses a word incorrectly it erodes the power of that word.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because what we’re doing here — trying to advance the goals of social justice, move towards equity and liberation — matters deeply to us, so should every misstep.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Calling things White supremacist that aren’t ultimately helps White supremacy, and hinders the progress of social justice.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ditto goes for every other “bad thing” we falsely attribute to an “-ism” we’re trying to unravel.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I’m not &lt;em>just&lt;/em> talking &lt;a href="http://www.storyarts.org/library/aesops/stories/boy.html">“Boy Who Cried Wolf”&lt;/a>-style either. Let’s work through some of the other problems within the frame of a proposed solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="proposing-an-alternative">Proposing an Alternative&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What if, instead of the algorithm above, we committed the following:&lt;figure class="wp-block-image">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img data-src="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/FLOWCHART-If-it-advances-the-goals-of-White-supremacy-its-white-supremacy.png" alt="" class="wp-image-3984 lazy-load" srcset="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/FLOWCHART-If-it-advances-the-goals-of-White-supremacy-its-white-supremacy.png 800w, https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/FLOWCHART-If-it-advances-the-goals-of-White-supremacy-its-white-supremacy-300x189.png 300w, https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/FLOWCHART-If-it-advances-the-goals-of-White-supremacy-its-white-supremacy-768x484.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" />&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>White supremacy, patriarchy, colonialism, and the rest are all ideologies and belief systems. They are social projects with specific goals. They’re not synonyms for “evil.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But how can we &lt;em>know&lt;/em> if something contributes to the goals, outcomes, or ideology of White supremacy?&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="we8217ll-have-to-discuss-it-and-figure-it-out-ourselves">We’ll have to discuss it, and figure it out ourselves.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If we discuss, with other social justice people, whether or not something said or done is “contributing to the goals, outcomes, or ideology of White supremacy”, and not just something we disagree with, dislike, or find gross, I have full faith we land on the truth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that will, in the long run, benefit social justice and our individual efforts — whether it turns out the thing &lt;em>was&lt;/em> or &lt;em>wasn’t&lt;/em> White supremacy in action.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>When we determine that it is&lt;/strong>, we’ll have spent time figuring it out, questioning, digging in, proposing alternatives, and getting to the bottom of the issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And this time spent isn’t time wasted, it’s practice! Because anyone else we talk to about that thing will likely have some of those same questions, counterpoints, and skepticisms, and we’ll already have an answer in mind that can move the conversation from that sticking point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>When we determine that it’s not,&lt;/strong> we’ll have spared ourselves a ton of wasted time advocating something to other people an idea that — when we really dug into it — wasn’t rooted in something meaningful. That’s not just time saved, but an opportunity cost of trust and respect avoided.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Regardless of the outcome, discussing whether or not something actually &lt;em>is&lt;/em> White supremacist will have another benefit…&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="we-can8217t-just-fall-back-on-dogma">We can’t just fall back on dogma.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tag/social-justice-dogma/">Social Justice Dogma&lt;/a> shows up in our lives in lots of ways, and many of those prevent us from asking questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If someone says something is racist, our knee-jerk reaction is to distance ourselves as far away from it as possible, not to ask questions and get to the bottom of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We don’t often ask “Is this &lt;em>really&lt;/em> White supremacy in action? What if it were something else?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we question it, we run the risk of being questioned ourselves: “Are &lt;em>you&lt;/em> enabling racism? Have &lt;em>you&lt;/em> internalized White supremacy? Why are &lt;em>you&lt;/em> defending a racist?”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So we don’t question it. We just jump in and support. That’s all the dogma allows us to do.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While this might benefit us individually, it hinders us as a movement. Because when we toe the line of dogma we’re more concerned with preserving our relationships, or not being “canceled” or outcast, and we center our individual status instead of the cause we’re advancing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this way, the social justice dogma is a trap: it always gives us an answer, but sometimes what we really need is the ability to ask constructive questions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we keep our cause in mind, the movement front and center, the path seems forward becomes clear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As soon as we start questioning things, and getting to the root of an issue, we’re pushing back against the dogma and creating a chance for living social justice.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="cleaning-up-the-garbage-we-notice">Cleaning up the garbage we notice.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>For a moment, imagine that every time we notice an injustice — something standing in the way of social justice, or gender equity, or sexual liberation — we’re flagging a piece of garbage in a park.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’re walking around and making mental notes. “There’s an empty potato chip bag by that tree. A crumpled can under that bench. Some styrofoam floating in that pond.” And so on.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And we’re walking around the park making those notes because we plan to clean up the park. But first we’re getting a sense of the tools we need. How many trash bags, nets for the water, little poker things for the cans, etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Would it be helpful if we mistook a leaf for a potato chip bag? Or some pond scum for styrofoam? It would not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we want to actually rid the park of trash, we’d have to focus on the trash. We’d be wasting our time and resources trying to scoop up everything that looks kinda like trash.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We can see social justice, and our efforts within the social justice movement, in this same way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every time we call something “White supremacist” we’re creating a task for ourselves, something we need to clean up, in order to advance the cause of equity and racial justice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We can’t dismantle White supremacy unless we can accurately spot it in action. To do that&lt;/strong> &lt;em>&lt;strong>we need to be able to ask questions,&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> &lt;strong>&lt;em>and be willing to find the answers.&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’ll only benefit from focusing on the real problems.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="to-recap">To Recap:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Because I’m concerned this article is one of those that’s likely to get misinterpreted (and there’s a &lt;em>non-zero&lt;/em> chance it will un-ironically be labeled White supremacist itself), let’s recap.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to be absotively sure you know what I’m saying here, and — if it motivates you — that it pushes you in the direction I’m hoping to nudge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, here’s what I’m saying:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>We often use the phrase “White supremacist” simply to mean “a white person did something bad.”&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Some bad things aren’t White supremacist (or patriarchal, or sexist, cissexist, heterosexist, ableist, or any-ist).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Being careless about the distinction enables actual White supremacy (and other -isms) by providing cover and distraction.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Being clear about the distinction between “White supremacy” and “bad things that aren’t actually White supremacy” will help us move justice movements forward.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>So let’s be intentional with how and when we choose to call something “White supremacy” (and make sure that the thing in question is actually White supremacy in action).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Hopefully that shines through in the article above.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Now I’d like to hear what you have to say&lt;/strong>! &lt;strong>You can respond to me directly by&lt;/strong> &lt;a class="typeform-share" data-mode="popup" style="font-weight: bold;" href="https://hues.typeform.com/to/LApMm4">clicking here&lt;/a> (anonymous, quick, &amp;amp; easy)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Social Justice Minus Dogma Online Course</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/social-justice-minus-dogma-course/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/social-justice-minus-dogma-course/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/img/featured/social-justice-minus-dogma-course-screenshot.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>Over the course of 6 weeks of self-guided learning (or however long you choose), explore the social justice dogma, identify its cornerstones and pitfalls, and plot a path forward toward true living social justice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This course is an extension of all the writing I've done here about &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/social-justice-dogma/">&amp;ldquo;social justice dogma.&amp;quot;&lt;/a> Beyond thoroughly explaining what it is, and why it might be problematic, it's a map for taking steps toward living social justice, minus the dogma &amp;ndash; for educators, activists, and &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/">all types of social justice people&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="button-stack" style="margin: 2em auto; text-align: center; font-size: 1.2em;">
&lt;a class="button" href="https://gum.co/sjmdcourse?wanted=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Enroll Now&lt;/a> &lt;a class="button button-alt" href="https://course.sjmd.space" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Learn More&lt;/a>&lt;/div>
&lt;p>The course consists of 6 modules (in addition to Orientation &amp;amp; Graduation):&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dot-Com-Munity&lt;/strong>, answering: What does it take to create a community where you confront a dogma? What’s at stake? How easily can things go wrong? How can we create a durable container to hold real community?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Barks Like a Dogma&lt;/strong>, answering: What do we mean by “Social Justice Dogma”? Can we spot dogmatic thinking, acting, and believing? In what ways does SJD show up in our lives?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Cutting Cornerstones&lt;/strong>, answering: Why does dogma flourish? What are the foundational beliefs of SJD? How does SJD provide positive feedback?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>The Acolytes&lt;/strong>, answering: What are the virtues of the defenders of SJD? How can we give SJD acolytes a way out? What will an SJMD conversation feel like?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Theses Pieces&lt;/strong>, answering: What does social justice look like without the dogma? How do we avoid the pitfalls of recreating SJD? What are the building blocks of living social justice? How do we chart paths forward?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>SJMD IRL&lt;/strong>, answering: How do we bring SJMD to our IRL communities? What’s included in our MVP? What are the first steps we’re going to take?&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Like everything I do, it's offered in the gift economy, meaning you choose a tuition level that works for you (even $0), based on your ability, gratitude, or sense of what it's worth.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="button-stack" style="margin: 2em auto; text-align: center; font-size: 1.2em;">
&lt;a class="button" href="https://gum.co/sjmdcourse?wanted=true" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Enroll Now&lt;/a> &lt;a class="button button-alt" href="https://course.sjmd.space" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Learn More&lt;/a>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>How much injustice can we justify on the path toward social justice?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/05/justifying-injustice-for-social-justice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:36:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/05/justifying-injustice-for-social-justice/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/dont-worry.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>Close your eyes and imagine the world you would describe as living social justice. Equitable. Utopian, even. Whatever comes to mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Give it a shot. I’ll wait a moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What does it feel like to occupy that [future world][1] where all of our work as [social justice people][2] came to fruition?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How does it differ from our world today?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How radical of a difference you notice will be determined by the world you have in your mind. But surely the ways we spend our time, the social problems we grapple with, and even the ways we organize societies aren’t the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What do “jobs” look like? Do they even still exist? What about politics? What will there be more of? What will there be less of?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There’s likely a long list of [actions, attitudes, and beliefs][3] that wouldn’t make sense in that world, but seem perfectly sensical in our world right now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What comes to mind?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Focus on the gap, the distance between what would be normal in a socially-just world, compared to what is normal now in our oppressive and unjust world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay, now here comes the really tough part:&lt;/p>
&lt;aside class="heyHeyLook wednesdayEmail">&lt;p>&lt;span class="icon">💌&lt;/span>&lt;strong>Most Wednesdays&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>&lt;p>I publish new Social Justice, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Resources.&lt;/p> &lt;a class="button" title="Join my mailing list" href="http://bit.ly/2MmE28c" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Get the Email.&lt;/a>&lt;/aside>
&lt;p>How many things are you currently doing, arguing, and believing — in this world, today, on a regular basis — that are &lt;em>directly antithetical&lt;/em> to the socially-just world you imagined?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That fly in the face of it. The things you know aren’t “ideal.” The things “We’ll stop” doing, arguing, or believing “once we get there.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Where’s the line between &lt;em>justifying an inequitable action&lt;/em> today in the pursuit of a socially-just tomorrow, and &lt;em>actively creating&lt;/em> a different form of injustice?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I suspect we cross that line daily.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And what inequitable actions do we need to stop justifying today, in order to clear the path to the world you imagined?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My hunch: all of them.
[1]: /2019/03/the-two-worlds-dilemma/
[2]: /2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/
[3]: /2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>-isms, not -ists</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/isms-not-ists/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 16:11:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/isms-not-ists/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/found-the-problem.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>To achieve the goals of &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/socialjustice/">social justice&lt;/a>, we need to reform society at the system level. We need to dismantle rac-&lt;em>ism&lt;/em>, sex-&lt;em>ism&lt;/em>, cissex-&lt;em>ism&lt;/em>, heterosex-&lt;em>ism&lt;/em>, gender-&lt;em>ism&lt;/em>, able-&lt;em>ism&lt;/em>, class-&lt;em>ism&lt;/em>, and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Too much of social justice discourse and calls-to-action are focused on the &lt;em>-ists&lt;/em>, the people participating in (and perpetuating) those systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Our focus on individual actors keeps increasing in social justice spaces&lt;/strong> I occupy. It’s almost all of what I notice in online social justice activism/advocacy. I’m guessing you’ve noticed it, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This focus often takes the form of &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/10/what-kind-of-social-justice-are-you-talking-about/">punitive social justice&lt;/a>, identifying perpetrators, dragging them, publicly shaming them, “canceling” them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We also see it in listicles with titles that highlight the # Ways You’re Part of the Problem. Or the inverse: # Ways to Be Part of the Solution.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We experience it in workshops with activities designed to highlight individuals’ &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tag/privilege">privilege&lt;/a> or contributions to oppression.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every time a finger gets pointed at &lt;strong>a person&lt;/strong> — whether they’re a Fortune 500 CEO or a high school student — we’re focusing on an &lt;em>-ist&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We do it because it feels good, or tangible, or even just doable. It’s something that’s within our power. The system seems out of reach.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every campaign to “cancel” an &lt;em>-ist&lt;/em> — whether successful or not — isn’t the same as addressing the system. It brings our attention &lt;em>away&lt;/em> from the system and toward an individual within it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s the &lt;em>-ism&lt;/em> that created the conditions where that person’s behavior seemed right, celebrated, or like the only path they could walk, but instead of addressing that, we scapegoat the &lt;em>-ist&lt;/em>. A ceremonial sacrifice that opens up a vacancy the machine will dutifully fill with a replacement who can perform the role.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The system is unscathed, and potentially strengthened: the next person won’t make that same misstep, better concealing the machinations of the &lt;em>-ism&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Do we need to focus on &lt;em>-ists&lt;/em>, to some extent, in the pursuit of social justice? To hold people accountable, transform them, foster growth?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe. I don’t know. I certainly know that I’m not saying — here, now — that we never should, or that we never need to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What I’m saying is that focusing on&lt;/strong> &lt;em>&lt;strong>-ists&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> &lt;strong>will never be sufficient. That it’s energy we’re directing toward a symptom, not a cause.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that if we don’t do it carefully, it’s likely to create more problems than solutions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It already is.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Privilege Lie</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/the-privilege-lie/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 23:41:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/the-privilege-lie/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/privilege-pie.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>I’ve said it myself. I’ve read it a hundred times. You’ve probably heard it, or said it yourself. It usually goes something like, “We’re not asking you to give up your privileges. We’re trying to grant access to others who don’t have them.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or a pie analogy: “Privilege isn’t like pie. You don’t have to give up your slice for others to enjoy it.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The idea behind these sentiments is that the goal of &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/socialjustice/">social justice&lt;/a> is not to take privileges away&lt;/strong> from the “privileged” and give them to the “oppressed” (&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/binary-thinking/">an unhelpful binary&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When we &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/privilege-lists/">list privileges&lt;/a> (e.g., &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/11/30-examples-of-male-privilege/">male privileges&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/list-of-cisgender-privileges/">cisgender privileges&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/list-of-examples-of-christian-privileg/">Christian privileges&lt;/a>) and ask people to “check their privilege,” we say we’re not asking them to give anything up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Instead, we say that the goal is for &lt;em>everyone&lt;/em> to have access to those privileges.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We say this, usually, as a defense to [privileged] people pushing back against our goals.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>And it’s a lie. A well-intentioned lie, but a lie nonetheless.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To oversimplify, privilege shows up in two ways: ways society is organized to &lt;em>give you advantages&lt;/em>, and ways &lt;em>you aren’t penalized&lt;/em> for who you are.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Everything that falls into the first bucket only exists in contrast to not having it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If white-ness is how you got your job, or male-ness is why your opinion is received as fact, or straight-ness is why your parental fitness is unquestioned, then a socially just world is one where your job, opinion, parenthood, and more aren’t granted based on those identities. Where your advantage is taken away.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is that equity? And justice? And &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/build-your-own-world/">a world I want to build&lt;/a>? Absolutely.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But it’s also one where a lot of people no longer hold privileges they currently do. We need to be honest about that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Replacing One Binary with Another</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/binary-thinking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 16:43:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/binary-thinking/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/toucans-of-people.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>I’ve always believed that one of our superpowers as gender/sexuality activists, and &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/">social justice people&lt;/a> more broadly, is our ability to hold space for nuance. In the past few years, that belief has been crumbling. In part because of how much I’m seeing us replace one way of binary thinking for another.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a long time, we’ve known that sexuality isn’t a binary thing. It’s not gay/straight, either/or. It’s often both/and, neither, or another option altogether. &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kinsey_scale">The Kinsey Scale&lt;/a> often comes to mind here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More recently, we’ve recognized the same thing about gender. We’ve &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NRcPXtqdKjE">addressed the complexities of gender&lt;/a>, viewing it on a spectrum, &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/02/gender-scales-or-spectrums/">or, better, on scales&lt;/a>. And &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/breaking-through-the-binary-gender-explained-using-continuums/">broken through the binary&lt;/a> of woman/man. Just like sexuality, it’s not an either/or, but more of a both/and, neither, or another option altogether.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, it’s not entirely clear to me that everyone writing about binaries (e.g., the gender binary) is saying the same thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So allow me to be clear what I mean (and have always meant) by binary: two options. Two ways to be. Two categories. And that’s it. Only two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A binary can be succinctly summed up by this (no words needed):&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="wp-block-image">
&lt;p>&lt;img data-src="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/boxes-1.png" alt="Two empty checkboxes" class="wp-image-3733 lazy-load" data-srcset="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/boxes-1.png 800w, https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/boxes-1-300x169.png 300w, https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/02/boxes-1-768x432.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" />&lt;/figure>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And while neither the gender or sexuality binary is without plenty of debate (from middle-of-the-road people to outright anti-social justice people), there’s a feeling of consensus amongst social justice people: It’ll be better for everyone if we move beyond these binary ways of thinking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The truth that we’re pushing for here is the recognition that gender, sexuality, and other aspects of our personhood are complicated, nuanced, and more shades-of-gray (ahem) than black/white.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We argue that it’s important for everyone to recognize that truth because it results in the recognition, or visibility, of people made invisible by the previous discourse. We’re able to see people where they stand, for who they are, and allow them to show up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A binary simply doesn’t create enough room for most of us to fit. People are more complicated than that. More diverse.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we can’t recognize people, we can’t hear their voice. Can’t be made to care about their collective or individual suffering. Won’t be bothered to do anything about it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two binaries “smashed.” Destroyed. Demolished. Etc. other unnecessarily violent and hyperbolic descriptors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Great!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But (uh oh) there’s a hitch.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-binaries-we8217ve-come-to-love">The Binaries We’ve Come to Love&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In all of our campaigning against binary thinking — our arguments for recognizing the complexity and nuance and gradations of experience that are intrinsic to the human experience — we seem to have lost the plot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To accomplish our goal of convincing people that binaries are bad, we’ve created a bunch of new binaries. (At least, a lot of us who are &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/social-justice-fandom-aka-creating-new-barriers-name-dismantling-others/">parts of the fandom of social justice&lt;/a> have)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Similar to the &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-social-justice-power-inverse/">social justice power inverse&lt;/a>, we haven’t moved beyond the harmful mechanism — in this case, binary thinking, or forcing people to reduce nuance and complexity into simple dualities — we’ve just swapped out the binaries and options you can choose from.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’re maintaining and upholding the value of thinking in binary ways, as long as you confine yourself within the &lt;em>correct&lt;/em> binaries.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Those binaries are bad. But I have some new ones that aren’t. Trust me.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, here’s a binary that gets reinforced constantly in conversations about gender, sexuality, and social justice:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Privileged&lt;/span>      &lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Oppressed&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of people (almost non-hypothetically everyone) can’t check just one of those boxes. Most of us are both of those, depending on which aspect of us you’re talking about, or what situation we’re in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But when people bring &lt;em>that&lt;/em> up, what I just said — in workshops, online, or in other social justice education spaces — they’re met with another binary to either self-select into, or be shoved into:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Unquestioningly Supportive&lt;/span>      &lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Oppressive&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Have fun picking which of those boxes to check. It’s like when your parents gave you the “option” of putting on your shoes before the count of 3.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve seen this happen more times than I can recount, and I’m guessing you have too. Someone raises their hand, offers a counterpoint or constructive criticism, and suddenly the mood of the space changes from education to trial. Witnessing this over and over is one of the things that led me to start writing about &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tag/social-justice-dogma/">social justice dogma&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you question a social justice narrative, or complicate things, or add nuance, you risk being lumped into the “oppressive” box, being seen as part of the problem. Oh, that’s another binary we love:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Part of the Solution&lt;/span>      &lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Part of the Problem&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have so many new binaries that we’ve created, that we actively sort people into. New either/or ways of thinking, that tell us who is good, who we’re allowed to like, what ideas we should support, and how we’re allowed to show our support, and more. Each of those with a dichotomous opposite.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At the risk of boring you with example overload, I’ll just quickly blurt out a few more before I wrap this thing up.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Your &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/12/reasons-people-believe-feminism-hates-men/">feminism&lt;/a> is either…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Intersectional&lt;/span>      &lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Racist/Supremacist/Bigoted&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You’re either an…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Ally Who Wants Cookies&lt;/span>      &lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Good Ally (Who Doesn’t)&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Based on your &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/">identities&lt;/a>, choosing to speak is either…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Sharing Your Truth&lt;/span>      &lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Taking Up Space&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Based on community verdict, you’re either…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Okay (for now)&lt;/span>      &lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Canceled&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And ultimately, you’re either…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Woke&lt;/span>      &lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Problematic&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could go on (and on, and on) with that list. You can probably think of a few binaries I haven’t listed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I could also elaborate on each of them, and really dig into the unhelpfulness of &lt;em>that&lt;/em> binary way of thinking (e.g., arguing that everyone — including your favs, your friends, and you — is problematic).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead, I’m going to end this more broadly, focusing on binary thinking itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="so-what">So what?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At the risk of this article coming across as &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/hypocrisy-theatre/">hypocrisy theatre&lt;/a>, let me get to my point.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s a simple one, I think. And something that on its face feels obvious, but will nonetheless feel controversial to many:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>We can’t undo the harms of one oversimplified binary by enacting another oversimplified binary.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Liberating everyone from the confines of one of two boxes, only to force them into one of two &lt;em>other&lt;/em> boxes is not &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/">a path toward equity, or a truly just society&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I’m not saying that we “can’t” do this because we have a moral imperative, or should take “the high road.” It’s not about this being hypocritical. It’s not that at all. I’m saying can’t do it because it’s not working. It won’t work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Combatting dichotomous, rigid, reductive thinking with dichotomous, rigid, reductive thinking is not a winning strategy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It works when you’re preaching to the converted, sure. You can wield it as a weapon of fear to keep your people from stepping out of line. “Keep believing this, in these specific ways, or we’ll cast you out.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And weapon isn’t an overstatement. The threat of rejection, isolation, and alienation is the threat of &lt;a href="http://science.sciencemag.org/content/302/5643/290">physical pain&lt;/a>. Kicking someone out of your community is &lt;a href="https://fs.blog/2013/11/why-our-brains-are-wired-to-connect/">tantamount to breaking their leg&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We’re not just in the business of preaching to the converted. We’re about changing, and opening, minds. Creating health where before there was suffering.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we want people to recognize the diversity inherent in humanity — that shows up as spectrums of genders and sexualities — and the limitations of reducing all of that to two boxes into which we lump everyone, we have to recognize the diversity inherent in humanity. And stop lumping everyone into one of two boxes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We need to embrace nuance. Tap into &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/magical-power-social-justice-educators/">the magical power of “some.”&lt;/a> Recognize the truth that almost none of this is absolute, either/or. The same goes for us: we live in the gray. Hiding from that isn’t helping anyone.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The tool of binary thinking isn’t capable of fixing the problem of binary thinking.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or, to borrow the words of someone more brilliant than me:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>“The master’s tools will never dismantle the master’s house. They may allow us temporarily to beat him at his own game, but they will never enable us to bring about genuine change.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Are you going to disagree with Audre Lorde? Watch out, or you might land yourself in a box you don’t want to be in:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Disagreeing with Audre Lorde&lt;/span>     &lt;span style="display:inline-block">&lt;input type="checkbox" /> Not 100% Regretting A Foolish Mistake&lt;/span>&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Social Justice Power Inverse</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-social-justice-power-inverse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 18:19:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-social-justice-power-inverse/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/03/social-justice-power-inverse.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>A lot of social justice conversations focus on power. Who has power in society and who doesn’t?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We highlight how systems inequitably distribute power to some while withholding it from others — based on &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/">who we are&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We refer to people who are granted disproportionate power as “privileged,” “majoritized,” “centered,” etc. And those from whom power is withheld as “oppressed,” “minoritized,” “marginalized,” etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, nobody is only one of those two. We’re both, depending on which situation we’re in, and what dimensions of ourselves are brought to the forefront.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our goal in talking about this is dismantling inequitable power structures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/">The needle on our compass points toward equity.&lt;/a> Removing barriers, promoting access, and shrinking the gap between the “haves” and “have nots” — or, in &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-two-worlds-dilemma/">a perfect world&lt;/a>, making that dichotomy irrelevant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the things we don’t talk about is how power structures manifest in social justice spaces, or the micro-society that is the community of &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/">social justice people&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here, we preserve the idea of the power structure, but swap out who sits where.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We center people who are generally marginalized, privilege people who are otherwise oppressed, majoritize the previously minoritized. The more your voice is taken away in society based on intersecting aspects of who are, the more your voice holds weight here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We do it, in part, as a protection against the harms of society, where dominant group members often silence others, misinform, and act selfishly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The rationale here makes sense: it feels like righting a wrong. And it results in a lot of positive outcomes (e.g., agency, representation, solidarity).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But like all disproportionate power relationships, it’s also susceptible to abuse. We empower some to silence others, misinform, and act selfishly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It’s also, ultimately, inequitable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reversing who holds disproportionate power doesn’t reverse inequity. It maintains it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Two Worlds Dilemma</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-two-worlds-dilemma/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 18:37:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-two-worlds-dilemma/</guid><dc:creator>Sam Killermann</dc:creator><media:content type="image/jpeg" medium="image" width="1200" height="735" url="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/10/two-worlds-dilemma.jpg"/><description>&lt;p>Every justice movement — from &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/gender-2/">gender&lt;/a>, to &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/sexuality">sexuality&lt;/a>, to &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/">every other dimension&lt;/a> of who we are and how the world sees us — has to answer two big questions: What’s wrong with the world now? And what future world do you want to create?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m the fly on the wall for thousands of conversations about &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/socialjustice/">social justice&lt;/a>. And a lot of what I witness online and in-person (in workshops and conferences and retreats) goes off the rails because of &lt;strong>The Two Worlds Dilemma&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, there’s the world we live in currently. The one we grew up in, the one we see as flawed. Let’s call this &lt;strong>Now World&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Second, there’s the world we’re working toward. The goal of our activism and change. &lt;a href="https://charleseisenstein.org/books/the-more-beautiful-world-our-hearts-know-is-possible/">The more beautiful world our hearts know is possible&lt;/a>. &lt;strong>Future World&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The dilemma plays out in a few different ways, but they all feel roughly the same:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Someone doesn’t agree with how your characterize Now World, so they argue against your Future World (and vice versa)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Someone thinks you’re talking about Future World when really you’re just describing Now World (and vice versa)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>These arguments happen within the social justice movement as much as they do between &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/social-justice-fandom-aka-creating-new-barriers-name-dismantling-others/">SJ Fandom&lt;/a> and Anti-SJ people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And of course! Because there are tons of little things we can latch on to, and use to undermine the entire conversation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>As SJ people, we can do a lot more to clarify:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>What world we’re talking about (Now, Future, or some other)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How our aspirational Future differs from Now&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The specific changes (new systems, norms, laws, etc.) we think will get us from Now to Future.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>We can’t just point out what’s bad (about our Now, or other people’s proposed Future).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If we want to walk our talk, we have to &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/">point people toward&lt;/a> good.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>