<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sexuality on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/categories/sexuality/</link><description>Recent content in Sexuality on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:21:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/categories/sexuality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Defining LGBTQ+</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/books/defining-lgbtq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:21:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/books/defining-lgbtq/</guid><description>Defining LBGTQ+ is a helpful guide for getting a grasp on the terminology of gender and sexuality. It includes definitions for lots of terms, explainers for how to use them, and more!
Now, before you get too excited, it’s not really a book-book.</description></item><item><title>New E-Book: Defining LGBTQ+</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/02/defining-lgbtq-guide-to-gender-sexuality-terminology/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:21:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/02/defining-lgbtq-guide-to-gender-sexuality-terminology/</guid><description>Hi friends! I’m going to keep this short. I just put together an E-Book called “Defining LGBTQ+.” It’s a guide to gender and sexuality terminology, based on my article Comprehensive List of LGBTQ+ Vocabulary Definitions, which was based on the glossary from my first book (A Guide to Gender), that grew into a collaboration with Meg Bolger (The Safe Zone Project) and thousands of you.</description></item><item><title>Self-Guided Foundational Safe Zone Training</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/self-guided-foundational-safe-zone-training/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/self-guided-foundational-safe-zone-training/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Learn about your first impressions of LGBTQ+ people, core vocabulary, gender &amp;amp; sexuality theory, privilege &amp;amp; coming out, and get your questions answered.&amp;rdquo;
That's from the course description, and does a good job of summing this up. I co-created this course with Meg Bolger based on our years of experience facilitating countless in-person Safe Zone workshops.</description></item><item><title>One Huge Prickly Reason Why Anti-LGBTQ Folks Don’t Change Their Views</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/01/ignored-reason-people-dont-affirm-lgbtq-people-make-harder/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 20:08:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/01/ignored-reason-people-dont-affirm-lgbtq-people-make-harder/</guid><description>I need you to take a leap with me.
Leap into the shoes of someone who has walked through their life knowing that being gay, being bi, lesbian, or pan, or that being non-binary, gender non-conforming, or trans — that being different, different from straight, different from cisgender — is wrong.</description></item><item><title>What makes a relationship healthy? Unhealthy? These four things, to start.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2016/11/rest-columns-shadows-healthy-relationship-model/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 23:01:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2016/11/rest-columns-shadows-healthy-relationship-model/</guid><description>It’s hard to define what a healthy relationship looks like because we all navigate relationships differently. Relationships are generally seen through the lenses of our gender as well as our sexuality, but there are many other aspects of our identity that are going to inform what we see as good or bad, desirable or detestable, healthy or unhealthy.</description></item><item><title>The Many Elements of Comprehensive Sexuality: Meet the Sexualitree</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2016/05/sexualitree-model-of-comprehensive-sexuality/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 21:52:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2016/05/sexualitree-model-of-comprehensive-sexuality/</guid><description>Sexuality is a touchy subject. For example, just that opening joke might have been enough to turn someone off (I could go all day. But I won’t.). As easy as it is to make awkward puns, or be uncomfortable in general talking about sexuality, it’s an important subject that affects all of us on different levels of our lives.</description></item><item><title>When Someone Comes Out To You: DO &amp; DON’T</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2016/04/when-someone-comes-out-to-you-do-dont/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 20:32:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2016/04/when-someone-comes-out-to-you-do-dont/</guid><description>In one of the first safe zone trainings I remember participating in, there was a loaded question about coming out that was followed by an excellent answer from the facilitator. The question was something like “Why don’t some people come out of the closet?</description></item><item><title>Your Ally is Someone Who… (A Few Ways to Be #BetterAllies)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/10/better-ally-week/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 19:29:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/10/better-ally-week/</guid><description>To celebrate GLSEN‘s Ally Week, It Gets Better and I put our heads together to create a series of images. These comics exemplify what _they _described as the top traits of better allies, and in my best ally fashion I used my doodling powers to elevate that message.</description></item><item><title>Dear White, Straight, Cisgender, Man People: You Are Privileged</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/05/dear-white-straight-cisgender-men-privilege/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 17:17:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/05/dear-white-straight-cisgender-men-privilege/</guid><description>I’ve written about privilege here, and I’ve written my own privilege lists, inspired by Peggy McIntosh (blame her!), which have garnered a lot of hullabaloo on my site. Now, there seems to be a groundswell of backlash, where privileged people (like this super privileged Princeton student) are “denouncing their privilege” and “finally standing up for straight white guys” (HAHAHA).</description></item><item><title>15+ Fantastic Resources for Talking about “Homosexuality” (i.e., LGBTQ people) and The Bible</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/10/resources-lgbtq-homosexual-bible-christianity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 21:47:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/10/resources-lgbtq-homosexual-bible-christianity/</guid><description>Only a tiny, tiny part of the bible can even be argued to reference “homosexuality” (and that argument, in a few of the verses in particular, is worth looking into), yet it seems like whenever we hear about the Bible in the news it’s being slammed against LGBTQ equality.</description></item><item><title>Comprehensive* List of LGBTQ+ Vocabulary Definitions</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/01/a-comprehensive-list-of-lgbtq-term-definitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 23:46:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/01/a-comprehensive-list-of-lgbtq-term-definitions/</guid><description>Hi! This post is now available as part of an E-Book called &amp;#8220;Defining LGBTQ+&amp;#8221;. It includes the most recently updated definitions for all the terms below, the rules, and a bunch of other stuff. You can download it as a .</description></item><item><title>How to explain that bisexuality (or pansexuality) is real</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/how-to-explain-to-someone-bisexuality-or-pansexuality-is-real/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 20:24:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/how-to-explain-to-someone-bisexuality-or-pansexuality-is-real/</guid><description>&lt;address>
This is a second-part response to &lt;a title="Top Ten Tips on how to Thicken your Skin" href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/tips-on-thickening-skin-in-social-justice-work/" target="_blank">an email I received&lt;/a> from a high school senior (it&amp;#8217;d probably help contextualize if you read her email first).  
&lt;/address>
&lt;p>Bisexuality is a thing. It’s not just “a stop between gay and straight.” But how do you explain that to someone who just. simply. won’t. believe. you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am going to focus on the struggle many bisexual and pansexual folks have convincing their straight (or gay/lesbian) peers that bisexuality is an identity, not just a stopping point between two others.  While I’m focusing this article on advice for bi- and pansexual folks, some of it applies to all sexuality discussions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have three main approaches you can take below, but I’d love to hear suggestions for more ways to breach this subject in the comments below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top Ten Tips on how to Thicken your Skin</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/tips-on-thickening-skin-in-social-justice-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 21:23:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/tips-on-thickening-skin-in-social-justice-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>I received the following email from a high school senior (we’ll call her Angie), replied to her, she appreciated the response and told me she’d be cool with me sharing it with you folks in case any one else might be able to find it useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Angie’s Email:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I need tips on how to thicken my skin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here’s my issue. I’m taking Gender/Sexuality Diversity in Literature (basically Gender Studies), and there are kids in my class who don’t believe in bisexuality, let alone *my* sexuality (aka. pansexuality). I’m an easy crier and I just know that when this rather basic problem surfaces–because I’ve only ever heard these kids mutter their opinions under their breath–I won’t make it through the conversation. So, tips?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve thought about coming out to the class (I’m out to my friends, family, most teachers, and Facebook, but most people don’t know) but haven’t. I want people to step on eggshells because they’re being inclusive, not because I’m in the room and they don’t want to offend me personally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Any thoughts? Totally fine if not. A snarky one-liner would be just as welcome, because you’re hilarious and shit.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Costs of Marriage Inequality (an infographic)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/the-costs-of-marriage-inequality-an-infographic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 20:24:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/the-costs-of-marriage-inequality-an-infographic/</guid><description>This isn’t an IPM Edugraphic, but I felt compelled to get the message out. Check it out, be shocked, then head to takepart.com and do something about it. Annnnd go.</description></item><item><title>4 Reasons You Should Stop Saying “Non-Straight”</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/reasons-you-should-stop-saying-non-straight-and-say-queer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 18:13:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/reasons-you-should-stop-saying-non-straight-and-say-queer/</guid><description>With all the talk of marriage equality, gay comic book weddings, and even gayer flowcharts flowing around the web, people are getting ever more sensitive about using inclusive language when they can.
That’s great! But more often than ever I am hearing folks use the term “non-straight” to refer to people who are lesbian, gay, bi-, pan- or even trans*.</description></item><item><title>Flowchart: I Want To Say Gay (When it’s Okay)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/even-better-flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-gay/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 19:34:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/even-better-flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-gay/</guid><description>When I published my original flowchart, I said it was for the more analytical folks who are wondering if “gay” is the right word choice for them. Well, this one is for the most analytical folks, and also folks who enjoy data presented in cute and adorable ways.</description></item><item><title>Flowchart: when it’s okay to say “that’s so gay”</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-thats-so-gay-prin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 22:10:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-thats-so-gay-prin/</guid><description>For the more analytical folks, we created a handy flowchart to help make the decision “Is ‘gay’ the right word for me?”
As you can tell, in most cases, the answer is no. Print, post, and share freely.</description></item><item><title>When to use the word “gay”</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/when-to-use-the-word-gay-print/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 00:14:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/when-to-use-the-word-gay-print/</guid><description>When is it &amp;ldquo;okay&amp;rdquo; to say gay? Why is this even a question we need to be asking? Well, because it seems that people have some misconceptions, and this flowchart makes it simple.
This graphic was originally created to support this article, but then a comment was made saying this should be hung on every dorm wall in America.</description></item><item><title>Toyota airs a Gay-Friendly Super Bowl Commercial</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/toyota-airs-a-gay-friendly-super-bowl-commercial/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2012 17:29:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/toyota-airs-a-gay-friendly-super-bowl-commercial/</guid><description>Hello, Toyota.
@EricTeske pointed out the Super Bowl ad below, with the following comment:
The add features a decidedly gay-friendly moment, and we’re not talking about the Lionel Richie (he’s straight, folks). About 8 seconds in a man is presented with options for a super-hot near-naked ladies couch, or a super-hot near-naked dudes couch.</description></item><item><title>Sexual Orientation for the Genderqueer Person</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/sexual-orientation-for-the-genderqueer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2012 21:01:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/sexual-orientation-for-the-genderqueer/</guid><description>&lt;p>We understand that sexual orientation and gender are separate concepts.  This is something that is relatively easily understood within the contexts of cisgender identities.  But how does sexual orientation “work” for genderqueer or trans-identified peeps?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s talk about it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why I’m Boycotting Marriage</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/why-im-boycotting-marriage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 01:52:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/why-im-boycotting-marriage/</guid><description>If five days ago you told me I would consider Sarah Silverman a role model, even in just one aspect, I would have laughed milk through my nose. And I don’t even drink milk.
Update June 26, 2015: Hey. sK here.</description></item><item><title>“Gay Marriage Equals” Poster</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/gay-marriage-equals-poster-print/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2012 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/gay-marriage-equals-poster-print/</guid><description>This poster is for Rick Santorum, et al. Same-sex marriages are happening, gays are serving openly in the military, and the world isn’t falling apart (well, maybe it is, but it was a preexisting condition).
Yet anti-human-rights activists like Santorum and the rest of the Slippery Slopers can’t help but remind us that gay marriage is just the beginning.</description></item><item><title>2011: A year of progress for LGBT equality [VIDEO]</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/2011-a-year-of-progress-for-lgbt-equality/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2012 01:12:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/2011-a-year-of-progress-for-lgbt-equality/</guid><description>Check out this great YouTube clip of MSNBC’s Thomas Roberts highlighting a “banner year” for LGBT rights and equality. Thanks to ThinkProgress for uploading and sharing! Any notable events or advancements they missed? Share them in the comments below!
🔌 Enable Javascript to Watch Video</description></item><item><title>30+ Examples of Heterosexual (Straight) Privileges</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/29-examples-of-heterosexual-privilege/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 23:03:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/29-examples-of-heterosexual-privilege/</guid><description>Following is a list of examples of heterosexual privilege. If you are straight, these are unearned benefits you receive as a result of the sexuality you were born with.
If you are straight (or in some cases, perceived to be), you can live without ever having to think twice, face, confront, engage, or cope with anything listed below.</description></item><item><title>Why same-sex marriage is constitutional, and marrying a toaster is not.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/why-same-sex-marriage-is-constitutional-and-marrying-a-toaster-is-not/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 21:07:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/why-same-sex-marriage-is-constitutional-and-marrying-a-toaster-is-not/</guid><description>A graphic representation of an issue that should be simpler than it is, but it always leading to absurd slippery-slope arguments.
Below is a wonderful graphic that was shared with me that does a fantastic job of clearing the whole thing up.</description></item><item><title>A visual aid: when “gay” is okay</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/a-visual-aid-when-gay-okay-to-sa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 21:51:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/a-visual-aid-when-gay-okay-to-sa/</guid><description>Created a printer-friendly version of the first graphic (and a high-resolution version). Check it, share it, print it, love it. Also, check out the new-and-improved flowchart. For those of you still struggling with the idea of when it is and isn’t ideal to use the word “gay”, even after reading my article outlining the whole idea, I decided to create a few visual aids.</description></item><item><title>Why I say “partner” instead of boyfriend or girlfriend</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/why-i-sa-the-term-partner-instead-of-boyfriendgirlfriend-and-when/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 20:11:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/why-i-sa-the-term-partner-instead-of-boyfriendgirlfriend-and-when/</guid><description>Using the term “partner” to replace boyfriend or girlfriend is widely suggested as a means to speak more inclusively, allowing gay, lesbian, or bisexual people feel more comfortable. When I use this term to refer to my partner around straight people, I’m often asked, “why did you say your partner instead of your girlfriend?</description></item><item><title>If you call someone gay, he better be a guy who likes guys.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/if-you-call-someone-gay-he-better-be-a-guy-who-likes-guys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 21:32:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/if-you-call-someone-gay-he-better-be-a-guy-who-likes-guys/</guid><description>View this article in handy printable graphic form if you don&amp;#8217;t feel up to reading 400 words. Gay isn’t a bad word, assuming you’re using it to describe a man who is attracted (physically, spiritually, and emotionally) to other men, (depending on label preference) a woman who is attracted to women, or anyone else who self-identifies as gay.</description></item><item><title>What happens when a same sex couple raises a child?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/what-happens-when-a-same-sex-couple-raises-a-child/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2011 23:28:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/what-happens-when-a-same-sex-couple-raises-a-child/</guid><description>Check out this video of this courageous young man speaking out about his experience being raised by two moms. I dare you not to shed a tear.
🔌 Enable Javascript to Watch Video</description></item></channel></rss>