<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Social Justice Dogma on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/social-justice-dogma/</link><description>Recent content in Social Justice Dogma on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 17:34:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/social-justice-dogma/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Maybe we should stop using “White supremacist” and “bad” interchangeably?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/07/maybe-we-should-stop-using-white-supremacist-and-bad-interchangeably/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 17:34:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/07/maybe-we-should-stop-using-white-supremacist-and-bad-interchangeably/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, I’ve been noticing this weird trend. It’s become prevalent within the social justice movement, and I haven’t seen anyone else flag it. I brought it up in the context of our &lt;a href="https://www.sjmd.space">Social Justice, Minus Dogma Course + Community&lt;/a>, and it turns out other people are noticing it too. So let’s flag it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The short version is this:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A lot of people are using domination/oppression language (e.g., “white supremacist”, “patriarchal”) as synonyms for “bad” and marginalization/anti-oppression language (e.g., “indigenous,” “decolonized,” “feminist”) as synonyms for “good” — devoid of any meaningful connection to the actual structure, system, or culture they’re mentioning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My guess is that it’s a combination of our &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/04/isms-not-ists/">over focusing on “-ists” instead of “-isms”&lt;/a> plus the &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-social-justice-power-inverse/">“social justice power inverse,”&lt;/a> but I’ll leave the detective work up to you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Why highlight this at all? In short, because actual, sincere, real-life White supremacy is on the rise, and we need to be able to call it when we see it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Calling things “White supremacist” that aren’t creates a lot of unhelpful noise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wrote this article a few days before we got a blazingly clear example of White supremacy in action, when &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/1150381394234941448">U.S. President Donald Trump went on a “go back to your country” rant&lt;/a> against several members of congress, all of whom are women of color.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Being careful to use the phrase “White supremacy” correctly would allow a criticism of Trump’s rant, and other White supremacist actions, to be held as distinct from general criticisms of Trump.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Both are totally valid, by the way! However, we need to know which basket we’re putting our eggs into.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We need to be able to separate “I don’t like what you’re saying” from “What you’re saying is advancing White supremacy and ethnic cleansing.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And right now we’re not doing a good job of that, at all.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll explain what I’m talking about in more detail, then talk about a few of the reasons &lt;em>I&lt;/em> think this is (deeply) unhelpful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’d be curious to hear what you think, if you’re also noticing this. We’ll make space for that, too.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="8220white-supremacist8221-doesn8217t-mean-a-8220white-person-doing-something-bad8221">“White Supremacist” doesn’t mean a “White person doing something bad”&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Let me first say that, overall, it’s great that more people are becoming comfy using phrases like “white supremacist.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The same goes for words like “patriarchal,” “colonial,” “heterosexist,” etc. They’re useful words that can be used to pinpoint exactly what we’re talking about, concerned about in society, and wanting to change.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(If we could just add “capitalist” to our comfort zone, &lt;a href="https://www.mediaed.org/transcripts/Bell-Hooks-Transcript.pdf">we might even make bell hooks proud&lt;/a>.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The issue I’m flagging here is&lt;/strong> &lt;em>&lt;strong>not&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> &lt;strong>the use of the phrase “white supremacist”&lt;/strong> (or any of these other words I’m lumping together as domination/oppression language).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>The issue is people using these words like duct tape, sticking them to every problem they notice.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here’s what it looks like in general:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Social Justice Minus Dogma Online Course</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/social-justice-minus-dogma-course/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/social-justice-minus-dogma-course/</guid><description>Over the course of 6 weeks of self-guided learning (or however long you choose), explore the social justice dogma, identify its cornerstones and pitfalls, and plot a path forward toward true living social justice.
This course is an extension of all the writing I've done here about &amp;ldquo;social justice dogma.</description></item><item><title>How much injustice can we justify on the path toward social justice?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/05/justifying-injustice-for-social-justice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:36:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/05/justifying-injustice-for-social-justice/</guid><description>&lt;p>Close your eyes and imagine the world you would describe as living social justice. Equitable. Utopian, even. Whatever comes to mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Give it a shot. I’ll wait a moment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What does it feel like to occupy that [future world][1] where all of our work as [social justice people][2] came to fruition?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How does it differ from our world today?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>How radical of a difference you notice will be determined by the world you have in your mind. But surely the ways we spend our time, the social problems we grapple with, and even the ways we organize societies aren’t the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What do “jobs” look like? Do they even still exist? What about politics? What will there be more of? What will there be less of?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There’s likely a long list of [actions, attitudes, and beliefs][3] that wouldn’t make sense in that world, but seem perfectly sensical in our world right now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What comes to mind?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Focus on the gap, the distance between what would be normal in a socially-just world, compared to what is normal now in our oppressive and unjust world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay, now here comes the really tough part:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Replacing One Binary with Another</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/binary-thinking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2019 16:43:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/binary-thinking/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve always believed that one of our superpowers as gender/sexuality activists, and &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/">social justice people&lt;/a> more broadly, is our ability to hold space for nuance. In the past few years, that belief has been crumbling. In part because of how much I’m seeing us replace one way of binary thinking for another.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a long time, we’ve known that sexuality isn’t a binary thing. It’s not gay/straight, either/or. It’s often both/and, neither, or another option altogether. &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kinsey_scale">The Kinsey Scale&lt;/a> often comes to mind here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>More recently, we’ve recognized the same thing about gender. We’ve &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NRcPXtqdKjE">addressed the complexities of gender&lt;/a>, viewing it on a spectrum, &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/02/gender-scales-or-spectrums/">or, better, on scales&lt;/a>. And &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/breaking-through-the-binary-gender-explained-using-continuums/">broken through the binary&lt;/a> of woman/man. Just like sexuality, it’s not an either/or, but more of a both/and, neither, or another option altogether.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, it’s not entirely clear to me that everyone writing about binaries (e.g., the gender binary) is saying the same thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So allow me to be clear what I mean (and have always meant) by binary: two options. Two ways to be. Two categories. And that’s it. Only two.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A binary can be succinctly summed up by this (no words needed):&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Social Justice Power Inverse</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-social-justice-power-inverse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 18:19:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-social-justice-power-inverse/</guid><description>&lt;p>A lot of social justice conversations focus on power. Who has power in society and who doesn’t?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We highlight how systems inequitably distribute power to some while withholding it from others — based on &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/">who we are&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We refer to people who are granted disproportionate power as “privileged,” “majoritized,” “centered,” etc. And those from whom power is withheld as “oppressed,” “minoritized,” “marginalized,” etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, nobody is only one of those two. We’re both, depending on which situation we’re in, and what dimensions of ourselves are brought to the forefront.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our goal in talking about this is dismantling inequitable power structures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/">The needle on our compass points toward equity.&lt;/a> Removing barriers, promoting access, and shrinking the gap between the “haves” and “have nots” — or, in &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-two-worlds-dilemma/">a perfect world&lt;/a>, making that dichotomy irrelevant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the things we don’t talk about is how power structures manifest in social justice spaces, or the micro-society that is the community of &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/">social justice people&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here, we preserve the idea of the power structure, but swap out who sits where.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Incoming: “Social Justice, Minus Dogma” Course + Community</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/social-justice-dogma-course-community/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 19:49:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/social-justice-dogma-course-community/</guid><description>&lt;p>Over 1,000 of you said you’d want to participate in an &lt;a href="https://mailchi.mp/970acc41bb9c/social-justice-minus-dogma">online course and community focusing on Social Justice, Minus Dogma&lt;/a>. So I’m going to hold up my end of the bargain and make the thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;address>
&lt;strong>Update! The Course + Community is officially launched. &lt;/strong>Read all about it at &lt;a href="https://course.sjmd.space">www.sjmd.space&lt;/a>, and &lt;a href="https://gum.co/sjmdcourse?wanted=true">sign up today&lt;/a> and you can start learning and participating in the community immediately.
&lt;/address>
&lt;p>First, I want to say how blown away I am that so many people are up for this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a few weeks, I showed a question at the top of the site to some readers asking if you’d want to participate in a course about “social justice, minus dogma.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’m wasn’t sure what to expect, but I was bracing for &lt;em>bad&lt;/em>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Elephant in Every Socially-Just Room</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/12/the-elephant-in-every-socially-just-room/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 20:45:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/12/the-elephant-in-every-socially-just-room/</guid><description>&lt;p>For the past year, I’ve been in conversation with folks about what I’ve been calling the “Social Justice Dogma.” I’ve &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/12/introduction-social-justice-dogma/">written&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/12/why-i-finally-broke-silence-social-justice-dogma/">about&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tag/social-justice-dogma">it&lt;/a> &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/06/unhelpful-tenets-social-justice-dogma/">here&lt;/a> (&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tag/social-justice-dogma">read all&lt;/a>), &lt;a href="https://hereticpodcast.com/updates/want-to-be-a-guest-want-to-nominate-one-yes-please-heres-how/">tried to interview people&lt;/a> about it for a &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/videos-podcasts/">podcast&lt;/a>, and I’ve been having lots and lots of phone calls with social justice educators.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In &lt;em>literally&lt;/em> every case, when I’d start a conversation about Social Justice Dogma (SJD), the person I was talking with recognized the phenomenon, without me needing to explain what I meant —  even if they’d never heard the phrase “social justice dogma.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They’d reply with something like, “Oh, I know what you’re talking about,” or “Oh yeah, that’s a big thing in my circle.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then we’d get into some particular tenet that they were struggling with. Or talk through a recent current event, using the dogma as the lens.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the conversations generally ended the same, with them saying something like “I’m happy you’re talking about this” or “This conversation is needed” or “I’m looking forward to seeing more on this.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But then the conversation ended.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Yes, gender is a social construction. No, that doesn’t mean it’s not real.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/09/yes-gender-is-a-social-construction-no-that-doesnt-mean-its-not-real/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 21:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/09/yes-gender-is-a-social-construction-no-that-doesnt-mean-its-not-real/</guid><description>&lt;p>Gender is a social construction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even if you take the most extreme &lt;a href="https://www.encyclopedia.com/science-and-technology/biology-and-genetics/biology-general/biological-determinism">biological determinist&lt;/a> stance (which a lot of the “gender isn’t a social construction” crowd take), you cannot deny the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>What it means to be a “woman” or “man” changes over time (often within the timeframe of a generation — ask your grandparents if you don’t believe me).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Further, right now, the traits associated with each of those roles are different in different parts of the world (watch a sitcom from another country if you don’t believe me).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If our understanding of gender changes faster than our biology could possibly evolve, and currently exists in many forms around the world reflecting cultural differences, it’s socially constructed. End of argument. That’s what those two words, combined, &lt;em>mean.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>And gender is real.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just because something’s a social construction doesn’t mean it’s not real (despite many fellow “social construction” folks saying so).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3 Tenets of Social Justice Dogma that are Getting in Our Way</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/06/unhelpful-tenets-social-justice-dogma/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 17:46:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/06/unhelpful-tenets-social-justice-dogma/</guid><description>Now that I’ve been talking openly about Social Justice Dogma (SJD) for a few months, I have some findings I want to share. Below I’ve written about a bunch of tenets of the SJD that are likely unhelpful, counter-productive, or downright obstructive to the goals of social justice.</description></item><item><title>3-Dimensional Social Justice</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/05/3-dimensional-social-justice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 03:33:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/05/3-dimensional-social-justice/</guid><description>Despite a tidal wave of awareness of social justice issues (or maybe because of it), a lot of conversations are getting stuck. Some people are becoming increasingly “anti social justice.” And we seem to be circling loops that go back decades.</description></item><item><title>Social Justice Fandom (AKA Creating New Barriers in the Name of Dismantling Others)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/social-justice-fandom-aka-creating-new-barriers-name-dismantling-others/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 20:31:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/social-justice-fandom-aka-creating-new-barriers-name-dismantling-others/</guid><description>Maybe it was Glee. I don’t know. But at some point, within a small subsection of a small subsection of the population, social justice became cool. And whenever something becomes cool, two things tend to follow.
The first is that some of the people who like the cool thing start to covet it, protect it from outsiders, and claim it as their own — when just moments before those same people were making desperate pleas to others to like the thing they liked.</description></item><item><title>One Huge Prickly Reason Why Anti-LGBTQ Folks Don’t Change Their Views</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/01/ignored-reason-people-dont-affirm-lgbtq-people-make-harder/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 20:08:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/01/ignored-reason-people-dont-affirm-lgbtq-people-make-harder/</guid><description>I need you to take a leap with me.
Leap into the shoes of someone who has walked through their life knowing that being gay, being bi, lesbian, or pan, or that being non-binary, gender non-conforming, or trans — that being different, different from straight, different from cisgender — is wrong.</description></item><item><title>Why I Finally Broke My Silence about the Social Justice Dogma</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/12/why-i-finally-broke-silence-social-justice-dogma/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 02:27:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/12/why-i-finally-broke-silence-social-justice-dogma/</guid><description>Hi friend! If you haven&amp;#8217;t read my first article about the Social Justice Dogma, you probably should. At least if you want this article to make sense. A few days ago I wrote what I described as the scariest thing I’ve ever published to this site.</description></item><item><title>I can’t stop thinking about the “Social Justice Dogma,” or keeping quiet.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/12/introduction-social-justice-dogma/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 21:04:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/12/introduction-social-justice-dogma/</guid><description>Last spring, I got to spend a couple weeks in rural Ontario giving a few dozen (!) talks, assemblies, and shows at schools and organizations around the province. Every time I visit the Ontario countryside, I’m struck by how much it reminds me of my now-home state of Texas, in ways that are equal parts comfy (lots of hospitality) and uncomfy (lots of camouflage and usage of the word “lifestyle”).</description></item></channel></rss>