<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Trans on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/trans/</link><description>Recent content in Trans on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 15:53:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/trans/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Does the Genderbread Person exclude genderfluid people?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/articles/genderbread-person-and-genderfluidity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 15:53:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/articles/genderbread-person-and-genderfluidity/</guid><description>I got an email pointing out to me that my versions of the Genderbread Person exclude genderfluid people. And not just people who use the term &amp;ldquo;genderfluid&amp;rdquo; to identify themselves, but anyone who expresses gender differently at different times. So, do they?</description></item><item><title>Why Think of Gender on Scales Instead of a Spectrum?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/02/gender-scales-or-spectrums/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 01:41:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/02/gender-scales-or-spectrums/</guid><description>&lt;p>When it comes to gender, most people have a similar understanding of it in their minds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It looks something like this:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Genderbread Person version 4</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/10/the-genderbread-person-v4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 06:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/10/the-genderbread-person-v4/</guid><description>A few hundred workshops, three years, and one book edition later, I’m happy to finally publish here my 4th version of the Genderbread Person. Check it out, download it, and share it with your educator friend who is still using v3.</description></item><item><title>Yes, gender is a social construction. No, that doesn’t mean it’s not real.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/09/yes-gender-is-a-social-construction-no-that-doesnt-mean-its-not-real/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 21:26:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/09/yes-gender-is-a-social-construction-no-that-doesnt-mean-its-not-real/</guid><description>&lt;p>Gender is a social construction.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even if you take the most extreme &lt;a href="https://www.encyclopedia.com/science-and-technology/biology-and-genetics/biology-general/biological-determinism">biological determinist&lt;/a> stance (which a lot of the “gender isn’t a social construction” crowd take), you cannot deny the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>What it means to be a “woman” or “man” changes over time (often within the timeframe of a generation — ask your grandparents if you don’t believe me).&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Further, right now, the traits associated with each of those roles are different in different parts of the world (watch a sitcom from another country if you don’t believe me).&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>If our understanding of gender changes faster than our biology could possibly evolve, and currently exists in many forms around the world reflecting cultural differences, it’s socially constructed. End of argument. That’s what those two words, combined, &lt;em>mean.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>And gender is real.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Just because something’s a social construction doesn’t mean it’s not real (despite many fellow “social construction” folks saying so).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>One Huge Prickly Reason Why Anti-LGBTQ Folks Don’t Change Their Views</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/01/ignored-reason-people-dont-affirm-lgbtq-people-make-harder/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 20:08:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/01/ignored-reason-people-dont-affirm-lgbtq-people-make-harder/</guid><description>I need you to take a leap with me.
Leap into the shoes of someone who has walked through their life knowing that being gay, being bi, lesbian, or pan, or that being non-binary, gender non-conforming, or trans — that being different, different from straight, different from cisgender — is wrong.</description></item><item><title>What's the best way to view gender? As a Spectrum? Continuums?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/videos/gender-from-checkboxes-to-continuums/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/videos/gender-from-checkboxes-to-continuums/</guid><description>I was invited to give a Nerd Nite talk and speak about the subject I nerd out about the most: gender. And I got to talk about a lot of the dimensions of my work that I usually don't &amp;ndash; stuff that usually stays behind the scenes.</description></item><item><title>Let’s Talk About Bathrooms</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/03/lets-talk-about-bathrooms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 23:13:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/03/lets-talk-about-bathrooms/</guid><description>This is an excerpted NEW chapter from the 2nd Edition of my book, A Guide to Gender, which came out today (March 15th, 2017). I&amp;#8217;m publishing it here because today my state&amp;#8217;s senate took another step in a harmful direction, approving SB6, our current &amp;#8220;bathroom bill.</description></item><item><title>A Guide to Gender (2nd Edition)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/books/guide-to-gender/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:21:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/books/guide-to-gender/</guid><description>The first edition was featured as #1 best-seller in Gender on Amazon, and is being used by gender studies &amp;amp; sociology professors on 3 continents. Now with a new foreword by the author, brand new chapters, fixed tpyos, and more gender!</description></item><item><title>The Genderbread Person version 3</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2015/03/the-genderbread-person-v3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 02:05:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2015/03/the-genderbread-person-v3/</guid><description>Taking the lessons learned from version 2, and applying them to sexuality in a more meaningful way, here’s my best rendition of the genderbread person yet.
Hey! Friend! I published a version 4 of my Genderbread Person! It&amp;#8217;s at least 33.</description></item><item><title>Guerrilla Activism: Printable Gender Neutral Bathroom Signs Project</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/printable-gender-neutral-bathroom-sign-guerilla-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2014 14:03:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/printable-gender-neutral-bathroom-sign-guerilla-project/</guid><description>This sign has now officially become a thing! Thanks for playing along I wrote this post and made the included graphic yesterday in a moment of what I call using humor for self-preservation. I was frustrated with the gender neutral bathroom sign “debate” and reached my tipping point.</description></item><item><title>Solution for the “Confusing” Gender Neutral Toilet Sign Issue</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/gender-neutral-bathroom-sign/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2014 22:53:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/gender-neutral-bathroom-sign/</guid><description>Update: get involved in this simple guerilla activism project I started based on the reaction to this graphic. DOUBLE UPDATE: this is now a thing! A while ago I had the opportunity to sit in on some meetings where a group was lobbying their state legislators for gender neutral bathrooms.</description></item><item><title>My TED Talk: Understanding the Complexities of Gender</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/my-ted-talk-understanding-the-complexities-of-gender/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/my-ted-talk-understanding-the-complexities-of-gender/</guid><description>I had the honor of being asked to give another TEDx talk, and they let me do it all about gender.
You can watch the video below, and see as I try to condense hundreds of pages of my book into 16 minutes of comprehensible, enjoyable, and sometimes-rhyming words.</description></item><item><title>What does the asterisk in “trans*” stand for?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/what-does-the-asterisk-in-trans-stand-for/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 20:01:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/what-does-the-asterisk-in-trans-stand-for/</guid><description>A few people have asked why I write “trans*” (with the asterisk) instead of just “trans” when referring to trans* folks on my site. Well, I’m happy to answer that!
💌Most Wednesdays
I publish new Social Justice, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Resources.</description></item><item><title>5+ Ways to Make Our World More Trans*-Friendly</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/list-of-ways-to-make-world-trans-friendl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 17:55:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/list-of-ways-to-make-world-trans-friendl/</guid><description>&lt;p>We live in a world that recognizes two options for gender.  If you’re not &lt;em>exactly&lt;/em> “man” or “woman” you’re going to have a hard time finding your place, because right now there isn’t a &lt;em>place&lt;/em> for you.  Let’s change that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is a list of suggestions to make the world a bit less binary and a lot more transgender inclusive.  Read ’em, live ’em, and add to ’em in the comments below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Genderbread Person version 2</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/03/the-genderbread-person-v2-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 00:42:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/03/the-genderbread-person-v2-0/</guid><description>Heads up! I wrote a book all about gender that builds on the &amp;#8220;-ness&amp;#8221; concepts I introduced with this Genderbread Person. If you appreciate this, you&amp;#8217;ll love this book. Hundreds of comments, ditto emails, ditto Facebook messages and Twitter tweeters and in-person holla-atchas and I feel like I’m finally in a place to release this.</description></item><item><title>The Genderbread Person</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/the-genderbread-person/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 20:01:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/the-genderbread-person/</guid><description>Please check out the new-and-improved Genderbread Person v2.0. It&amp;#8217;s a heckuvalot better and just as free to share/print! I&amp;#8217;m leaving this up for now for those who want it, but I&amp;#8217;m no longer endorsing it as the effective model. The Genderbread Person is an infographic that breaks down gender identity, gender expression, biological sex, and sexual orientation into an easy to understand visual.</description></item><item><title>30+ Examples of Cisgender Privileges</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/list-of-cisgender-privileges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 04:01:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/list-of-cisgender-privileges/</guid><description>Heads up!&amp;nbsp;I wrote a book all about gender that provides tools for standing up against gender-based oppression (like the things below) and working toward a socially justice society. If you appreciate all that jazz,&amp;nbsp;you’ll love this book. Following is a list of cisgender identity privileges.</description></item><item><title>Breaking through the binary: Gender explained using continuums</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/breaking-through-the-binary-gender-explained-using-continuums/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 03:15:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/breaking-through-the-binary-gender-explained-using-continuums/</guid><description>&lt;address class="focus">
&lt;strong>Update:&lt;/strong> &lt;a title="The Genderbread Person v4" href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/10/the-genderbread-person-v4/">View my newest version of the Genderbread Person, version 4 here.&lt;/a>  It&amp;#8217;s a heckuvalot better and just as free to use however you&amp;#8217;d like! And here is the &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/genderbread-person/">Genderbread Person page&lt;/a> with downloads and all versions.
&lt;/address>
&lt;p>Gender is a tough subject to tackle.  There are a lot of facets to consider, a lot of pressures at play, and we have all been conditioned in such a way that our first instinct is almost unanimously wrong.  But we’re going to tackle it.  No, we’re going to tackle the snot out of it.  Coming to our aid, I would like to present to you: The Genderbread Person!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>