<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Public Thinking on It&#39;s Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/tags/public-thinking/</link><description>Recent content in Public Thinking on It&#39;s Pronounced Metrosexual</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 17:34:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/tags/public-thinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Social Justice Minus Dogma Online Course</title><link>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/courses/social-justice-minus-dogma-course/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/courses/social-justice-minus-dogma-course/</guid><description>Over the course of 6 weeks of self-guided learning (or however long you choose), explore the social justice dogma, identify its cornerstones and pitfalls, and plot a path forward toward true living social justice.
This course is an extension of all the writing I&amp;rsquo;ve done here about &amp;ldquo;social justice dogma.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Social Justice Compass</title><link>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 23:09:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Are you sailing the seas of social injustice, looking for a path toward equity, and in need of a tool that can point you in the right direction? Perhaps you are &lt;a href=&#34;https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2019/01/social-justice-then-and-now/&#34;&gt;rethinking how you &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; social justice now&lt;/a&gt;, today, in 2019 &amp;#8212; with everything happening in the world &amp;#8212; and searching for a new path forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Avast!&lt;/em&gt; A new model for thinking about and doing social justice&amp;#8230; &lt;em&gt;ho&lt;/em&gt;! This is off to a bad start. It turns out that every day can be &lt;a href=&#34;http://talklikeapirate.com/wordpress/&#34;&gt;International Talk like a Pirate Day&lt;/a&gt; if you don&amp;#8217;t care about having friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if you care about social justice, friend, well, look no further!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I&amp;#8217;m happy to share with you a new model for thinking about social justice, for considering your actions, attitudes, and beliefs, and for guiding yourself and your community toward equity: The Social Justice Compass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;#8217;s dive right in.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Genderbread Person version 4</title><link>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2018/10/the-genderbread-person-v4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 06:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2018/10/the-genderbread-person-v4/</guid><description>A few hundred workshops, three years, and one book edition later, I&amp;#8217;m happy to finally publish here my 4th version of the Genderbread Person. Check it out, download it, and share it with your educator friend who is still using v3.</description></item><item><title>3-Dimensional Social Justice</title><link>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2018/05/3-dimensional-social-justice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 03:33:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2018/05/3-dimensional-social-justice/</guid><description>Despite a tidal wave of awareness of social justice issues (or maybe because of it), a lot of conversations are getting stuck. Some people are becoming increasingly &amp;#8220;anti social justice.&amp;#8221; And we seem to be circling loops that go back decades.</description></item><item><title>What makes a relationship healthy? Unhealthy? These four things, to start.</title><link>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2016/11/rest-columns-shadows-healthy-relationship-model/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 23:01:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2016/11/rest-columns-shadows-healthy-relationship-model/</guid><description>It&amp;#8217;s hard to define what a healthy relationship looks like because we all navigate relationships differently. Relationships are generally seen through the lenses of our gender as well as our sexuality, but there are many other aspects of our identity that are going to inform what we see as good or bad, desirable or detestable, healthy or unhealthy.</description></item><item><title>The Many Elements of Comprehensive Sexuality: Meet the Sexualitree</title><link>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2016/05/sexualitree-model-of-comprehensive-sexuality/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 21:52:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2016/05/sexualitree-model-of-comprehensive-sexuality/</guid><description>Sexuality is a touchy subject. For example, just that opening joke might have been enough to turn someone off (I could go all day. But I won&amp;#8217;t.). As easy as it is to make awkward puns, or be uncomfortable in general talking about sexuality, it&amp;#8217;s an important subject that affects all of us on different levels of our lives.</description></item><item><title>The Genderbread Person version 3</title><link>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2015/03/the-genderbread-person-v3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 02:05:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2015/03/the-genderbread-person-v3/</guid><description>Taking the lessons learned from version 2, and applying them to sexuality in a more meaningful way, here&amp;#8217;s my best rendition of the genderbread person yet.
Hey! Friend! I published a version 4 of my Genderbread Person! It&amp;#8217;s at least 33.</description></item><item><title>You Soup: understanding diversity and the intersections of identity</title><link>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 19:17:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In doing the work I do, I often find myself struggling to help people make sense of the two extremes of identity: on one side we have the idea that people in a group are all the same (stereotypes); while the other side supports this idea that everyone is absolutely unique (snowflakes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find myself saying &amp;#8220;we&amp;#8217;re not the same, but we&amp;#8217;re also not that different,&amp;#8221; to the furrowing of brows, so I wanted to take a moment here to talk about the relationship of individual identity and social group memberships, as well as introduce a new graphic concept.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Genderbread Person version 2</title><link>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2012/03/the-genderbread-person-v2-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 00:42:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2012/03/the-genderbread-person-v2-0/</guid><description>Heads up! I wrote a book all about gender that builds on the &amp;#8220;-ness&amp;#8221; concepts I introduced with this Genderbread Person. If you appreciate this, you&amp;#8217;ll love this book. Hundreds of comments, ditto emails, ditto Facebook messages and Twitter tweeters and in-person holla-atchas and I feel like I&amp;#8217;m finally in a place to release this.</description></item><item><title>The Genderbread Person</title><link>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2012/01/the-genderbread-person/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 20:01:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://itspronouncedmetrosexual.netlify.com/2012/01/the-genderbread-person/</guid><description>Please check out the new-and-improved Genderbread Person v2.0. It&amp;#8217;s a heckuvalot better and just as free to share/print! I&amp;#8217;m leaving this up for now for those who want it, but I&amp;#8217;m no longer endorsing it as the effective model. The Genderbread Person is an infographic that breaks down gender identity, gender expression, biological sex, and sexual orientation into an easy to understand visual.</description></item></channel></rss>