<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>TMI on It&#39;s Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/tmi/</link><description>Recent content in TMI on It&#39;s Pronounced Metrosexual</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 11:49:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/tmi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Brand New Site for a Brand New Decade</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/news/brand-new-site-for-a-brand-new-decade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 11:49:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/news/brand-new-site-for-a-brand-new-decade/</guid><description>I created this site in 2011 not knowing what I was doing, or what to expect. Hundreds of millions of downloads, shares, and resources distributed later, as we&amp;rsquo;re about to embark on a new decade, I figured it was time to recreate this site.</description></item><item><title>The State of this Site (Or “Funding Online Work in 2018, an Infographic”)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/09/the-state-of-this-site-or-funding-online-work-in-2018-an-infographic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 17:25:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/09/the-state-of-this-site-or-funding-online-work-in-2018-an-infographic/</guid><description>I&amp;#8217;ve been running this site for about 7 years now. I&amp;#8217;ve funded this site by performing comedy shows, and via speaking fees and book royalties. At the beginning of this year, in light of increased hosting costs, I started to ask for reader support to fund this site.</description></item><item><title>Announcement: I’m no longer affiliated with a talent agency, or manager</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/02/announcement-im-no-longer-affiliated-talent-agency-manager/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 20:07:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/02/announcement-im-no-longer-affiliated-talent-agency-manager/</guid><description>I rarely make &amp;#8220;announcements&amp;#8221; on this site. And this one, unlike the others I&amp;#8217;ve made, is more melancholy than anything else: As of yesterday, I&amp;#8217;m no longer represented by a manager, or affiliated with a comedy/speaking/talent agency.
Quick and important: If you or your campus/organization/conference had me booked or were in talks of booking me for the near or distant future, there&amp;#8217;s a good chance I don&amp;#8217;t know about it.</description></item><item><title>Why I Finally Broke My Silence about the Social Justice Dogma</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/12/why-i-finally-broke-silence-social-justice-dogma/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 02:27:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/12/why-i-finally-broke-silence-social-justice-dogma/</guid><description>Hi friend! If you haven&amp;#8217;t read my first article about the Social Justice Dogma, you probably should. At least if you want this article to make sense. A few days ago I wrote what I described as the scariest thing I&amp;#8217;ve ever published to this site.</description></item><item><title>I can’t stop thinking about the “Social Justice Dogma,” or keeping quiet.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/12/introduction-social-justice-dogma/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2017 21:04:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/12/introduction-social-justice-dogma/</guid><description>Last spring, I got to spend a couple weeks in rural Ontario giving a few dozen (!) talks, assemblies, and shows at schools and organizations around the province. Every time I visit the Ontario countryside, I&amp;#8217;m struck by how much it reminds me of my now-home state of Texas, in ways that are equal parts comfy (lots of hospitality) and uncomfy (lots of camouflage and usage of the word &amp;#8220;lifestyle&amp;#8221;).</description></item><item><title>What&#39;s the best way to view gender? As a Spectrum? Continuums?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/videos/gender-from-checkboxes-to-continuums/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/videos/gender-from-checkboxes-to-continuums/</guid><description>I was invited to give a Nerd Nite talk and speak about the subject I nerd out about the most: gender. And I got to talk about a lot of the dimensions of my work that I usually don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ndash; stuff that usually stays behind the scenes.</description></item><item><title>Taking Up Space vs. Adding to a Space: Questions to Consider</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/02/taking-up-space-vs-adding-to-a-space-questions-to-consider/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 22:46:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/02/taking-up-space-vs-adding-to-a-space-questions-to-consider/</guid><description>A lot of us want to just &amp;#8220;be people,&amp;#8221; and leave our social identities at the door when we enter a room. In September 2016, I was asked to participate in Katie Couric&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;Gender Revolution&amp;#8221; documentary (by National Geographic). The following questions were what I worked through &amp;#8212; and what I generally work through &amp;#8212; when deciding to say &amp;#8220;yes&amp;#8221; or &amp;#8220;no.</description></item><item><title>I Uncopyrighted My Work One Year Ago: Here’s What I’ve Learned</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/12/uncopyright-reflection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 18:21:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/12/uncopyright-reflection/</guid><description>I gave a keynote recently, and after someone (a sexual health educator) found me at the conference. &amp;#8220;I just wanted to thank you,&amp;#8221; they started.
💌Most Wednesdays
I publish new Social Justice, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Resources.
Get the Email. Remembering the Journey This site started with a message in the [about page][1]: &amp;#8220;Share/Borrow/Steal.</description></item><item><title>How the Gender Neutral Bathroom Sign I Made is Being Manufactured and Donated to Colleges</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/07/how-the-gender-neutral-bathroom-sign-i-made-is-being-manufactured-and-donated-to-colleges/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:28:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/07/how-the-gender-neutral-bathroom-sign-i-made-is-being-manufactured-and-donated-to-colleges/</guid><description>A few months ago I [sarcastically] threw my hat into the Gender Neutral Bathroom Signage ring. I called that article a coping mechanism to help me deal with a current frustration. But thanks to you, the magic of the internet, and the fine folks at My Door Sign, it became a thing.</description></item><item><title>I’m Heading to Cairo — Wanna hang?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/sam-killermann-in-cairo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 19:59:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/sam-killermann-in-cairo/</guid><description>Hey y&amp;#8217;all!
I&amp;#8217;m going to be in Cairo for the month of June 2014. I&amp;#8217;m going there for a bunch of reasons, but primary among those (and why I&amp;#8217;m posting here) is because I&amp;#8217;d love to meet some of you lovelies.</description></item><item><title>I Have Not Given You Consent</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/i-have-not-given-you-consent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 23:43:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/04/i-have-not-given-you-consent/</guid><description>I work on the internet. It&amp;#8217;s true. I write things for you to read (or not read), and spend a lot of my free time creating things that may (or may not) help you fill yours. I&amp;#8217;m not asking for thanks, or really asking for you to do anything at all, but there are a few things I&amp;#8217;m asking that you don&amp;#8217;t do.</description></item><item><title>Announcement: I’m Uncopyrighting Everything I’ve Published Here</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/11/uncopyright/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 00:13:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/11/uncopyright/</guid><description>Update: Check out my reflection that I wrote a year after this experiment for my thoughts on how was I was feeling about it then (in December 2014), which are still true today. As of now (and to be applied retroactively) I am releasing my copyright on everything I&amp;#8217;ve created, written, and published on this site.</description></item><item><title>Being an Ally Between a Rock and a Hard Place</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/being-an-ally-between-a-rock-and-a-hard-place/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 23:14:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/being-an-ally-between-a-rock-and-a-hard-place/</guid><description>I&amp;#8217;m an ally. I&amp;#8217;ve written before why I&amp;#8217;m an ally, and I&amp;#8217;ve even once defended my allyship publicly, highlighting many of my privileged identities. But one thing I&amp;#8217;ve never fully addressed is the double-edged-sword, Kobayashi-Maru-no-win scenario that _can be _what it means to be an ally like me.</description></item><item><title>Gender Book Coming Soon (Update: It&#39;s OUT!)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/02/gender-book-coming-soon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 04:51:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/02/gender-book-coming-soon/</guid><description>Update: the book is super out and you can get your copy at www.guidetogender.com/get. I&amp;#8217;ll leave the original announcement below for posterity&amp;#8217;s sake Hey folks! Great news!
(if you&amp;#8217;re a fan of my work, otherwise &amp;#8220;bad news!&amp;#8221;)
💌Most Wednesdays</description></item><item><title>30&#43; Examples of Masculine Dude (“Bro”) Privileges</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/02/30-examples-of-masculine-dude-bro-privilege/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 23:00:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/02/30-examples-of-masculine-dude-bro-privilege/</guid><description>I&amp;#8217;ve written a few privilege lists, several of which are about privileged identities I possess. They are serious articles that provide a couple hundred examples of systemic oppression (in the US and elsewhere). This article is not that.
I ask that you please humor me as I take a moment to address the many privileges I _don&amp;#8217;t _have access to, due to my gender expression/ metrosexuality.</description></item><item><title>Top Ten Tips on how to Thicken your Skin</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/tips-on-thickening-skin-in-social-justice-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 21:23:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/tips-on-thickening-skin-in-social-justice-work/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I received the following email from a high school senior (we&amp;#8217;ll call her Angie), replied to her, she appreciated the response and told me she&amp;#8217;d be cool with me sharing it with you folks in case any one else might be able to find it useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Angie&amp;#8217;s Email:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need tips on how to thicken my skin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s my issue. I&amp;#8217;m taking Gender/Sexuality Diversity in Literature (basically Gender Studies), and there are kids in my class who don&amp;#8217;t believe in bisexuality, let alone *my* sexuality (aka. pansexuality). I&amp;#8217;m an easy crier and I just know that when this rather basic problem surfaces&amp;#8211;because I&amp;#8217;ve only ever heard these kids mutter their opinions under their breath&amp;#8211;I won&amp;#8217;t make it through the conversation. So, tips?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve thought about coming out to the class (I&amp;#8217;m out to my friends, family, most teachers, and Facebook, but most people don&amp;#8217;t know) but haven&amp;#8217;t. I want people to step on eggshells because they&amp;#8217;re being inclusive, not because I&amp;#8217;m in the room and they don&amp;#8217;t want to offend me personally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any thoughts? Totally fine if not. A snarky one-liner would be just as welcome, because you&amp;#8217;re hilarious and shit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>Build Your Own World</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/build-your-own-world/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2012 22:30:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/build-your-own-world/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Look around you.  Every product, gadget, building, company &amp;#8212; every &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; &amp;#8212; was created by a person who is just like you or me or Uncle Jesse from Full House (kidding &amp;#8212; &lt;em&gt;nobody&lt;/em&gt; is like Uncle Jesse).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you walk through your life, you&amp;#8217;re surrounded by the accomplishments and influences of individuals of the past and present.  You&amp;#8217;re surrounded by a world &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; built &amp;#8212; for you, and everyone around you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, for one, am not entirely happy with the world that has been built for me.  I want to live in a world that is socially just, where individuals all have the same access to the good stuff &amp;#8212; education, jobs, swedish fish, etc. &amp;#8212; regardless of the identities they do or do not possess.  If you&amp;#8217;re like me, you&amp;#8217;ve likely thought, at some point, something along the lines of &lt;em&gt;I want to make this world a better place to live in&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>365 Days of It’s Pronounced Metrosexual (an infographic)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/365-days-of-its-pronounced-metrosexual-an-infographic/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2012 18:19:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/365-days-of-its-pronounced-metrosexual-an-infographic/</guid><description>Holy cow! I just had to renew my domain registration, which was a cue to me that I&amp;#8217;ve been at this for a year now! I collected some fun stats about the site, the show, the genderbread person, and TheMetroStore.com below.</description></item><item><title>My Reasons for being an Ally (AKA Social Justice Advocate)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/5-reasons-im-a-social-justice-all/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 20:00:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/5-reasons-im-a-social-justice-all/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hey, folks.  First of all, thanks for continuing to read what I write here, and thanks even more for sharing.  I don&amp;rsquo;t say that enough.  I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about why I do what I do lately, and I want to once-and-for-all answer a question I get asked an average of 1.6 times per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sam, why do you do what you do?&amp;rdquo; people say, but they are only saying half of what they&amp;rsquo;re thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the context, they might be thinking, &amp;ldquo;Sam, if you&amp;rsquo;re straight, why do you work so much for gay equality?&amp;rdquo;  Or &amp;ldquo;Sam, you&amp;rsquo;re a man, why do you work so much for women&amp;rsquo;s or trans people&amp;rsquo;s equality&amp;rdquo;  Or &amp;ldquo;Sam, you&amp;rsquo;re White, why do you care about equality for people of color?&amp;rdquo;  Or &amp;ldquo;Sam, you&amp;rsquo;re a huge dork, why don&amp;rsquo;t you do anything about that?&amp;rdquo;  And on it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My answer is different every time, because it&amp;rsquo;s hard for me to get down to the absolute root of it all.  But let me provide some of the front-runner explanations for why I do what I do.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>One reason I’m a social justice advocate (as a white, straight, male)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/one-reason-i-do-what-i-do/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2012 21:29:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/one-reason-i-do-what-i-do/</guid><description>I&amp;#8217;ve dedicated my life to progressing social justice, in the hopes that one day we can have a society that is equitable for all. I have a lot of reasons for doing this, but there are just as many reasons why it might be viewed that I _shouldn&amp;#8217;t.</description></item><item><title>Why I’m Boycotting Marriage</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/why-im-boycotting-marriage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 01:52:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/why-im-boycotting-marriage/</guid><description>If five days ago you told me I would consider Sarah Silverman a role model, even in just one aspect, I would have laughed milk through my nose. And I don&amp;#8217;t even drink milk.
Update June 26, 2015: Hey. sK here.</description></item><item><title>Defining a “Metrosexual Male”</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/defining-a-metrosexual-male/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2011 06:21:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/defining-a-metrosexual-male/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;What does metrosexual mean?  What&amp;#8217;s the difference between a metro guy and a non-metro guy?  Isn&amp;#8217;t metrosexual just another word for gay?  Is your ringtone from Kimpossible?  These are questions I find myself answering on a semi-daily basis, and I&amp;#8217;ll be answering them all and more here, now, in the first and only&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;most-comprehensive-blog-post-about-metrosexuality-ever-written-probably&#34;&gt;Most Comprehensive Blog Post about Metrosexuality Ever Written (probably)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s a lot more to metrosexuality than well-fitting jeans, plucked unibrow hairs, and beautiful, flowing hair.  Those are givens, sure, but it goes a bit deeper.  Heck, there&amp;#8217;s even a bit of history behind the whole ordeal.  Let&amp;#8217;s start with that.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>