<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Identity on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/identity/</link><description>Recent content in Identity on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 15:53:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/identity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Does the Genderbread Person exclude genderfluid people?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/articles/genderbread-person-and-genderfluidity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 15:53:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/articles/genderbread-person-and-genderfluidity/</guid><description>I got an email pointing out to me that my versions of the Genderbread Person exclude genderfluid people. And not just people who use the term &amp;ldquo;genderfluid&amp;rdquo; to identify themselves, but anyone who expresses gender differently at different times. So, do they?</description></item><item><title>The Social Justice Power Inverse</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-social-justice-power-inverse/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 18:19:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-social-justice-power-inverse/</guid><description>&lt;p>A lot of social justice conversations focus on power. Who has power in society and who doesn’t?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We highlight how systems inequitably distribute power to some while withholding it from others — based on &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/">who we are&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We refer to people who are granted disproportionate power as “privileged,” “majoritized,” “centered,” etc. And those from whom power is withheld as “oppressed,” “minoritized,” “marginalized,” etc.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, nobody is only one of those two. We’re both, depending on which situation we’re in, and what dimensions of ourselves are brought to the forefront.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our goal in talking about this is dismantling inequitable power structures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/">The needle on our compass points toward equity.&lt;/a> Removing barriers, promoting access, and shrinking the gap between the “haves” and “have nots” — or, in &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/03/the-two-worlds-dilemma/">a perfect world&lt;/a>, making that dichotomy irrelevant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the things we don’t talk about is how power structures manifest in social justice spaces, or the micro-society that is the community of &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/">social justice people&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here, we preserve the idea of the power structure, but swap out who sits where.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Defining LGBTQ+</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/books/defining-lgbtq/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:21:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/books/defining-lgbtq/</guid><description>Defining LBGTQ+ is a helpful guide for getting a grasp on the terminology of gender and sexuality. It includes definitions for lots of terms, explainers for how to use them, and more!
Now, before you get too excited, it’s not really a book-book.</description></item><item><title>Why Think of Gender on Scales Instead of a Spectrum?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/02/gender-scales-or-spectrums/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 01:41:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/02/gender-scales-or-spectrums/</guid><description>&lt;p>When it comes to gender, most people have a similar understanding of it in their minds.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It looks something like this:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Genderbread Person version 4</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/10/the-genderbread-person-v4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 06:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/10/the-genderbread-person-v4/</guid><description>A few hundred workshops, three years, and one book edition later, I’m happy to finally publish here my 4th version of the Genderbread Person. Check it out, download it, and share it with your educator friend who is still using v3.</description></item><item><title>Self-Guided Foundational Safe Zone Training</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/self-guided-foundational-safe-zone-training/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/self-guided-foundational-safe-zone-training/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Learn about your first impressions of LGBTQ+ people, core vocabulary, gender &amp;amp; sexuality theory, privilege &amp;amp; coming out, and get your questions answered.&amp;rdquo;
That's from the course description, and does a good job of summing this up. I co-created this course with Meg Bolger based on our years of experience facilitating countless in-person Safe Zone workshops.</description></item><item><title>A Few Pronoun Best [Preferred?] Practices</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/pronoun-best-preferred-practices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 20:20:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/pronoun-best-preferred-practices/</guid><description>Pronouns: reentering prominence in many people’s lives for the first time since grammar school. How do we do them best? What should we avoid?
A couple things to keep in mind up front:
Pronouns replace people’s names (e.g., “Sam is nice” ?</description></item><item><title>What's the best way to view gender? As a Spectrum? Continuums?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/videos/gender-from-checkboxes-to-continuums/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/videos/gender-from-checkboxes-to-continuums/</guid><description>I was invited to give a Nerd Nite talk and speak about the subject I nerd out about the most: gender. And I got to talk about a lot of the dimensions of my work that I usually don't &amp;ndash; stuff that usually stays behind the scenes.</description></item><item><title>A Guide to Gender (2nd Edition)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/books/guide-to-gender/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:21:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/books/guide-to-gender/</guid><description>The first edition was featured as #1 best-seller in Gender on Amazon, and is being used by gender studies &amp;amp; sociology professors on 3 continents. Now with a new foreword by the author, brand new chapters, fixed tpyos, and more gender!</description></item><item><title>The Genderbread Person version 3</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2015/03/the-genderbread-person-v3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 02:05:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2015/03/the-genderbread-person-v3/</guid><description>Taking the lessons learned from version 2, and applying them to sexuality in a more meaningful way, here’s my best rendition of the genderbread person yet.
Hey! Friend! I published a version 4 of my Genderbread Person! It&amp;#8217;s at least 33.</description></item><item><title>My TED Talk: Understanding the Complexities of Gender</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/my-ted-talk-understanding-the-complexities-of-gender/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/my-ted-talk-understanding-the-complexities-of-gender/</guid><description>I had the honor of being asked to give another TEDx talk, and they let me do it all about gender.
You can watch the video below, and see as I try to condense hundreds of pages of my book into 16 minutes of comprehensible, enjoyable, and sometimes-rhyming words.</description></item><item><title>Comprehensive* List of LGBTQ+ Vocabulary Definitions</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/01/a-comprehensive-list-of-lgbtq-term-definitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 23:46:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/01/a-comprehensive-list-of-lgbtq-term-definitions/</guid><description>Hi! This post is now available as part of an E-Book called &amp;#8220;Defining LGBTQ+&amp;#8221;. It includes the most recently updated definitions for all the terms below, the rules, and a bunch of other stuff. You can download it as a .</description></item><item><title>You Soup: understanding diversity and the intersections of identity</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 19:17:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/</guid><description>&lt;p>In doing the work I do, I often find myself struggling to help people make sense of the two extremes of identity: on one side we have the idea that people in a group are all the same (stereotypes); while the other side supports this idea that everyone is absolutely unique (snowflakes).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I find myself saying “we’re not the same, but we’re also not that different,” to the furrowing of brows, so I wanted to take a moment here to talk about the relationship of individual identity and social group memberships, as well as introduce a new graphic concept.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What does the asterisk in “trans*” stand for?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/what-does-the-asterisk-in-trans-stand-for/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 20:01:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/what-does-the-asterisk-in-trans-stand-for/</guid><description>A few people have asked why I write “trans*” (with the asterisk) instead of just “trans” when referring to trans* folks on my site. Well, I’m happy to answer that!
💌Most Wednesdays
I publish new Social Justice, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Resources.</description></item><item><title>3 Reasons Positive Stereotypes aren’t that Positive</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/reasons-positive-stereotypes-are-not-positive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2012 04:30:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/reasons-positive-stereotypes-are-not-positive/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a title="A show about snap judgments, identity, and oppression." href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/a-show-about-snap-judgments-identity-and-oppression/" target="_blank">my show&lt;/a>, I address the issue of positive stereotypes head-on, but I wanted to write an article about it as well.  For those of you unaware, positive stereotypes are assumptions about an entire group or identity (e.g., gay men) that are considered to be &amp;ldquo;good.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some examples of positive stereotypes of gay men: they are artsy, friendly, fun, social, well-spoken, well-dressed, well-groomed, fit, and sassy (I think sassy is positive).  The list goes on.  Those are all good things, yeah?  There can’t be any harm in perpetuating those stereotypes, right?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Positive stereotypes exist for just about every identity and have the capacity to be just as damaging as the negative ones.  Don’t believe me?  Read this list of reasons why and get back to me afterward.  Oh, and if you have any additional examples, as always, share them in the comments below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Genderbread Person version 2</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/03/the-genderbread-person-v2-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 00:42:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/03/the-genderbread-person-v2-0/</guid><description>Heads up! I wrote a book all about gender that builds on the &amp;#8220;-ness&amp;#8221; concepts I introduced with this Genderbread Person. If you appreciate this, you&amp;#8217;ll love this book. Hundreds of comments, ditto emails, ditto Facebook messages and Twitter tweeters and in-person holla-atchas and I feel like I’m finally in a place to release this.</description></item><item><title>The Genderbread Person</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/the-genderbread-person/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 20:01:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/the-genderbread-person/</guid><description>Please check out the new-and-improved Genderbread Person v2.0. It&amp;#8217;s a heckuvalot better and just as free to share/print! I&amp;#8217;m leaving this up for now for those who want it, but I&amp;#8217;m no longer endorsing it as the effective model. The Genderbread Person is an infographic that breaks down gender identity, gender expression, biological sex, and sexual orientation into an easy to understand visual.</description></item></channel></rss>