<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Education on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/education/</link><description>Recent content in Education on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 17:34:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Social Justice Minus Dogma Online Course</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/social-justice-minus-dogma-course/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/social-justice-minus-dogma-course/</guid><description>Over the course of 6 weeks of self-guided learning (or however long you choose), explore the social justice dogma, identify its cornerstones and pitfalls, and plot a path forward toward true living social justice.
This course is an extension of all the writing I've done here about &amp;ldquo;social justice dogma.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Social Justice Compass</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 23:09:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you sailing the seas of social injustice, looking for a path toward equity, and in need of a tool that can point you in the right direction? Perhaps you are &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/social-justice-then-and-now/">rethinking how you &lt;em>do&lt;/em> social justice now&lt;/a>, today, in 2019 — with everything happening in the world — and searching for a new path forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Avast!&lt;/em> A new model for thinking about and doing social justice… &lt;em>ho&lt;/em>! This is off to a bad start. It turns out that every day can be &lt;a href="http://talklikeapirate.com/wordpress/">International Talk like a Pirate Day&lt;/a> if you don’t care about having friends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But if you care about social justice, friend, well, look no further!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, I’m happy to share with you a new model for thinking about social justice, for considering your actions, attitudes, and beliefs, and for guiding yourself and your community toward equity: The Social Justice Compass.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s dive right in.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>If You’re Still Doing Social Justice How You Were Then, Reconsider.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/social-justice-then-and-now/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 19:41:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/social-justice-then-and-now/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’ve seen people at conferences giving the same talk they gave two years ago. Activists speaking and organizing in ways unchanged since 2015. Educators facilitating workshops with a curriculum written in 2012.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The world is different now than it was then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The people you’re working with — or against, or for — have different mindsets, beliefs, knowledge, perspectives, values, opinions, grudges, predispositions, awarenesses, and biases now than they did then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The world you’re working in — and trying to improve — is comprised of different technologies, constituencies, zeitgeists, cultural norms, and public knowledge now than it was then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the “then” could be yesterday. Or last year. Your “then” could be “before Trump was elected. Or “when we didn’t know this huge thing.” Or “before ‘Black Lives Matter’ activism started.” Or “when we weren’t sure whether this one thing would work or not.” Or “before our community experienced that travesty.” Or “when we didn’t have social media.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I started doing social justice work, most people didn’t know what “social justice” meant. They’d never heard the phrase. It was brand new to them. That was the first bar to jump: explaining &lt;em>what I was working to do&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That’s a “then”: when most people I encountered hadn’t heard the phrase “social justice.”&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Genderbread Person version 4</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/10/the-genderbread-person-v4/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 06:00:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/10/the-genderbread-person-v4/</guid><description>A few hundred workshops, three years, and one book edition later, I’m happy to finally publish here my 4th version of the Genderbread Person. Check it out, download it, and share it with your educator friend who is still using v3.</description></item><item><title>Self-Guided Foundational Safe Zone Training</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/self-guided-foundational-safe-zone-training/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/courses/self-guided-foundational-safe-zone-training/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Learn about your first impressions of LGBTQ+ people, core vocabulary, gender &amp;amp; sexuality theory, privilege &amp;amp; coming out, and get your questions answered.&amp;rdquo;
That's from the course description, and does a good job of summing this up. I co-created this course with Meg Bolger based on our years of experience facilitating countless in-person Safe Zone workshops.</description></item><item><title>3-Dimensional Social Justice</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/05/3-dimensional-social-justice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 03:33:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/05/3-dimensional-social-justice/</guid><description>Despite a tidal wave of awareness of social justice issues (or maybe because of it), a lot of conversations are getting stuck. Some people are becoming increasingly “anti social justice.” And we seem to be circling loops that go back decades.</description></item><item><title>A Few Pronoun Best [Preferred?] Practices</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/pronoun-best-preferred-practices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 20:20:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/pronoun-best-preferred-practices/</guid><description>Pronouns: reentering prominence in many people’s lives for the first time since grammar school. How do we do them best? What should we avoid?
A couple things to keep in mind up front:
Pronouns replace people’s names (e.g., “Sam is nice” ?</description></item><item><title>The Magical Power of “Some” for Social Justice Educators</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/magical-power-social-justice-educators/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 22:56:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/magical-power-social-justice-educators/</guid><description>There are few things that changed how effective of a social justice educator I was as much as the word “some.”
It started as a way to correct people, or redirect them, or respond to problematic questions.
Someone would ask something like “When people say they’re bisexual, isn’t it really just a phase?</description></item><item><title>Some Different Taxonomies for Social Justice People</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 22:29:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/taxonomy-social-justice-people/</guid><description>We often group social justice people by identity, cause, or “-ism” (e.g., racial justice people, gender justice, queer justice, wage justice). People outside of the social justice movement seem inclined to group SJ people as being either “social justice warriors” or not.</description></item><item><title>One Huge Prickly Reason Why Anti-LGBTQ Folks Don’t Change Their Views</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/01/ignored-reason-people-dont-affirm-lgbtq-people-make-harder/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 20:08:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/01/ignored-reason-people-dont-affirm-lgbtq-people-make-harder/</guid><description>I need you to take a leap with me.
Leap into the shoes of someone who has walked through their life knowing that being gay, being bi, lesbian, or pan, or that being non-binary, gender non-conforming, or trans — that being different, different from straight, different from cisgender — is wrong.</description></item><item><title>What's the best way to view gender? As a Spectrum? Continuums?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/videos/gender-from-checkboxes-to-continuums/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/videos/gender-from-checkboxes-to-continuums/</guid><description>I was invited to give a Nerd Nite talk and speak about the subject I nerd out about the most: gender. And I got to talk about a lot of the dimensions of my work that I usually don't &amp;ndash; stuff that usually stays behind the scenes.</description></item><item><title>What makes a relationship healthy? Unhealthy? These four things, to start.</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2016/11/rest-columns-shadows-healthy-relationship-model/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2016 23:01:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2016/11/rest-columns-shadows-healthy-relationship-model/</guid><description>It’s hard to define what a healthy relationship looks like because we all navigate relationships differently. Relationships are generally seen through the lenses of our gender as well as our sexuality, but there are many other aspects of our identity that are going to inform what we see as good or bad, desirable or detestable, healthy or unhealthy.</description></item><item><title>The Many Elements of Comprehensive Sexuality: Meet the Sexualitree</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2016/05/sexualitree-model-of-comprehensive-sexuality/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 21:52:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2016/05/sexualitree-model-of-comprehensive-sexuality/</guid><description>Sexuality is a touchy subject. For example, just that opening joke might have been enough to turn someone off (I could go all day. But I won’t.). As easy as it is to make awkward puns, or be uncomfortable in general talking about sexuality, it’s an important subject that affects all of us on different levels of our lives.</description></item><item><title>When Someone Comes Out To You: DO &amp; DON’T</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2016/04/when-someone-comes-out-to-you-do-dont/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 20:32:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2016/04/when-someone-comes-out-to-you-do-dont/</guid><description>In one of the first safe zone trainings I remember participating in, there was a loaded question about coming out that was followed by an excellent answer from the facilitator. The question was something like “Why don’t some people come out of the closet?</description></item><item><title>Unlocking the Magic of Facilitation</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/books/unlocking-the-magic-of-facilitation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 00:21:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/books/unlocking-the-magic-of-facilitation/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Meg and Sam have given us a gift; their book is smartly designed to invite new and seasoned facilitators to be intentional about having those tough group discussions. As an educator and facilitator, this book gives me a framework to understand my own facilitation style, and ways that I can continue to improve.</description></item><item><title>The Genderbread Person version 3</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2015/03/the-genderbread-person-v3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 02:05:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2015/03/the-genderbread-person-v3/</guid><description>Taking the lessons learned from version 2, and applying them to sexuality in a more meaningful way, here’s my best rendition of the genderbread person yet.
💌Most Wednesdays
I publish new Social Justice, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Resources.
Get the Email. Someone pointed out that I hadn’t shared this here yet, even though it’s been _out _for awhile.</description></item><item><title>Empathy leads to Understanding</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/10/empathy-leads-to-understanding/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2014 21:57:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2014/10/empathy-leads-to-understanding/</guid><description>The other day I was at Lehigh University engaging in a bunch of conversations about identity, sexuality, gender, and social justice (ya know — my jam). The groups I was talking with and to were eager and willing to learn, which is not to be taken for granted, but a sentiment kept popping up: “This identity stuff is complicated.</description></item><item><title>The Intentions vs. Outcomes Matrix</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/12/the-intentions-vs-outcomes-matrix/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2013 22:42:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/12/the-intentions-vs-outcomes-matrix/</guid><description>It’s no secret I’m not a big fan of how highly we regard intentions. There’s even a whole chapter in my bookabout it, and it recently led to a great conversation, which led to this more visual representation of the dynamics between intentions and outcomes.</description></item><item><title>15+ Fantastic Resources for Talking about “Homosexuality” (i.e., LGBTQ people) and The Bible</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/10/resources-lgbtq-homosexual-bible-christianity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 21:47:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/10/resources-lgbtq-homosexual-bible-christianity/</guid><description>Only a tiny, tiny part of the bible can even be argued to reference “homosexuality” (and that argument, in a few of the verses in particular, is worth looking into), yet it seems like whenever we hear about the Bible in the news it’s being slammed against LGBTQ equality.</description></item><item><title>9+ Silly Gender Comics I drew in 5 Minutes or Less</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/silly-gender-comics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 01:19:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/silly-gender-comics/</guid><description>I made all of these comics for my book. Some of them are in there. Some didn’t make the cut. And many more that aren’t here did. Hope they give you a gender-equity giggle.</description></item><item><title>My TED Talk: Understanding the Complexities of Gender</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/my-ted-talk-understanding-the-complexities-of-gender/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 17:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/05/my-ted-talk-understanding-the-complexities-of-gender/</guid><description>I had the honor of being asked to give another TEDx talk, and they let me do it all about gender.
You can watch the video below, and see as I try to condense hundreds of pages of my book into 16 minutes of comprehensible, enjoyable, and sometimes-rhyming words.</description></item><item><title>Comprehensive* List of LGBTQ+ Vocabulary Definitions</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/01/a-comprehensive-list-of-lgbtq-term-definitions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 23:46:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2013/01/a-comprehensive-list-of-lgbtq-term-definitions/</guid><description>*This list is neither comprehensive nor inviolable, but it’s a work in progress toward those goals. With identity terms, trust the person who is using the term and their definition of it above any dictionary. These definitions are the creation of a cultural commons: emails, online discussions, and in-person chats, with the initial curation being mine, then growing into a collaboration between Meg Bolger and me at TheSafeZoneProject.</description></item><item><title>You Soup: understanding diversity and the intersections of identity</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2012 19:17:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/10/individual-difference-and-group-similiarity/</guid><description>&lt;p>In doing the work I do, I often find myself struggling to help people make sense of the two extremes of identity: on one side we have the idea that people in a group are all the same (stereotypes); while the other side supports this idea that everyone is absolutely unique (snowflakes).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I find myself saying “we’re not the same, but we’re also not that different,” to the furrowing of brows, so I wanted to take a moment here to talk about the relationship of individual identity and social group memberships, as well as introduce a new graphic concept.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to explain that bisexuality (or pansexuality) is real</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/how-to-explain-to-someone-bisexuality-or-pansexuality-is-real/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 20:24:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/how-to-explain-to-someone-bisexuality-or-pansexuality-is-real/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Bisexuality is a thing. It’s not just “a stop between gay and straight.” But how do you explain that to someone who just. simply. won’t. believe. you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am going to focus on the struggle many bisexual and pansexual folks have convincing their straight (or gay/lesbian) peers that bisexuality is an identity, not just a stopping point between two others.  While I’m focusing this article on advice for bi- and pansexual folks, some of it applies to all sexuality discussions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have three main approaches you can take below, but I’d love to hear suggestions for more ways to breach this subject in the comments below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top Ten Tips on how to Thicken your Skin</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/tips-on-thickening-skin-in-social-justice-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 21:23:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/tips-on-thickening-skin-in-social-justice-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>I received the following email from a high school senior (we’ll call her Angie), replied to her, she appreciated the response and told me she’d be cool with me sharing it with you folks in case any one else might be able to find it useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Angie’s Email:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I need tips on how to thicken my skin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here’s my issue. I’m taking Gender/Sexuality Diversity in Literature (basically Gender Studies), and there are kids in my class who don’t believe in bisexuality, let alone *my* sexuality (aka. pansexuality). I’m an easy crier and I just know that when this rather basic problem surfaces–because I’ve only ever heard these kids mutter their opinions under their breath–I won’t make it through the conversation. So, tips?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve thought about coming out to the class (I’m out to my friends, family, most teachers, and Facebook, but most people don’t know) but haven’t. I want people to step on eggshells because they’re being inclusive, not because I’m in the room and they don’t want to offend me personally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Any thoughts? Totally fine if not. A snarky one-liner would be just as welcome, because you’re hilarious and shit.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>How To Avoid Being a Stereotype</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-avoid-being-a-stereotype/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 23:57:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-avoid-being-a-stereotype/</guid><description>&lt;p>You want to be seen as an individual, right?  Of course you do.  But it’s bordering on impossible to avoid perpetuating at least some of the stereotypes attached to the various aspects of your identity.  There are just too many of them!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, that’s where I can help.  Consider this a “How to be [X], without being a stereotypical [X]” guide.  I’m hitting a variety of major identities, but feel free to request addendums to the guide in the comments below, on &lt;a href="http://facebook.com/metrosam" title="http://facebook.com/metrosam">Facebook&lt;/a>, or on &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Twitter&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, if you’re more prone to spot-reading than reading-reading, &lt;strong>I strongly encourage you to at least read the last section before you formulate your reaction to this article&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Without further ado, in alphabetical order…&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to respond when someone uses non-inclusive (or bigoted) language</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-respond-to-non-inclusive-language-or-bigoted-speec/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 21:24:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-respond-to-non-inclusive-language-or-bigoted-speec/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Intentions don’t matter, outcomes do&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->.  However, I still think we need to do a much better job of being supportive of newcomers to the social justice “scene” who may be well-intended, but don’t quite know the ropes yet.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is my picture guide (sorry, no &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->flowchart&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->) of how to properly handle such situations, without scaring off a potential ally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/how-to-respond-comic.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Costs of Marriage Inequality (an infographic)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/the-costs-of-marriage-inequality-an-infographic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 20:24:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/the-costs-of-marriage-inequality-an-infographic/</guid><description>This isn’t an IPM Edugraphic, but I felt compelled to get the message out. Check it out, be shocked, then head to takepart.com and do something about it. Annnnd go.</description></item><item><title>What does the asterisk in “trans*” stand for?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/what-does-the-asterisk-in-trans-stand-for/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 20:01:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/what-does-the-asterisk-in-trans-stand-for/</guid><description>A few people have asked why I write “trans*” (with the asterisk) instead of just “trans” when referring to trans* folks on my site. Well, I’m happy to answer that!
💌Most Wednesdays
I publish new Social Justice, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Resources.</description></item><item><title>4 Reasons You Should Stop Saying “Non-Straight”</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/reasons-you-should-stop-saying-non-straight-and-say-queer/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 18:13:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/reasons-you-should-stop-saying-non-straight-and-say-queer/</guid><description>With all the talk of marriage equality, gay comic book weddings, and even gayer flowchartsflowing around the web, people are getting ever more sensitive about using inclusive language when they can.
That’s great! But more often than ever I am hearing folks use the term “non-straight” to refer to people who are lesbian, gay, bi-, pan- or even trans*.</description></item><item><title>30+ Examples of Christian Privileges</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/list-of-examples-of-christian-privileg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 18:13:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/list-of-examples-of-christian-privileg/</guid><description>Following is a list of privileges granted to people in the U.S. (and many western nations) for being Christian.
💌Most Wednesdays
I publish new Social Justice, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Resources.
Get the Email. Please comment below if you have any additions or revisions to make!</description></item><item><title>5 Reasons My Approach to Social Justice Work is Better than Yours</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/5-reasons-my-approach-to-social-justice-work-is-better-than-yours/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 21:10:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/5-reasons-my-approach-to-social-justice-work-is-better-than-yours/</guid><description>&lt;p>The way I approach social justice and ally work on this site and &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->in my show&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> has a distinct flavor.  Some would call it sweet, but I think &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->ginger&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> is a bit spicy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t often do things by accident, and in this case it is very _on purpose.  _My flavor is even so noticeable that if you’ve seen a lot of what I’ve created here, you’re likely taken aback by the headline of this article.  Well, that actually leads me into my first point.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why your intentions don’t really matter, but outcomes do</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/why-your-intentions-dont-matter-victim-blaming-and-political-correctness/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 23:34:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/why-your-intentions-dont-matter-victim-blaming-and-political-correctness/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/ingrids-intentionality-elixir.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve created a &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->few&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->graphics&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> about &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->when it’s okay to say “gay”&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> and the one argument that keeps coming up goes something like “How can you regulate language? What’s offensive to one person is not to another.  What matters is your intentions.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Intentions don’t matter, effect does.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I will elaborate on my response to that question more in a bit, but first I want to pose another question, and posit an answer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Flowchart: I Want To Say Gay (When it’s Okay)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/even-better-flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-gay/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 19:34:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/even-better-flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-gay/</guid><description>When I published my original flowchart, I said it was for the more analytical folks who are wondering if “gay” is the right word choice for them. Well, this one is for the most analytical folks, and also folks who enjoy data presented in cute and adorable ways.</description></item><item><title>Flowchart: when it’s okay to say “that’s so gay”</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-thats-so-gay-prin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 22:10:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-thats-so-gay-prin/</guid><description>For the more analytical folks, we created a handy flowchart to help make the decision “Is ‘gay’ the right word for me?”
As you can tell, in most cases, the answer is no. Print, post, and share freely.</description></item><item><title>The Genderbread Person version 2</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/03/the-genderbread-person-v2-0/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2012 00:42:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/03/the-genderbread-person-v2-0/</guid><description>Hundreds of comments, ditto emails, ditto Facebook messages and Twitter tweeters and in-person holla-atchas and I feel like I’m finally in a place to release this. I give you the new and improved Genderbread Person!
(click for larger size)
Depending on what you folks have to say after checking this out and reading the rationale below, I’ll be updating the Breaking through the Binary article and uploading a printer-friendly version of the new graphic.</description></item><item><title>When to use the word “gay”</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/when-to-use-the-word-gay-print/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 00:14:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/when-to-use-the-word-gay-print/</guid><description>When is it &amp;ldquo;okay&amp;rdquo; to say gay? Why is this even a question we need to be asking? Well, because it seems that people have some misconceptions, and this flowchart makes it simple.
This graphic was originally created to support this article, but then a comment was made saying this should be hung on every dorm wall in America.</description></item><item><title>The Genderbread Person</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/the-genderbread-person/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 20:01:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/the-genderbread-person/</guid><description>The Genderbread Person is an infographic that breaks down gender identity, gender expression, biological sex, and sexual orientation into an easy to understand visual.
It’s been around in some form for many years, and this is my whack at making an inclusive, adorable, easy to understand depiction.</description></item><item><title>Political Correctness VS. Inclusiveness</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/political-correct-versus-being-inclusiv/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2011 21:41:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/political-correct-versus-being-inclusiv/</guid><description>I would never ask you to be politically correct. I’ve gotten some flak from my “When Gay is Okay” and “Why I say partner” articles. People feel that I’m soap-boxing for political correctness, when that couldn’t be further from the truth.</description></item><item><title>The Corruption of the Golden Rule</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/the-corruption-of-the-golden-rule/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2011 21:25:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/the-corruption-of-the-golden-rule/</guid><description>Do unto others as you would have them do unto you. Right?
Wrong.
What we’ve been teaching our children, what I have learned and re-learned all of my life, is one of the worst pieces of advice around. What’s worse: it’s nearly universally accepted as gospel (pun intended).</description></item><item><title>A visual aid: when “gay” is okay</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/a-visual-aid-when-gay-okay-to-sa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 21:51:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/a-visual-aid-when-gay-okay-to-sa/</guid><description>For those of you still struggling with the idea of when it is and isn’t ideal to use the word “gay”, even after reading my article outlining the whole idea, I decided to create a few visual aids. Hopefully they are straightforward.</description></item><item><title>30+ Examples of Cisgender Privileges</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/list-of-cisgender-privileges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 04:01:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/list-of-cisgender-privileges/</guid><description>Following is a list of cisgender identity privileges. If you are cisgender, listed below are benefits that result from your alignment of identity and perceived identity.
If cisgender is a new term to you, here’s how I define it in my list of LGBTQ+ vocabulary:</description></item><item><title>Breaking through the binary: Gender explained using continuums</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/breaking-through-the-binary-gender-explained-using-continuums/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 03:15:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/11/breaking-through-the-binary-gender-explained-using-continuums/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Gender is a tough subject to tackle.  There are a lot of facets to consider, a lot of pressures at play, and we have all been conditioned in such a way that our first instinct is almost unanimously wrong.  But we’re going to tackle it.  No, we’re going to tackle the snot out of it.  Coming to our aid, I would like to present to you: The Genderbread Person!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>