<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>How-To on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/how-to/</link><description>Recent content in How-To on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 18:34:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How (Not) To Use a Privilege List</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/how-not-to-use-a-privilege-list/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 18:34:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/how-not-to-use-a-privilege-list/</guid><description>&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/category/privilege-lists/">Privilege Lists&lt;/a> that &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/about/about-sam-killermann/">I’ve&lt;/a> published &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/about/">here&lt;/a> have been downloaded over 100 million times cumulatively. I share this because it’s cool to say (big number!), but also because that reach has allowed me to see these lists used in a variety of ways: some good, some neutral, and some downright harmful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ways to use a privilege list are innumerable, and the creativity I’ve witnessed has been astounding. As a tool, they can be transformative.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So instead of using this space to advocate for ways I encourage using the lists, it’ll be easier to write few quick “Please Don’t Do This” bullets:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Introducing the Social Justice Compass</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 23:09:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/introducing-the-social-justice-compass/</guid><description>&lt;p>Are you sailing the seas of social injustice, looking for a path toward equity, and in need of a tool that can point you in the right direction? Perhaps you are &lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2019/01/social-justice-then-and-now/">rethinking how you &lt;em>do&lt;/em> social justice now&lt;/a>, today, in 2019 — with everything happening in the world — and searching for a new path forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Avast!&lt;/em> A new model for thinking about and doing social justice… &lt;em>ho&lt;/em>! This is off to a bad start. It turns out that every day can be &lt;a href="http://talklikeapirate.com/wordpress/">International Talk like a Pirate Day&lt;/a> if you don’t care about having friends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But if you care about social justice, friend, well, look no further!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, I’m happy to share with you a new model for thinking about social justice, for considering your actions, attitudes, and beliefs, and for guiding yourself and your community toward equity: The Social Justice Compass.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let’s dive right in.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Few Pronoun Best [Preferred?] Practices</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/pronoun-best-preferred-practices/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 20:20:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/04/pronoun-best-preferred-practices/</guid><description>Pronouns: reentering prominence in many people’s lives for the first time since grammar school. How do we do them best? What should we avoid?
A couple things to keep in mind up front:
Pronouns replace people’s names (e.g., “Sam is nice” ?</description></item><item><title>The Magical Power of “Some” for Social Justice Educators</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/magical-power-social-justice-educators/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2018 22:56:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2018/03/magical-power-social-justice-educators/</guid><description>There are few things that changed how effective of a social justice educator I was as much as the word “some.”
It started as a way to correct people, or redirect them, or respond to problematic questions.
Someone would ask something like “When people say they’re bisexual, isn’t it really just a phase?</description></item><item><title>Taking Up Space vs. Adding to a Space: Questions to Consider</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/02/taking-up-space-vs-adding-to-a-space-questions-to-consider/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2017 22:46:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/02/taking-up-space-vs-adding-to-a-space-questions-to-consider/</guid><description>A lot of us want to just “be people,” and leave our social identities at the door when we enter a room. In September 2016, I was asked to participate in Katie Couric’s “Gender Revolution” documentary (by National Geographic). The following questions were what I worked through — and what I generally work through — when deciding to say “yes” or “no.</description></item><item><title>A Few Small Tips for Attending Your First Protest March</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/01/a-few-small-tips-for-attending-your-first-protest-march/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 23:28:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2017/01/a-few-small-tips-for-attending-your-first-protest-march/</guid><description>I’ve organized and participated in a lot of political resistance over the years. From high school walkouts, to college sit-ins, to guerrilla activism campaigns, to marches and public demonstrations. And I’m guessing that a lot of folks in the U.S. may be wading into these waters for the first time this year (because Trump presidency year one), or this week (because Women’s March on Washington).</description></item><item><title>When Someone Comes Out To You: DO &amp; DON’T</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2016/04/when-someone-comes-out-to-you-do-dont/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 20:32:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2016/04/when-someone-comes-out-to-you-do-dont/</guid><description>In one of the first safe zone trainings I remember participating in, there was a loaded question about coming out that was followed by an excellent answer from the facilitator. The question was something like “Why don’t some people come out of the closet?</description></item><item><title>50+ concrete things you can do today to make for a more socially just tomorrow</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/11/things-you-can-do-today-for-social-justice/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 05:34:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/11/things-you-can-do-today-for-social-justice/</guid><description>&lt;p>Social justice — the idea that everyone in a society, regardless of the identities they embody, can have an equitable shot at success and happiness — is a goal that seems unrealistic for many people. “It’s a pipe dream, Sam,” they say, smugly. “Life isn’t rainbows and butterflies,” they say, adorably.&lt;/p>
&lt;aside class="heyHeyLook wednesdayEmail">&lt;p>&lt;span class="icon">💌&lt;/span>&lt;strong>Most Wednesdays&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>&lt;p>I publish new Social Justice, Gender, &amp; Sexuality Resources.&lt;/p> &lt;a class="button" title="Join my mailing list" href="http://bit.ly/2MmE28c" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Get the Email.&lt;/a>&lt;/aside>
&lt;p>To achieve social justice we will have to break down a lot of huge barriers that exist on a scale far above the individual, but even the biggest scale change is nothing more than the sum of &lt;em>a whole lot&lt;/em> of individual efforts.  My goal with this site is to support you in doing just that: making big change on an individual level.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following are &lt;em>a whole&lt;/em> &lt;em>lot&lt;/em> of individual efforts you can make today that will be significant steps toward that biggest scale change we need for a socially just tomorrow.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to explain that bisexuality (or pansexuality) is real</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/how-to-explain-to-someone-bisexuality-or-pansexuality-is-real/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 20:24:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/how-to-explain-to-someone-bisexuality-or-pansexuality-is-real/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>Bisexuality is a thing. It’s not just “a stop between gay and straight.” But how do you explain that to someone who just. simply. won’t. believe. you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am going to focus on the struggle many bisexual and pansexual folks have convincing their straight (or gay/lesbian) peers that bisexuality is an identity, not just a stopping point between two others.  While I’m focusing this article on advice for bi- and pansexual folks, some of it applies to all sexuality discussions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have three main approaches you can take below, but I’d love to hear suggestions for more ways to breach this subject in the comments below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top Ten Tips on how to Thicken your Skin</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/tips-on-thickening-skin-in-social-justice-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 21:23:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/tips-on-thickening-skin-in-social-justice-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>I received the following email from a high school senior (we’ll call her Angie), replied to her, she appreciated the response and told me she’d be cool with me sharing it with you folks in case any one else might be able to find it useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Angie’s Email:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I need tips on how to thicken my skin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here’s my issue. I’m taking Gender/Sexuality Diversity in Literature (basically Gender Studies), and there are kids in my class who don’t believe in bisexuality, let alone *my* sexuality (aka. pansexuality). I’m an easy crier and I just know that when this rather basic problem surfaces–because I’ve only ever heard these kids mutter their opinions under their breath–I won’t make it through the conversation. So, tips?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve thought about coming out to the class (I’m out to my friends, family, most teachers, and Facebook, but most people don’t know) but haven’t. I want people to step on eggshells because they’re being inclusive, not because I’m in the room and they don’t want to offend me personally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Any thoughts? Totally fine if not. A snarky one-liner would be just as welcome, because you’re hilarious and shit.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>How to respond when someone uses non-inclusive (or bigoted) language</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-respond-to-non-inclusive-language-or-bigoted-speec/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 21:24:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-to-respond-to-non-inclusive-language-or-bigoted-speec/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->Intentions don’t matter, outcomes do&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->.  However, I still think we need to do a much better job of being supportive of newcomers to the social justice “scene” who may be well-intended, but don’t quite know the ropes yet.  &lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is my picture guide (sorry, no &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->flowchart&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->) of how to properly handle such situations, without scaring off a potential ally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/how-to-respond-comic.jpg">&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How you can make the gender question on an application form more inclusive</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-can-i-make-the-gender-question-on-an-application-form-more-inclusive/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2012 21:11:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/06/how-can-i-make-the-gender-question-on-an-application-form-more-inclusive/</guid><description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&lt;p>A lot of people are unsure of how to make an inclusive gender or sex question on a form, and default to “are you male or female?”  Let’s not do that.  Read on for some best practices and suggestions to make your forms more gender inclusive.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>5 Reasons My Approach to Social Justice Work is Better than Yours</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/5-reasons-my-approach-to-social-justice-work-is-better-than-yours/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 21:10:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/05/5-reasons-my-approach-to-social-justice-work-is-better-than-yours/</guid><description>&lt;p>The way I approach social justice and ally work on this site and &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->in my show&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> has a distinct flavor.  Some would call it sweet, but I think &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted -->ginger&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --> is a bit spicy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I don’t often do things by accident, and in this case it is very _on purpose.  _My flavor is even so noticeable that if you’ve seen a lot of what I’ve created here, you’re likely taken aback by the headline of this article.  Well, that actually leads me into my first point.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Flowchart: I Want To Say Gay (When it’s Okay)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/even-better-flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-gay/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2012 19:34:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/even-better-flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-gay/</guid><description>When I published my original flowchart, I said it was for the more analytical folks who are wondering if “gay” is the right word choice for them. Well, this one is for the most analytical folks, and also folks who enjoy data presented in cute and adorable ways.</description></item><item><title>Flowchart: when it’s okay to say “that’s so gay”</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-thats-so-gay-prin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 22:10:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/flowchart-when-its-okay-to-say-thats-so-gay-prin/</guid><description>For the more analytical folks, we created a handy flowchart to help make the decision “Is ‘gay’ the right word for me?”
As you can tell, in most cases, the answer is no. Print, post, and share freely.</description></item><item><title>5+ Ways to Make Our World More Trans*-Friendly</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/list-of-ways-to-make-world-trans-friendl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 17:55:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/list-of-ways-to-make-world-trans-friendl/</guid><description>&lt;p>We live in a world that recognizes two options for gender.  If you’re not &lt;em>exactly&lt;/em> “man” or “woman” you’re going to have a hard time finding your place, because right now there isn’t a &lt;em>place&lt;/em> for you.  Let’s change that.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Following is a list of suggestions to make the world a bit less binary and a lot more transgender inclusive.  Read ’em, live ’em, and add to ’em in the comments below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>When to use the word “gay”</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/when-to-use-the-word-gay-print/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2012 00:14:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/when-to-use-the-word-gay-print/</guid><description>When is it &amp;ldquo;okay&amp;rdquo; to say gay? Why is this even a question we need to be asking? Well, because it seems that people have some misconceptions, and this flowchart makes it simple.
This graphic was originally created to support this article, but then a comment was made saying this should be hung on every dorm wall in America.</description></item><item><title>A visual aid: when “gay” is okay</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/a-visual-aid-when-gay-okay-to-sa/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2011 21:51:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2011/12/a-visual-aid-when-gay-okay-to-sa/</guid><description>For those of you still struggling with the idea of when it is and isn’t ideal to use the word “gay”, even after reading my article outlining the whole idea, I decided to create a few visual aids. Hopefully they are straightforward.</description></item></channel></rss>