<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Replies on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/replies/</link><description>Recent content in Replies on It's Pronounced Metrosexual</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 15:53:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/tags/replies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Does the Genderbread Person Exclude Genderfluid People?</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/articles/genderbread-person-and-genderfluidity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 15:53:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/articles/genderbread-person-and-genderfluidity/</guid><description>I got an email pointing out to me that my versions of the Genderbread Person exclude genderfluid people. And not just people who use the term &amp;ldquo;genderfluid&amp;rdquo; to identify themselves, but anyone who expresses gender differently at different times. So, do they?</description></item><item><title>How to explain that bisexuality (or pansexuality) is real</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/how-to-explain-to-someone-bisexuality-or-pansexuality-is-real/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 20:24:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/how-to-explain-to-someone-bisexuality-or-pansexuality-is-real/</guid><description>&lt;address>
This is a second-part response to &lt;a title="Top Ten Tips on how to Thicken your Skin" href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/tips-on-thickening-skin-in-social-justice-work/" target="_blank">an email I received&lt;/a> from a high school senior (it&amp;#8217;d probably help contextualize if you read her email first).  
&lt;/address>
&lt;p>Bisexuality is a thing. It’s not just “a stop between gay and straight.” But how do you explain that to someone who just. simply. won’t. believe. you.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am going to focus on the struggle many bisexual and pansexual folks have convincing their straight (or gay/lesbian) peers that bisexuality is an identity, not just a stopping point between two others.  While I’m focusing this article on advice for bi- and pansexual folks, some of it applies to all sexuality discussions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have three main approaches you can take below, but I’d love to hear suggestions for more ways to breach this subject in the comments below.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Top Ten Tips on how to Thicken your Skin</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/tips-on-thickening-skin-in-social-justice-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 21:23:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/09/tips-on-thickening-skin-in-social-justice-work/</guid><description>&lt;p>I received the following email from a high school senior (we’ll call her Angie), replied to her, she appreciated the response and told me she’d be cool with me sharing it with you folks in case any one else might be able to find it useful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Angie’s Email:&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>I need tips on how to thicken my skin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here’s my issue. I’m taking Gender/Sexuality Diversity in Literature (basically Gender Studies), and there are kids in my class who don’t believe in bisexuality, let alone *my* sexuality (aka. pansexuality). I’m an easy crier and I just know that when this rather basic problem surfaces–because I’ve only ever heard these kids mutter their opinions under their breath–I won’t make it through the conversation. So, tips?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve thought about coming out to the class (I’m out to my friends, family, most teachers, and Facebook, but most people don’t know) but haven’t. I want people to step on eggshells because they’re being inclusive, not because I’m in the room and they don’t want to offend me personally.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Any thoughts? Totally fine if not. A snarky one-liner would be just as welcome, because you’re hilarious and shit.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>An open letter to Bradlee Dean (and all Biblical literalists who label homosexuality as sin)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/open-letter-to-biblical-literalists-on-homosexualit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 00:59:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/04/open-letter-to-biblical-literalists-on-homosexualit/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/bradley-dean.jpg">&lt;img class="alignright size-full wp-image-1181 lazy-load" data-src="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/bradley-dean.jpg" alt="Bradlee Dean" width="250" data-srcset="https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/bradley-dean.jpg 480w, https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/bradley-dean-300x198.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 100vw, 480px" />&lt;/a>Bradlee Dean, heavy metal rocker slash minister, recently alluded that the &lt;a title="DailyMail.co.uk" href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2099397/Muslim-fanatics-called-execution-gays-wanted-set-medieval-state-Sharia-law-Derby-jailed.html" target="_blank">Muslims who were calling for execution of gays&lt;/a> are “more moral” than Christians (read about it at the &lt;a title="Huffington Post: Preacher calls for execution of gays" href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2012/04/03/bradlee-dean-preacher-allegations-gays-execution_n_1399971.html?utm_campaign=040312&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_source=Alert-gay-voices&amp;utm_content=FullStory" target="_blank">Huffington Post&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He’s since backtracked a lot, and wishy-washied, and etc.  But it’s as apparent how he truly feels as it is how bad he is at playing politics.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="focus">
&lt;p>
I sent him an email.  It&amp;#8217;s below.  Discuss.
&lt;/p>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>One reason I’m a social justice advocate (as a white, straight, male)</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/one-reason-i-do-what-i-do/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2012 21:29:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/02/one-reason-i-do-what-i-do/</guid><description>I’ve dedicated my life to progressing social justice, in the hopes that one day we can have a society that is equitable for all. I have a lot of reasons for doing this, but there are just as many reasons why it might be viewed that I _shouldn’t.</description></item><item><title>Ron Paul: When the morality changes, it will reflect on the laws</title><link>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/ron-paul-when-the-morality-changes-it-will-reflect-on-the-laws/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2012 05:46:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.itspronouncedmetrosexual.com/2012/01/ron-paul-when-the-morality-changes-it-will-reflect-on-the-laws/</guid><description>I was watching one of the recent GOP debates and I heard Ron Paul say something that really struck me, responding with his thoughts on abortion. I transcribed the quote, but the video is down below that if you’d like to watch.</description></item></channel></rss>